<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: sports | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/sports/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-30T23:55:41+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-04-10]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/04/10/information-overload-2011-04-10/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/04/10/information-overload-2011-04-10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"A few of my Git tricks, tips and workflows":http://nuclearsquid.com/writings/git-tricks-tips-workflows.html<br>Really nice collection of Git tricks by "Markus Prinz":http://twitter.com/cypher.</li>
<li>"Booted - What really ails Italy?":http://www.newyorker.com/arts/critics/atlarge/2011/04/11/110411crat_atlarge_parks?currentPage=all<br>Great New Yorker article by "Tim Parks":http://tim-parks.com/ on Italy and Silvio Berlusconi.</li>
<li>"The Future Of Libraries In The E-Book Age":http://www.npr.org/2011/04/04/135117829/the-future-of-libraries-in-the-e-book-age<br>A follow-up to last week's post on ebooks. I hope we'll eventually have sane policies for digital media.</li>
<li>"The Writer's Handbook":http://writing.wisc.edu/Handbook/index.html<br>Prepared by the University of Wisconsin - Madison this has some good tips for writing English (a lot of which also apply to German).</li>
<li>"Interview With Albert Graef":http://blueparen.com/node/6<br>An interview with the inventor of "Pure":http://code.google.com/p/pure-lang/, an unfortunately rather unknown functional programming language I used to play around with a bit last year (there's also a "second part":http://blueparen.com/node/7).</li>
<li>"Why You Should Care About Cricket":http://sports.espn.go.com/espn/eticket/story?page=110329/Cricket<br>This is a very good read not only about Cricket, but also about India.</li>
<li>"Detecting Cheaters":http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2011/04/detecting_cheat_2.html<br>Interesting as always, this article by Bruce Schneier covers cheating, evolutionary psychology and formal logic.</li>
<li>"The Story of Emily and Control":http://squid314.livejournal.com/293753.html<br>Here we go, for once I'm linking to some fiction in "Information Overload". This is a very nice short story, don't let yourself be turned away by the fact that it was posted on LJ.</li>
<li>"The world can be powered by alternative energy in 20-40 years, Stanford researcher says":http://news.stanford.edu/news/2011/january/jacobson-world-energy-012611.html<br>While this is interesting, I'm still somewhat doubtful that there'll be enough political will to make this happen.</li>
<li>"The Cicada Principle and Why It Matters to Web Designers":http://designfestival.com/the-cicada-principle-and-why-it-matters-to-web-designers/<br>When math helps design.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First real Taekwondo training]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/11/13/first-real-taekwondo-training/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/11/13/first-real-taekwondo-training</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After my two private lessons last week I had my first full Taekwondo training session today. Here's what I learned: My overall lifestyle and sports don't really mix. Sex, drugs and Rock'n'Roll - unfortunately I'm doing way better in some categories than in others - definitely took a beating (pun intended) from martial arts. My lungs declared war on me (damn you cheap Chinese cigarettes!), my pulse was going so fast that I was afraid an 8bit counter might not suffice for counting it and various other parts of my body just seemed very surprised to get used again. But once this painful first 15 minutes were over, the following 50 minutes were actually pretty cool and I'm looking forward to Thursday's session.</p>

<p>Boomtime, The Aftermath 25, 3172 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Taekwondo lesson]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/11/06/first-taekwondo-lesson/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/11/06/first-taekwondo-lesson</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since I started my new job this January, I more or less stopped doing any sports, which had the usual consequences of fitness--&nbsp;&amp;&amp; weight++. I've wanted to change this for quite a while now and since my local "Taekwondo school":http://www.taekwondo-twin-center.at/home.php?ttc_schule_id=8 - which by the way is conviniently located half-way between my apartment and the office - currently has a special offer (two private introductory lessons plus the "dobok":http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dobok for 25 Euro) I decided to give it a go. The first intro lesson today was pretty cool and the second will be this Wednesday. After this I'll get my white belt and will formally start training in the beginner's class.</p>

<p><b>Update:</b>
Had my second private lesson on Wednesday and really liked it too, so I signed up for the school and will try to train 2-3 times a week from now on. Since there are 13(!) training sessions per week I can choose from, I should be able to squeeze them in even in rather busy weeks.</p>

<p>Setting Orange, The Aftermath 18, 3172 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
