<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: language | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/language/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-24T16:20:20+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-12-25]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/25/information-overload-2011-12-25/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/25/information-overload-2011-12-25</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>They’ve reminded us that politics is not a matter of choosing among what we’re offered but of fighting for what we and others actually need, not to mention what we hope for.</p><footer><strong>Nathan Schneider</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.thenation.com/article/165240/thank-you-anarchists'>Thank You, Anarchists</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://web.mit.edu/newsoffice/2011/mitx-education-initiative-1219.html">MIT launches online learning initiative</a><br>After Stanford's successful online courses, the MIT also develops a new online platform on top of the already cool <a href="http://ocw.mit.edu/index.htm">OCW</a>. I always welcome more good and free learning resources.</li>
<li><a href="http://metamodern.com/2009/05/27/how-to-learn-about-everything/">How to Learn About Everything</a><br>As you can see from the subtitle of this blog, this is something I'm also trying to do, with a comparable method.</li>
<li><a href="http://hbr.org/2006/10/sleep-deficit-the-performance-killer">Sleep Deficit: The Performance Killer</a><br>As someone who sometimes suffers from bouts of insomnia, I can attest to the bad effects lack of sleep can have. You may believe that you got used to it, but really, you don't.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.thenation.com/article/165240/thank-you-anarchists">Thank You, Anarchists</a><br>I know The Nation is a left-wing magazine, but it's still nice to see a positive article about anarchism somewhere.</li>
<li><a href="http://togetherforjacksoncountykids.tumblr.com/post/14314184651/one-teachers-approach-to-preventing-gender-bullying-in">One teachers approach to preventing gender bullying in a classroom</a><br>There should be more teachers like this.</li>
<li><a href="http://persquaremile.com/2011/12/21/which-reads-faster-chinese-or-english/">Which reads faster, Chinese or English?</a><br>Once again a language related article. The comments are also quite interesting by the way.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.andyworthington.co.uk/2011/12/16/an-extraordinary-interview-with-former-guantanamo-child-prisoner-mohammed-el-gharani/">An Extraordinary Interview with Former Guantánamo Child Prisoner Mohammed El-Gharani</a><br>Some bits of this interview seem a bit odd to me, but you can judge that for yourself.</li>
<li><a href="http://games.greggman.com/game/the-zelda-test-or-why-no-zelda-clones/">The Zelda Test (or Why no Zelda Clones?)</a><br>I don't spend much time on playing video games anymore, but it's still good to read something like this by a real gaming nerd.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.arminsoyka.at/blog/uber-das-leben-eines-heterojungen-mit-schwulen-eltern/">Über das Leben eines Heterojungen mit schwulen Eltern</a><br>An Austrian exchange student describes his experience staying with a gay couple (in German).</li>
<li><a href="http://seedmagazine.com/content/article/why_we_havent_met_any_aliens/">Why We Haven't Met Any Aliens</a><br>While the overall gist of the article doesn't really strike home with me, I still find it an interesting thought experiment.</li>
</ul>


<p><blockquote><p>The business of humanity has become entertainment, and entertainment is the business of feeding fake fitness cues to our brains.</p><footer><strong>Geoffrey Miller</strong> <cite><a href='http://seedmagazine.com/content/article/why_we_havent_met_any_aliens/'>Why We Haven't Met Any Aliens</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-10-16]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/10/16/information-overload-2011-10-16/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-16T20:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/10/16/information-overload-2011-10-16</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>Above all, remember the more harm you cause, the more hate you feel, and the more kindness you deal into the world the more you come to love the people you help.</p><footer><strong>David McRaney</strong> <cite><a href='http://youarenotsosmart.com/2011/10/05/the-benjamin-franklin-effect/'>The Benjamin Franklin Effect</a></cite></footer></blockquote>
* <a href="http://youarenotsosmart.com/2011/10/05/the-benjamin-franklin-effect/">The Benjamin Franklin Effect</a><br>A very interesting article on cognitive dissonance and how we tend to rationalize things.
* <a href="http://www.twitlonger.com/show/dh5l3q">Letter from a psychopath</a><br>An email copy/pasted into TwitLonger, giving great insight into the world of a (claimed) psychopath.</li>
* <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/11/health/views/11klass.html">Hearing Bilingual: How Babies Sort Out Language</a><br>Research shows that language development starts really early on, and that the brain adopts to bilingualism easily.</li>
* <a href="http://econerdfood.blogspot.com/2011/10/benfords-law-and-decreasing-reliability.html">Benford's Law and the Decreasing Reliability of Accounting Data for US Firms</a><br>This article uses some math to show that accounting data is becoming less reliable and also how deviations from Benford's Law seem to coincide with outside events.</li>
* <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2011/oct/06/huaxi-village-tower-china">Huaxi: the village that towers above China</a><br>A small town in China builds a 328m high skyscraper because of one very influential man.</li>
* <a href="http://www.zeit.de/campus/2011/05/autismus/komplettansicht">Die Andersdenkenden</a><br>Autistic identical twins are studying philosophy at a German university and surprise their teachers and fellow students with the depth of their though processes (in German).</li>
* <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/foreigners/2011/10/silvio_berlusconi_a_new_book_reveals_why_italians_put_up_with_hi.html">That’s Italian</a><br>Italian journalists Beppe Seevergnini gives 10 reasons why Silvio Berlusconi gets away with being how he is.</li>
* <a href="http://norvig.com/chomsky.html">On Chomsky and the Two Cultures of Statistical Learning</a><br>Peter Norvig's rebuttal to a statement by Chomsky on statistical learning in regards to language.</li>
* <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/krulwich/2011/09/14/140467059/the-toughest-little-bird-youve-never-heard-of">The Toughest Little Bird You've Never Heard Of</a><br>A small species of birds migrates every year from Alaska to New Zealand.</li>
* <a href="http://zenhabits.net/tired/">Tired of Being Tired</a><br>I know that occasionally I should take some of the advice offered in this article.
<blockquote><p>If he went to see a basketball game, he’d walk out taller.</p><footer><strong>Beppe Severgnini</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/foreigners/2011/10/silvio_berlusconi_a_new_book_reveals_why_italians_put_up_with_hi.html'>That’s Italian</a></cite></footer></blockquote>
</ul></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-04-17]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/04/17/information-overload-2011-04-17/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/04/17/information-overload-2011-04-17</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"How I got a blank book to the top of the Amazon charts":http://realbusiness.co.uk/news/how-i-got-a-blank-book-to-the-top-of-the-amazon-charts<br>A good example of what marketing can do for you.</li>
<li>"The Grand Tour":http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2011/04/18/110418fa_fact_osnos?currentPage=all<br>Very interesting insight into a Chinese tour group in Europe.</li>
<li>"The mathematics of being nice":http://www.newscientist.com/article/mg20928045.200-the-mathematics-of-being-nice.html?full=true<br>An interview with Martin Nowak professor of mathematics and biology at Harvard University (and Austrian btw) about evolutionary biology, mathematics and his beliefs.</li>
<li>"The Lisp Curse":http://www.winestockwebdesign.com/Essays/Lisp_Curse.html<br>While I don't necessarily agree on all points, this is still a pretty interesting read.</li>
<li>"Why is one man primarily responsible for the existence of the letter 'J' and what letter did it split off from? ":http://hotword.dictionary.com/j/<br>The language nerd in me like this a lot.</li>
<li>"This Tech Bubble Is Different":http://www.businessweek.com/print/magazine/content/11_17/b4225060960537.htm<br>Let me sum up this article with an actual quote from it: <i>"The best minds of my generation are thinking about how to make people click ads," he says. "That sucks."</i></li>
<li>"The road to being a kick-ass public speaker":http://www.wait-till-i.com/2011/04/11/the-road-to-being-a-kick-ass-public-speaker/<br>This should be mandatory reading for anyone speaking at (tech) conferences.</li>
<li>"What happens when an air traffic controller is asleep?":http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/philg/2011/04/14/what-happens-when-an-air-traffic-controller-is-asleep/<br>I really like insights into the aviation industry, so I found this quite interesting.</li>
<li>"The Worst Mistake in the History of the Human Race":http://www.ditext.com/diamond/mistake.html<br>Was adopting agriculture the worst mistake we ever made? According to this article, probably yes, but as always you are invited to form your own opinion.</li>
<li>"When Did Girls Start Wearing Pink?":http://www.smithsonianmag.com/arts-culture/When-Did-Girls-Start-Wearing-Pink.html<br>A closer look at yet another gender stereotype.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-04-10]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/04/10/information-overload-2011-04-10/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/04/10/information-overload-2011-04-10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"A few of my Git tricks, tips and workflows":http://nuclearsquid.com/writings/git-tricks-tips-workflows.html<br>Really nice collection of Git tricks by "Markus Prinz":http://twitter.com/cypher.</li>
<li>"Booted - What really ails Italy?":http://www.newyorker.com/arts/critics/atlarge/2011/04/11/110411crat_atlarge_parks?currentPage=all<br>Great New Yorker article by "Tim Parks":http://tim-parks.com/ on Italy and Silvio Berlusconi.</li>
<li>"The Future Of Libraries In The E-Book Age":http://www.npr.org/2011/04/04/135117829/the-future-of-libraries-in-the-e-book-age<br>A follow-up to last week's post on ebooks. I hope we'll eventually have sane policies for digital media.</li>
<li>"The Writer's Handbook":http://writing.wisc.edu/Handbook/index.html<br>Prepared by the University of Wisconsin - Madison this has some good tips for writing English (a lot of which also apply to German).</li>
<li>"Interview With Albert Graef":http://blueparen.com/node/6<br>An interview with the inventor of "Pure":http://code.google.com/p/pure-lang/, an unfortunately rather unknown functional programming language I used to play around with a bit last year (there's also a "second part":http://blueparen.com/node/7).</li>
<li>"Why You Should Care About Cricket":http://sports.espn.go.com/espn/eticket/story?page=110329/Cricket<br>This is a very good read not only about Cricket, but also about India.</li>
<li>"Detecting Cheaters":http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2011/04/detecting_cheat_2.html<br>Interesting as always, this article by Bruce Schneier covers cheating, evolutionary psychology and formal logic.</li>
<li>"The Story of Emily and Control":http://squid314.livejournal.com/293753.html<br>Here we go, for once I'm linking to some fiction in "Information Overload". This is a very nice short story, don't let yourself be turned away by the fact that it was posted on LJ.</li>
<li>"The world can be powered by alternative energy in 20-40 years, Stanford researcher says":http://news.stanford.edu/news/2011/january/jacobson-world-energy-012611.html<br>While this is interesting, I'm still somewhat doubtful that there'll be enough political will to make this happen.</li>
<li>"The Cicada Principle and Why It Matters to Web Designers":http://designfestival.com/the-cicada-principle-and-why-it-matters-to-web-designers/<br>When math helps design.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2010-11-14]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2010/11/14/information-overload-2010-11-14/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2010/11/14/information-overload-2010-11-14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"JVM Bytecode for Dummies":http://www.slideshare.net/CharlesNutter/redev-2010-jvm-bytecode-for-dummies<br>Awesome presentation by "Charles Nutter":http://blog.headius.com/ on JVM Bytecode. No matter if you are just curious or want to write your own programming language, this is interesting!</li>
<li>"Cutting out the middle men":http://www.economist.com/node/17420321?story_id=17420321&fsrc=scn/tw/te/rss/pe<br>Great pilot project in the UK, empowering homeless people instead by directly giving them money.</li>
<li>"Can't play, won't play":http://www.hideandseek.net/cant-play-wont-play/<br>Lots of websites and incentive programs nowadays try to "gamify" themselves by adding badges and point systems. Read why in most cases this has nothing to do with real games.</li>
<li>"Obscene Losses":http://www.portfolio.com/culture-lifestyle/culture-inc/arts/2007/10/15/YouPorn-Vivid-Entertainment-Profile/index.html<br>Very detailed article on how YouPorn and other amateur sites damage the business of established adult movie producers.</li>
<li>"Mystery of how cats lap is revealed":http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-11717510<br>Cats even drink in cool ways.</li>
<li>"10 centuries in 5 minutes":http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DrZvn1qckIs<br>Absolutely fantastic 5 minute video of 1000 years of European history. This is fascinating and a good reminder that today's empires may very well be tomorrow's ashes.</li>
<li>"20 Awesomely Untranslatable Words from Around the World":http://matadornetwork.com/abroad/20-awesomely-untranslatable-words-from-around-the-world/2/<br>Interesting collection of untranslatable words from around the world. This made the language geek in me very happy.</li>
<li>"What I Would Do With This: Groceries":http://blog.mrmeyer.com/?p=4646<br>The mathematics of grocery shopping.</li>
<li>"Skateistan: To live and skate Kabul":http://vimeo.com/15841377<br>Short movie about a co-educational Skateboarding school in Kabul, Afghanistan.</li>
<li>"Hubris Versus Humility: The $15 billion Difference":http://steveblank.com/2010/11/08/hubris-versus-humility-the-15-billion-difference/<br>While I think that the comparison in this article is a bit apples and oranges, it's an interesting take on initial market positioning.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
