<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: technology | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/categories/technology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-15T19:48:44+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2015-02-15]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2015/02/15/information-overload-2015-02-15/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-15T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2015/02/15/information-overload-2015-02-15</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://manoharvanga.com/hackme/">hackme: Deconstructing an ELF File</a><br>
Great read. If you like this sort of thing, I can wholeheartedly recommend <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1593273851/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1593273851&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20&amp;linkId=TQPCBOME4UONL52F">A Bug Hunter&rsquo;s Diary</a> (affiliate link).</li>
<li><a href="http://io9.com/10-things-people-once-complained-would-ruin-the-english-1684240298">10 Things People Once Complained Would Ruin The English Language</a><br>
Next up: the Internet.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.cnet.com/au/news/samsungs-warning-our-smart-tvs-record-your-living-room-chatter/">Samsung&rsquo;s warning: Our Smart TVs record your living room chatter</a><br>
If you read the article, also read this comment: <a href="http://fyre.it/PlswOh.4">comment</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thediplomat.com/2015/02/singapore-a-mutiny-like-no-other/">Singapore: A Mutiny Like No Other</a><br>
A bit of history for the 50 years anniversary this year.</li>
<li><a href="http://phys.org/news/2015-02-big-quantum-equation-universe.html">No Big Bang? Quantum equation predicts universe has no beginning</a><br>
This week&rsquo;s most discussed Physic&rsquo;s article.</li>
<li><a href="http://thespeaker.co/chinese-charge-government-officials-part-illegal-underground-tibetan-independence-organization/">Chinese charge government officials for being part of “illegal underground Tibetan independence organization”</a><br>
I have to say I&rsquo;m somewhat surprised by this.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.livetravelenjoy.com/a-city-where-everyone-works-there-is-no-police-and-the-salary-is-1200-euros/">A City Where Everyone Works, There is No Police, and the Salary is 1200 Euros</a><br>
This is not some sort of socialist utopia, but a real place.</li>
<li><a href="http://theanarchistlibrary.org/library/l-susan-brown-does-work-really-work">Does Work Really Work?</a><br>
Somewhat older, but still a very good read.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.sciencealert.com/spanish-is-the-happiest-language-chinese-is-the-most-balanced-new-study-reveals">Spanish is the happiest language, Chinese the most balanced, new study reveals</a><br>
Language ans statistics, of course I like this.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2015-02-08]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2015/02/08/information-overload-2015-02-08/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-08T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2015/02/08/information-overload-2015-02-08</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.inseasia.com/2015/02/life-in-prisons-southeast-asia-is-far-removed-west/">Life in Prisons in Southeast Asia is far removed from the West</a><br>
No news here, but may be interesting for people not aware of the situation in SE Asian prisons.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.siliconafrica.com/dont-call-them-expats-they-are-immigrants-like-everyone-else/">Don’t Call them Expats, They are Immigrants like Everyone Else</a><br>
For me: expat = sent abroad by company, getting bonuses etc. for working abroad. Everyone else, myself included, is a foreign worker/migrant. In a discussion on Facebook however someone mentioned the following, which strikes me as true: moving from richer to poorer country = expat. Moving from poorer to richer country = migrant.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.psmag.com/politics-and-law/oil-behind-civil-war-intervention">Yes, Oil Is Behind a Lot of Wars</a><br>
Also interesting in this context: <a href="http://www.wikiwand.com/en/Greed_versus_grievance">Greed versus Grievance</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thediplomat.com/2015/01/india-the-austria-hungary-of-the-21st-century/">India: The Austria-Hungary of the 21st Century?</a><br>
You don&rsquo;t see Austria and India compared all that often. Th comparison seems rather far-fetched though.</li>
<li><a href="http://blog.mbl.edu/?p=3285">Sea Slug has Taken Genes from the Algae it Eats, Allowing it to Photosynthesize Like a Plant, Study Reports</a><br>
This is really fascinating, but <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23645554">is it true</a>?</li>
<li><a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/top-china-analyst-beijing-has-been-duping-the-us-since-mao-2015-2">Top China analyst: Beijing has been duping the US since Mao</a><br>
Now I&rsquo;m not one to underestimate the Chinese, but this does sound a bit paranoid.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.propublica.org/article/the-worlds-email-encryption-software-relies-on-one-guy-who-is-going-broke">The World’s Email Encryption Software Relies on One Guy, Who is Going Broke</a><br>
Luckily this article seems to have greatly improved things for Werner Koch.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2015/feb/05/europe-europeans-fears-terrorism-unemployment-pandemics">What are Europeans afraid of most?</a><br>
&ldquo;A hideous ecstasy of fear and vindictiveness, a desire to kill, to torture, to smash faces in with a sledge hammer, seemed to flow through the whole group of people like an electric current, turning one even against one&rsquo;s will into a grimacing, screaming lunatic. And yet the rage that one felt was an abstract, undirected emotion which could be switched from one object to another like the flame of a blowlamp.&rdquo; — George Orwell, 1984</li>
<li><a href="http://somefactsare.blogspot.com/2014/05/parton-sends-books-to-rotherham.html">Parton sends books to Rotherham</a><br>
Let&rsquo;s finish on a positive note&hellip;</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2015-01-18]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2015/01/18/information-overload-2015-01-18/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2015/01/18/information-overload-2015-01-18</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/11/09/fashion/the-life-of-a-pot-critic-denver-post-clean-with-citrus-notes.html">The Life of a Pot Critic: Clean, With Citrus Notes</a><br>
New laws, new jobs.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.smithsonianmag.com/arts-culture/its-the-umami-stupid-why-the-truth-about-msg-is-so-easy-to-swallow-180947626/">It’s the Umami, Stupid. Why the Truth About MSG is So Easy to Swallow</a><br>
Always good to challenge one&rsquo;s assumptions. This time: MSG.</li>
<li><a href="http://saigoneer.com/saigon-people/2346-l-h-i-saigon-s-gangster-queen">Lệ Hải: Saigon’s Gangster Queen</a><br>
This life story would make for an excellent movie.</li>
<li><a href="http://gizmodo.com/my-brief-and-curious-life-as-a-mechanical-turk-1587864671">My Brief and Curious Life As a Mechanical Turk</a><br>
Talk about alienation at the workplace&hellip;</li>
<li><a href="http://sea-globe.com/malaysia-student-visas-southeast-asia-globe/">Degrees of Difficulty</a><br>
Unexpected visa problems for foreign exchange students in Malaysia.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/cities/2015/jan/13/subliminal-power-city-fonts-typeface-design">The subliminal power of city fonts</a><br>
Cities and fonts, two things I enjoy in the same article.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/professional-cuddlers-embrace-more-clients-1420759074">Professional Cuddlers Embrace More Clients</a><br>
Nope, not from The Onion.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bangkokpost.com/news/special-reports/457600/sukhumvit-shakedown">Sukhumvit shakedown</a><br>
A good summary for everyone who hasn&rsquo;t been following these incidents.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dailynewsegypt.com/2015/01/15/girl-tries-break-egyptian-social-taboos/">A girl tries to break Egyptian social taboos</a><br>
Courageous and uplifting.</li>
<li><a href="http://sea-globe.com/one-hun-sen-cambodia-southeast-asia/">The One and Only: Hun Sen</a><br>
Hun Sen, the man who ruled Cambodia for the last 30 years is the world&rsquo;s longest serving leader.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2014-09-21]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2014/09/21/information-overload-2014-09-21/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-21T12:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2014/09/21/information-overload-2014-09-21</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After an almost 2 year hiatus, it&rsquo;s time to revive this series, although I&rsquo;m not yet sure if it&rsquo;s going to be weekly again.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://io9.com/10-lessons-from-real-life-revolutions-that-fictional-dy-1634087647">10 Lessons From Real-Life Revolutions That Fictional Dystopias Ignore</a><br>
Ignoring artistic license, there are some interesting points here regarding real life revolutions.</li>
<li><a href="http://vimeo.com/102051605">Enter Pyongyang</a><br>
An interesting video about the normally extremely secluded DPRK.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2014/09/16/world/middleeast/how-isis-works.html">How ISIS Works</a><br>
Some background information on organization, finances, etc.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/cities/2014/sep/03/mongolia-ulanbaatar-ger-yurt-tent-city">Life in Ulaanbaatar&rsquo;s tent city is hard</a><br>
A nice piece on the tent slums of Ulaanbaatar.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2014/sep/03/tunisian-street-art-in-pictures">Tunisian street art &ndash; in pictures</a><br>
Amazing pictures from the &ldquo;Djerbahood&rdquo; project.</li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/everything-about-startups-and-entrepreneurship/how-quitting-my-corporate-job-for-my-startup-dream-f-cked-my-life-up-3b6b3e29b318">How quitting my corporate job for my startup dream f*cked my life up</a><br>
IMHO one of the more reasonable startups pieces I read lately.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/national/archive/2014/09/in-cambridge-md-a-soviet-style-punishment-for-a-novelist/379431/">In Maryland, a Soviet-Style Punishment for a Novelist</a><br>
The times they are a-changin'&hellip;</li>
<li><a href="http://www.electronicbeats.net/en/features/monologues/sound-is-a-weapon-alec-empire/">&ldquo;Music is a weapon&rdquo; – Alec Empire on Digital Hardcore</a><br>
A good read not only for ATR fans.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/cities/2014/sep/19/khartoum-most-selfish-city-sudan-arab-capital">Khartoum: the most selfish city?</a><br>
This article certainly enhanced my limited understanding of Sudanese issues.</li>
<li><a href="http://sea-globe.com/stir-crazy-thailand-prisons-southeast-asia-globe/">Stir crazy</a><br>
The SEA Globe writes about the Thai prison system.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Kindle Fire and I]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/06/07/my-kindle-fire-and-i/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-07T16:52:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/06/07/my-kindle-fire-and-i</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in October I broke my trusty old <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004HZYA6E/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004HZYA6E&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Kindle Keyboard</a>, a rather
annoying thing to happen at the beginning of a long trip. As a
workaround I started to use the Kindle app on my iPod Touch, and while
I did manage to finish several books on it, it&rsquo;s a bit annoying to
read on such a small screen. So I decided to get a new device, but
which one? Either the new <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008UB7DU6/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B008UB7DU6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Kindle Paperwhite</a>, a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008GGCAVM/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B008GGCAVM&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Kindle Fire</a> or maybe
just an iPad or an Android tablet with the Kindle app?</p>

<p><strong>Tablet or Kindle?</strong></p>

<p>Lately I got a lot more serious about my chess playing, so I own
several books on the topic in digital form. Needless to say, they
don&rsquo;t do too well on a &ldquo;classical&rdquo; Kindle, so I started considering a
Fire or other tablet. Once I started thinking along those lines,
another group of publications came to mind, comics and graphic
novels. I used to love and collect them, but eventually stopped
because they just take up way too much space. Nowadays a lot of
publishers do have digital editions though, so this became the point
where the Paperwhite got thrown out of the race.</p>

<p><strong>The decision process</strong></p>

<p>So I knew I wanted a tablet, and I knew I wanted something small. This
left me with four contestants, the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008GGCAVM/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B008GGCAVM&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Kindle Fire HD 7"</a>, the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00746W3HG/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00746W3HG&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">iPad Mini</a>,
the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009X3UW2G/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009X3UW2G&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Nexus 7</a> and the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B007P4VOWC/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B007P4VOWC&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Galaxy Tab 2 7"</a>.</p>

<p>I like Apple products, but I wasn&rsquo;t really willing to shell out the
money for an iPad Mini (although you can get them for as little as 300
bucks at Wallmart at the moment). One down, three to go. Now for the
Nexus 7. It&rsquo;s a powerful Android device and also caters to the &ldquo;power
user&rdquo;, whatever that&rsquo;s worth in the tablet world. Alas I found a ton
of comments and posts about quality issues (DOA, glass coming off the
screens, devices having to be RMA&rsquo;d after only two weeks etc.) so I
was hesitant to get one, because the last thing I need while traveling
is carrying around a dead device while trying to get it replaced. Also
at $250 it was only $50 cheaper than an iPad Mini.</p>

<p>That left the Kindle Fire HD and the Galaxy Tab 2, the latter of which
is ridiculously cheap by now (the cheapest I saw was $150 with a
cover), but it&rsquo;s also not exactly the newest piece of hardware. I
still was leaning in the direction of the more general device
though&hellip; Until I walked into a Radioshack during our layover in
Florida, saw the Kindle Fire HD and bought it. Damn you, instant
gratification!</p>

<p><strong>First impressions</strong></p>

<p>When I turned it on for the first time, I was amazed. The display is
good, and I mean really good! As are the Dolby speakers. In short, I
find the audio and video quality to be pretty amazing for a 7 inch
device. Reading with the Kindle app is a pleasure, as is watching
movies and listening to music. I actually really enjoy watching stuff
on the Kindle Fire, much more than I expected on such a small screen.</p>

<p>But then I started to explore a bit more, and I got disappointed
rather fast. Amazon&rsquo;s user interface clearly was only built for two
purposes: shopping and consuming content. The Kindle Fire is not meant
to be a full-fledged Android tablet, it&rsquo;s a portable frontend to the
Amazon store and cloud. Starting from the ads which get displayed when
you wake up the device (I know, you can pay to have them removed),
over the unavailability of many apps in Amazon&rsquo;s app store (for
example all Google apps like GMail or Google Maps) to the extremely
content focused UI, everything screams &ldquo;Consume!&rdquo; in a rather shrill
and annoying voice.</p>

<p><strong>Making it work for me</strong></p>

<p>Luckily, there are lots of things you can do to make the Kindle Fire a
lot more interesting, even without rooting it (something I really
can&rsquo;t be bothered to do while on the road).</p>

<p>First off, you will need an alternative app store. After some research
I settled on <a href="http://slideme.org/">SlideME</a>, mostly because they actually check the
applications they are offering, thus alleviating some of the security
concerns I had about other offerings. Next I got myself a decent file
manager in the form of <a href="http://slideme.org/application/es-file-explorer">ES File Explorer</a>, before setting out to
find a decent browser. Yes, a browser, because somehow Amazon&rsquo;s own
offering, called Silk, doesn&rsquo;t really cut it for me. It has good
features, but I found it to be rather sluggish. And I had some privacy
concerns about the cloud rendering, euphemistically called &ldquo;Accelerate
Page Loading&rdquo; in the settings. Sure, you can choose to encrypt the
data or disable this &ldquo;feature&rdquo; completely, but it did leave a somewhat
bitter aftertaste. Most people seem to prefer <a href="http://slideme.org/application/dolphin-browser-0">Dolphin</a> or similar
offerings for their Android devices, but I settled for the good old
Firefox (or rather Aurora) in its <a href="http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/mobile/aurora/">mobile incarnation</a>. It&rsquo;s a solid app
and so far provides everything I need, including a direct download
from the website. This is how I interact with Google apps for the time
being, I just use their mobile versions in the browser.</p>

<p>App store fixed, file manager acquired, browser fixed, on to the
horrible UI. Unfortunately there&rsquo;s not really too much you can do in
this regard, but I found <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004VN7BRC/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004VN7BRC&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Smart Taskbar</a> to be a huge
improvement. It has a small icon for triggering the app from
everywhere and features quick launch for up to five apps, configurable
labels and much more. Not as good as having a &ldquo;normal&rdquo; Android
interface, but definitely much better than the standard Kindle Fire
offering.</p>

<p>Last but not least I installed <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/android">Dropbox</a> for easier file exchange, which
is super easy because there&rsquo;s a direct download link on the web
site. I wish more developers would do this&hellip;</p>

<p><strong>More content</strong></p>

<p>Once I was done with the basics, it was time to add more content
sources/viewers. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004UBB1HQ/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004UBB1HQ&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">ComiCat</a> is an exzellent CBR/CBZ reader and I
highly recommend it for managing and reading your digital
comics. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005VVSQU4/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B005VVSQU4&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">ComiXology</a> (and its app Comics) also is a good addition,
especially since they have a rather well stocked online store and a
decent read-by-panel feature. Both of these apps are available in
Amazon&rsquo;s app store ($3 for ComiCat, Comics is for free).</p>

<p>For access to more books I added the <a href="http://slideme.org/application/gutenberg-ereader">Gutenberg eReader</a> app, a frontend
to the well-known Project Gutenberg, as well as the <a href="http://slideme.org/application/nook">NOOK</a>
software. Yes, NOOK, on a Kindle. As you can imagine this did not come
from the official app store but from SlideME instead. Since I&rsquo;m
usually really happy with Amazon&rsquo;s offerings I&rsquo;m not even sure I&rsquo;ll
use it, but it&rsquo;s nice to have a choice and apparently the NOOK store
has a dedicated comic section, so who knows&hellip;</p>

<p>On to movies. While Amazon&rsquo;s streaming service is great (or so I&rsquo;ve
heard), it&rsquo;s of no use to me while traveling. I do however have quite
a few films and documentaries on my netbook (go check out <a href="http://vodo.net/">VODO</a>,
there&rsquo;s some great free stuff on there), but I don&rsquo;t want to convert
all of them to a format the Kindle understands. Enter <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AHQNHSY/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00AHQNHSY&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">MoboPlayer</a>, a
great free movie player that can deal with a ton of formats and even
has a windowed mode. Yes, on a tablet!</p>

<p>With comics, books and movies covered, what&rsquo;s left? Games! The guys
over at <a href="https://www.humblebundle.com/">Humble Bundle</a> don&rsquo;t only compile great game bundles, they
also have a nifty <a href="https://www.humblebundle.com/app">Android app</a>, that let&rsquo;s you manage all your
purchases. Since they offered several Android bundles in the past I
actually have a ton of games, and the Kindle Fire is an excellent
device to play them on.</p>

<p>Of course I have a lot more apps than that (Instapaper, Twitter,
Flipboard, LinkedIn etc.) but they all come from the official app
store and don&rsquo;t really need any explanation here.</p>

<p><strong>Final verdict</strong></p>

<p>After I got over my initial frustrations, I REALLY like my Kindle
Fire. I guess it&rsquo;s all about expectation management. This is not a
productivity device, it&rsquo;s a gadget for consuming media in all its
forms. I especially love reading comics and graphic novels on it, the
colors are great, and the resolution is high enough to actually be
able to enjoy them, even on a rather small screen. It&rsquo;s also great for
watching movies or listening to music and audiobooks, and since it&rsquo;s a
Kindle, reading eBooks is a pleasure too once you configured the app
to your liking.</p>

<p>The hardware is fantastic (especially for $200) and the battery life
(around 10-11h) is great. I don&rsquo;t exclude the possibility of rooting
it in the future and maybe even flashing a different ROM, but for now
I take the Kindle Fire for what it is and thoroughly enjoy it that
way: during a bus ride the other day I read a book, watched a video,
and read some comics, all on the same device.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
