<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: technology | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/categories/technology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-06T13:13:30+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2014-09-21]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2014/09/21/information-overload-2014-09-21/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-21T12:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2014/09/21/information-overload-2014-09-21</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After an almost 2 year hiatus, it&rsquo;s time to revive this series, although I&rsquo;m not yet sure if it&rsquo;s going to be weekly again.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://io9.com/10-lessons-from-real-life-revolutions-that-fictional-dy-1634087647">10 Lessons From Real-Life Revolutions That Fictional Dystopias Ignore</a><br>
Ignoring artistic license, there are some interesting points here regarding real life revolutions.</li>
<li><a href="http://vimeo.com/102051605">Enter Pyongyang</a><br>
An interesting video about the normally extremely secluded DPRK.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2014/09/16/world/middleeast/how-isis-works.html">How ISIS Works</a><br>
Some background information on organization, finances, etc.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/cities/2014/sep/03/mongolia-ulanbaatar-ger-yurt-tent-city">Life in Ulaanbaatar&rsquo;s tent city is hard</a><br>
A nice piece on the tent slums of Ulaanbaatar.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2014/sep/03/tunisian-street-art-in-pictures">Tunisian street art &ndash; in pictures</a><br>
Amazing pictures from the &ldquo;Djerbahood&rdquo; project.</li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/everything-about-startups-and-entrepreneurship/how-quitting-my-corporate-job-for-my-startup-dream-f-cked-my-life-up-3b6b3e29b318">How quitting my corporate job for my startup dream f*cked my life up</a><br>
IMHO one of the more reasonable startups pieces I read lately.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/national/archive/2014/09/in-cambridge-md-a-soviet-style-punishment-for-a-novelist/379431/">In Maryland, a Soviet-Style Punishment for a Novelist</a><br>
The times they are a-changin'&hellip;</li>
<li><a href="http://www.electronicbeats.net/en/features/monologues/sound-is-a-weapon-alec-empire/">&ldquo;Music is a weapon&rdquo; – Alec Empire on Digital Hardcore</a><br>
A good read not only for ATR fans.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theguardian.com/cities/2014/sep/19/khartoum-most-selfish-city-sudan-arab-capital">Khartoum: the most selfish city?</a><br>
This article certainly enhanced my limited understanding of Sudanese issues.</li>
<li><a href="http://sea-globe.com/stir-crazy-thailand-prisons-southeast-asia-globe/">Stir crazy</a><br>
The SEA Globe writes about the Thai prison system.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Kindle Fire and I]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/06/07/my-kindle-fire-and-i/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-07T16:52:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/06/07/my-kindle-fire-and-i</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in October I broke my trusty old <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004HZYA6E/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004HZYA6E&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Kindle Keyboard</a>, a rather
annoying thing to happen at the beginning of a long trip. As a
workaround I started to use the Kindle app on my iPod Touch, and while
I did manage to finish several books on it, it&rsquo;s a bit annoying to
read on such a small screen. So I decided to get a new device, but
which one? Either the new <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008UB7DU6/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B008UB7DU6&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Kindle Paperwhite</a>, a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008GGCAVM/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B008GGCAVM&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Kindle Fire</a> or maybe
just an iPad or an Android tablet with the Kindle app?</p>

<p><strong>Tablet or Kindle?</strong></p>

<p>Lately I got a lot more serious about my chess playing, so I own
several books on the topic in digital form. Needless to say, they
don&rsquo;t do too well on a &ldquo;classical&rdquo; Kindle, so I started considering a
Fire or other tablet. Once I started thinking along those lines,
another group of publications came to mind, comics and graphic
novels. I used to love and collect them, but eventually stopped
because they just take up way too much space. Nowadays a lot of
publishers do have digital editions though, so this became the point
where the Paperwhite got thrown out of the race.</p>

<p><strong>The decision process</strong></p>

<p>So I knew I wanted a tablet, and I knew I wanted something small. This
left me with four contestants, the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B008GGCAVM/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B008GGCAVM&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Kindle Fire HD 7"</a>, the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00746W3HG/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00746W3HG&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">iPad Mini</a>,
the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009X3UW2G/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B009X3UW2G&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Nexus 7</a> and the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B007P4VOWC/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B007P4VOWC&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Galaxy Tab 2 7"</a>.</p>

<p>I like Apple products, but I wasn&rsquo;t really willing to shell out the
money for an iPad Mini (although you can get them for as little as 300
bucks at Wallmart at the moment). One down, three to go. Now for the
Nexus 7. It&rsquo;s a powerful Android device and also caters to the &ldquo;power
user&rdquo;, whatever that&rsquo;s worth in the tablet world. Alas I found a ton
of comments and posts about quality issues (DOA, glass coming off the
screens, devices having to be RMA&rsquo;d after only two weeks etc.) so I
was hesitant to get one, because the last thing I need while traveling
is carrying around a dead device while trying to get it replaced. Also
at $250 it was only $50 cheaper than an iPad Mini.</p>

<p>That left the Kindle Fire HD and the Galaxy Tab 2, the latter of which
is ridiculously cheap by now (the cheapest I saw was $150 with a
cover), but it&rsquo;s also not exactly the newest piece of hardware. I
still was leaning in the direction of the more general device
though&hellip; Until I walked into a Radioshack during our layover in
Florida, saw the Kindle Fire HD and bought it. Damn you, instant
gratification!</p>

<p><strong>First impressions</strong></p>

<p>When I turned it on for the first time, I was amazed. The display is
good, and I mean really good! As are the Dolby speakers. In short, I
find the audio and video quality to be pretty amazing for a 7 inch
device. Reading with the Kindle app is a pleasure, as is watching
movies and listening to music. I actually really enjoy watching stuff
on the Kindle Fire, much more than I expected on such a small screen.</p>

<p>But then I started to explore a bit more, and I got disappointed
rather fast. Amazon&rsquo;s user interface clearly was only built for two
purposes: shopping and consuming content. The Kindle Fire is not meant
to be a full-fledged Android tablet, it&rsquo;s a portable frontend to the
Amazon store and cloud. Starting from the ads which get displayed when
you wake up the device (I know, you can pay to have them removed),
over the unavailability of many apps in Amazon&rsquo;s app store (for
example all Google apps like GMail or Google Maps) to the extremely
content focused UI, everything screams &ldquo;Consume!&rdquo; in a rather shrill
and annoying voice.</p>

<p><strong>Making it work for me</strong></p>

<p>Luckily, there are lots of things you can do to make the Kindle Fire a
lot more interesting, even without rooting it (something I really
can&rsquo;t be bothered to do while on the road).</p>

<p>First off, you will need an alternative app store. After some research
I settled on <a href="http://slideme.org/">SlideME</a>, mostly because they actually check the
applications they are offering, thus alleviating some of the security
concerns I had about other offerings. Next I got myself a decent file
manager in the form of <a href="http://slideme.org/application/es-file-explorer">ES File Explorer</a>, before setting out to
find a decent browser. Yes, a browser, because somehow Amazon&rsquo;s own
offering, called Silk, doesn&rsquo;t really cut it for me. It has good
features, but I found it to be rather sluggish. And I had some privacy
concerns about the cloud rendering, euphemistically called &ldquo;Accelerate
Page Loading&rdquo; in the settings. Sure, you can choose to encrypt the
data or disable this &ldquo;feature&rdquo; completely, but it did leave a somewhat
bitter aftertaste. Most people seem to prefer <a href="http://slideme.org/application/dolphin-browser-0">Dolphin</a> or similar
offerings for their Android devices, but I settled for the good old
Firefox (or rather Aurora) in its <a href="http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/mobile/aurora/">mobile incarnation</a>. It&rsquo;s a solid app
and so far provides everything I need, including a direct download
from the website. This is how I interact with Google apps for the time
being, I just use their mobile versions in the browser.</p>

<p>App store fixed, file manager acquired, browser fixed, on to the
horrible UI. Unfortunately there&rsquo;s not really too much you can do in
this regard, but I found <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004VN7BRC/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004VN7BRC&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">Smart Taskbar</a> to be a huge
improvement. It has a small icon for triggering the app from
everywhere and features quick launch for up to five apps, configurable
labels and much more. Not as good as having a &ldquo;normal&rdquo; Android
interface, but definitely much better than the standard Kindle Fire
offering.</p>

<p>Last but not least I installed <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/android">Dropbox</a> for easier file exchange, which
is super easy because there&rsquo;s a direct download link on the web
site. I wish more developers would do this&hellip;</p>

<p><strong>More content</strong></p>

<p>Once I was done with the basics, it was time to add more content
sources/viewers. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004UBB1HQ/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B004UBB1HQ&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">ComiCat</a> is an exzellent CBR/CBZ reader and I
highly recommend it for managing and reading your digital
comics. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005VVSQU4/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B005VVSQU4&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">ComiXology</a> (and its app Comics) also is a good addition,
especially since they have a rather well stocked online store and a
decent read-by-panel feature. Both of these apps are available in
Amazon&rsquo;s app store ($3 for ComiCat, Comics is for free).</p>

<p>For access to more books I added the <a href="http://slideme.org/application/gutenberg-ereader">Gutenberg eReader</a> app, a frontend
to the well-known Project Gutenberg, as well as the <a href="http://slideme.org/application/nook">NOOK</a>
software. Yes, NOOK, on a Kindle. As you can imagine this did not come
from the official app store but from SlideME instead. Since I&rsquo;m
usually really happy with Amazon&rsquo;s offerings I&rsquo;m not even sure I&rsquo;ll
use it, but it&rsquo;s nice to have a choice and apparently the NOOK store
has a dedicated comic section, so who knows&hellip;</p>

<p>On to movies. While Amazon&rsquo;s streaming service is great (or so I&rsquo;ve
heard), it&rsquo;s of no use to me while traveling. I do however have quite
a few films and documentaries on my netbook (go check out <a href="http://vodo.net/">VODO</a>,
there&rsquo;s some great free stuff on there), but I don&rsquo;t want to convert
all of them to a format the Kindle understands. Enter <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AHQNHSY/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00AHQNHSY&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20">MoboPlayer</a>, a
great free movie player that can deal with a ton of formats and even
has a windowed mode. Yes, on a tablet!</p>

<p>With comics, books and movies covered, what&rsquo;s left? Games! The guys
over at <a href="https://www.humblebundle.com/">Humble Bundle</a> don&rsquo;t only compile great game bundles, they
also have a nifty <a href="https://www.humblebundle.com/app">Android app</a>, that let&rsquo;s you manage all your
purchases. Since they offered several Android bundles in the past I
actually have a ton of games, and the Kindle Fire is an excellent
device to play them on.</p>

<p>Of course I have a lot more apps than that (Instapaper, Twitter,
Flipboard, LinkedIn etc.) but they all come from the official app
store and don&rsquo;t really need any explanation here.</p>

<p><strong>Final verdict</strong></p>

<p>After I got over my initial frustrations, I REALLY like my Kindle
Fire. I guess it&rsquo;s all about expectation management. This is not a
productivity device, it&rsquo;s a gadget for consuming media in all its
forms. I especially love reading comics and graphic novels on it, the
colors are great, and the resolution is high enough to actually be
able to enjoy them, even on a rather small screen. It&rsquo;s also great for
watching movies or listening to music and audiobooks, and since it&rsquo;s a
Kindle, reading eBooks is a pleasure too once you configured the app
to your liking.</p>

<p>The hardware is fantastic (especially for $200) and the battery life
(around 10-11h) is great. I don&rsquo;t exclude the possibility of rooting
it in the future and maybe even flashing a different ROM, but for now
I take the Kindle Fire for what it is and thoroughly enjoy it that
way: during a bus ride the other day I read a book, watched a video,
and read some comics, all on the same device.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2012-08-26]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2012/08/26/information-overload-2012-08-26/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-26T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2012/08/26/information-overload-2012-08-26</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Remember how I said there probably won&rsquo;t be an Information Overload this week? Turns out I was wrong :&ndash;)</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2012/aug/20/burma-ends-advance-press-censorship">Burma ends advance press censorship</a><br>This seems like a step in the right direction, let&rsquo;s hope it stays this way.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.businessweek.com/news/2012-08-12/imf-says-bailouts-iceland-style-hold-lessons-for-crisis-nations">IMF Says Bailouts Iceland-Style Hold Lessons in Crisis Times</a><br>How Icenland recovered the economic crisis.</li>
<li><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/08/23/indias-sms-hoax-panic-could-it-happen-in-the-u-s/">India’s SMS Hoax Panic: Could It Happen In The U.S.?</a><br>With the ubiquity of social media and text messages, this should be fairly easy to replicate anywhere.</li>
<li><a href="http://apple.copydesk.org/2012/08/25/keep-in-mind-as-you-put-together-your-neil-armstrong-packages-tonight/">Keep in mind as you put together your Neil Armstrong packages tonight…</a><br>RIP Neil Armstrong!</li>
<li><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/08/25/5-design-tricks-facebook-uses-to-affect-your-privacy-decisions/">5 Design Tricks Facebook Uses To Affect Your Privacy Decisions</a><br>Anyone surprised by this? No? Thought so.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theiacp.org/About/Governance/Divisions/StateAssociationsofChiefsofPoliceSACOP/CurrentSACOPProjects/MissingAlzheimersDiseasePatientInitiative/AlzheimersSuccessStory/tabid/1007/Default.aspx?id=1665">Fake Bus Stops for Alzheimer&rsquo;s Patients in Germany</a><br>I guess this qualifies as a mind hack.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=your-scientific-reasoning-more-flawed-than-you-think">Your Scientific Reasoning Is More Flawed Than You Think</a><br>Even scientifically minded peopel fall back to childhood ideas about how the world works.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/08/26/sunday-review/how-long-do-you-want-to-live.html">How Long Do You Want to Live?</a><br>An interesting question to pose in light of ever-increasing life expectancy.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2012-08-19]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2012/08/19/information-overload-2012-08-19/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2012/08/19/information-overload-2012-08-19</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Note: I&rsquo;ll probably be too busy this upcoming week, so don&rsquo;t expect an Information Overload next Sunday.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://dowlingduncan.com/2010/dowling-duncan-redesign-us-bank-notes/">Dowling Duncan redesign the US bank notes</a><br>This is a bit older, but a very cool design.</li>
<li><a href="http://eng-pussy-riot.livejournal.com/7473.html">The Pussy Riot Lawyers &ndash; They will try to disbar us</a><br>Interesting interview with the Pussy Riot lawyers.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.stevenpressfield.com/2009/10/writing-wednesdays-2-the-most-important-writing-lession-i-ever-learned/">The Most Important Writing Lesson I Ever Learned</a><br>It&rsquo;s a good lesson indeed and one I wish more artists followed.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.prospectmagazine.co.uk/politics/mark-kitto-youll-never-be-chinese-leaving-china/">You&rsquo;ll never be Chinese</a><br>A foreigner living in China for 16 years explains why he wants to leave now.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.geekwire.com/2012/startup-acting-big-company/">How to keep your startup from acting like a big company</a><br>One would figure a lot of this boils down to common sense, but since I have seen enough startups that fail to follow this simple advices, I may be wrong.</li>
<li><a href="http://articles.latimes.com/2012/aug/15/world/la-fg-israel-sperm-20120816">Israel sperm banks find quality is plummeting</a><br>And nobody really knows why.</li>
<li><a href="http://slifty.com/2012/08/a-tor-of-the-dark-web/">A Tor of the Dark Web</a><br>This lighthearted article is a good introduction to Tor that you can send on to your less tech-savvy friends.</li>
<li><a href="http://pod2g-ios.blogspot.co.uk/2012/08/never-trust-sms-ios-text-spoofing.html">Never trust SMS: iOS text spoofing</a><br>This is obviously a scammer&rsquo;s dream. I wonder how Android phones deal with this.</li>
<li><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10000872396390444772404577589270444059332.html">The Panic Over Fukushima</a><br>The WSJ does some math related to radiatin in Fukushima.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2012-08-05]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2012/08/05/information-overload-2012-08-05/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-05T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2012/08/05/information-overload-2012-08-05</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="https://plus.google.com/101960720994009339267/posts/R58WgWwN9jp">A lesson in shortcuts</a><br>A nice piece of Unix history by Rob Pike.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.raptitude.com/2012/06/why-we-fck/">Why we f*ck</a><br>I like different perspectives. Whether you buy into this or not, it&rsquo;s a good read with some interesting discussion in the comments.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2012/aug/01/somali-comedian-islamists-shot-dead">Somali comedian who mocked Islamists is shot dead</a><br>While the main theme of this article is sad, it also mentions the new Somali constitution and the upcoming elections.</li>
<li><a href="http://taz.de/Schwaebische-Beamte-beim-Ku-Klux-Klan/!98469/">Polizisten, Ritter und Rassisten</a><br>Two German police men were members of the European KKK (in German).</li>
<li><a href="http://mondediplo.com/2012/08/06bedouin">The end of the Bedouin</a><br>Israel wants to relocate Bedouins from their unrecognized settlements.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.economist.com/node/21559947?fsrc=scn/tw/te/pe/workinprogress">Work in progress</a><br>The Economist analyzes Facebook&rsquo;s current share value.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/08/02/us/sexual-harassment-in-online-gaming-stirs-anger.html?_r=1">In Virtual Play, Sex Harassment Is All Too Real</a><br>On sexual harassment in the gaming community.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/foreigners/2012/08/china_s_wealthy_and_influential_sometimes_hire_body_doubles_to_serve_their_prison_sentences.html">Double Jeopardy</a><br>If you are wealthy in China, you may be able to hire a substitute to go to prison for you.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.wired.com/business/2012/08/ff_wallstreet_trading/all/">Raging Bulls: How Wall Street Got Addicted to Light-Speed Trading</a><br>Wired looks at high-frequency trading.</li>
<li><a href="http://arstechnica.com/apple/2012/07/os-x-10-8/">OS X 10.8 Mountain Lion: the Ars Technica review</a><br>There&rsquo;s no better way to inform yourself about a new OS X release than the Ars Technica review that comes with it.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
