<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: media | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/media/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-25T17:51:05+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2012-03-25]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/03/25/information-overload-2012-03-25/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/03/25/information-overload-2012-03-25</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/music/2012/mar/17/punk-rock-state-oppression-burma">Punk rock … alive and kicking in a repressive state near you</a><br>On the state of punk music in Iraq, Russia, Burma and Indonesia.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/technology/2012/03/ruby_ruby_on_rails_and__why_the_disappearance_of_one_of_the_world_s_most_beloved_computer_programmers_.html?tid=sm_p1_button_toolbar">Where’s _why?</a><br>An article on _why and Ruby in Slate. Hello, mainstream. :-)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.aljazeera.com/indepth/opinion/2012/03/201231284336601364.html">Dangerous ignorance: The hysteria of Kony 2012</a><br>More negative feedback on the Kony 2012 campaign.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/matthewherper/2012/02/10/the-truly-staggering-cost-of-inventing-new-drugs/">The Truly Staggering Cost Of Inventing New Drugs</a><br>Make sure to also read the comments, some good stuff in there.</li>
<li><a href="http://theradicalantfarm.blogspot.com/2009/07/russian-prison-tattoos-implied-in-ink.html">Russian Prison Tattoos - Implied In Ink</a><br>I first read this a couple of years ago, but it came up in conversation today, so I decided to include it.</li>
<li><a href="http://libcom.org/library/%E2%80%98bout-explode-day-life-precarious-worker">'Bout to explode: a day in the life of a precarious worker</a><br>What precarious working conditions do to people...</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2012/03/21/how_to_get_paid_more/">You're crap and paid too much for the little work you actually do</a><br>I don't really like this article and the author doesn't sound like someone I'd want to have a beer with, but maybe some of you find this interesting.</li>
<li><a href="http://therealkatie.net/blog/2012/mar/21/lighten-up/">Lighten Up</a><br>About the subtle sexism female programmers have to endure, although I'm sure that's true in most professions.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.physorg.com/news/2011-10-microbes-inherit-earth.html">And the microbes shall inherit the Earth</a><br>Looking at the past to predict what consequences global warming could have in the future.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.zeit.de/politik/ausland/2012-03/fotografie-journalismus-ruben-salvadori/komplettansicht">Wie Pressefotos die Wirklichkeit manipulieren</a><br>Italian photographer Ruben Salvadori shows the truth behind press photos (in German).</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-11-06]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/11/06/information-overload-2011-11-06/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-06T20:36:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/11/06/information-overload-2011-11-06</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://motherjones.com/kevin-drum/2011/10/climate-skepticism-takes-another-hit">Climate Skeptics Take Another Hit</a><br>A scientist who was skeptical about climate change set out to prove others wrong and found out that they actually were right.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.geekwire.com/2011/gates-tells-uw-students-billionaire-overrated">Gates to students: Don’t try to be a billionaire, it’s overrated</a><br>Shorthand notes from a Q&amp;A session with Bill Gates at the University of Washington.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/Simple-Made-Easy">Simple Made Easy</a><br>Another excellent presentation by Clojure's Rich Hickey. This is not really Clojure specific, but something most programmers should watch!</li>
<li><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052970203476804576613284007315072.html">Secret Orders Target Email</a><br>Since it's harder to get search warrants for property or postal mail, US law enforcements seems to target electronic communications more and more. Maybe the Electronics Communication Privacy Act is due for an update, it's been a while since 1986...</li>
<li><a href="http://www.slaveryfootprint.org/">Slavery Footprint</a><br>Find out how many slaves work for you. Great campaign for raising awareness about human trafficking and slave labor worldwide.</li>
<li><a href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/notrocketscience/2011/10/31/man-with-schizophrenia-has-out-of-body-experience-in-lab-gains-knowledge-controls-his-psychosis/">Man with schizophrenia has out-of-body experience in lab, gains knowledge, controls his psychosis</a><br>The title is maybe a bit dramatic, but the article itself is still interesting.</li>
<li><a href="http://sourcefabric.org/en/community/blog/788">TagesWoche portrays new future for Swiss media </a><br>A great new publication from Switzerland: online journalism with user participation, version history, micro payments etc., as well as an accompanying weekly magazine.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.businessweek.com/magazine/apples-supplychain-secret-hoard-lasers-11032011.html">Apple's Supply-Chain Secret? Hoard Lasers</a><br>Interesting piece on Apple's supply chain management. Like so many things related to Apple, this triggered a mix of awe and unease in me.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.businessweek.com/magazine/todd-rider-has-a-kill-switch-for-viruses-11032011.html">Todd Rider Has a Kill Switch for Viruses</a><br>A scarily clever man — look at his academic credentials in the article — may have revolutionized who we treat virus-caused illnesses.</li>
<li><a href="http://idlewords.com/2011/08/why_arabic_is_terrific.htm">Why Arabic is Terrific</a><br>The language nerd in me loved this article.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-10-02]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/10/02/information-overload-2011-10-02/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-02T20:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/10/02/information-overload-2011-10-02</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.zeit.de/2009/44/Gesellschaft-Soziale-Netzwerke/komplettansicht">Höfische Gesellschaft 2.0</a><br>How social media resembles imperial courts (in German).</li>
<li><a href="http://www.eurozine.com/articles/2011-08-25-overy-en.html">The concentration camp</a><br>Very long and detailed article on one of humanity's darkest sides.</li>
<li><a href="http://theconversation.edu.au/princeton-bans-academics-from-handing-all-copyright-to-journal-publishers-3596">Princeton bans academics from handing all copyright to journal publishers</a><br>It's always good to see major institutions taking a step in the right direction.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/09/12/us/12agent.html?_r=1">Ex-F.B.I. Agent Cites High-Level Dysfunction Over 9/11</a><br>A former CIA agent published a behind the scenes book on the "War On Terror".</li>
<li><a href="http://www.crit-hit.net/top-20-games-nintendo-wouldnt-release-in-the-us/">Top 20 Games Nintendo Wouldn’t Release In The US</a><br>I don't play much anymore, but as a former console collector I know how frustrating this is (and I won't even mention all the cool stuff that never made it to Europe).</li>
<li><a href="http://www.jamisbuck.org/presentations/rubyconf2011/index.html">"Algorithm" is Not a Four-Letter Word</a><br>You are in a maze of twisty little passages, all alike.</li>
<li><a href="http://shaun.net/2011/05/whats-contained-in-a-boarding-pass-barcode/">What’s contained in a boarding pass barcode?</a><br>If you know me and this blog post series, you know that this is the type of stuff I like.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.we-make-money-not-art.com/archives/2011/09/hackteria.php">Hackteria | Open Source Biological Art</a><br>Interview with Andy Gracie of <a href="http://hackteria.org/">Hackteria</a> on bioelecronix and the Hackteria workshops.</li>
<li><a href="http://radian.org/notebook/porsche">How Porsche hacked the financial system and made a killing</a><br>This article from 2009 shows very well why it's called "playing the stock market".</li>
<li><a href="http://medicalxpress.com/news/2011-09-dose-hallucinogen-personality.html">Single dose of hallucinogen may create lasting personality change</a><br>What the headline doesn't say, is that's it's a rather positive change. Anyway, every bit of serious drug research is a step in the right direction.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-06-19]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/06/19/information-overload-2011-06-19/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-19T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/06/19/information-overload-2011-06-19</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"Take a look at the world's oldest mathematical object":http://io9.com/5806767/<br>A short article about the Ishango bone, apparently the &quot;<a href="http://mathworld.wolfram.com/IshangoBone.html">oldest known object containing logical carvings</a>&quot;.</li>
<li>"Nemesis: Der Todesstern und die Dinosaurier":http://www.scienceblogs.de/astrodicticum-simplex/2011/06/nemesis-der-todesstern-und-die-dinosaurier.php<br>Somehow I've missed the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nemesis_(hypothetical_star)">Nemesis theory</a> until now, but it sure is interesting (in German).</li>
<li>"Rich Hickey Q&A":http://www.codequarterly.com/2011/rich-hickey/<br>Great interview with Rich Hickey in Code Quarterly. Whenever I hear/read something by Rich, I understand why Clojure is such an awesome language.</li>
<li>"Earth may be headed into a mini Ice Age within a decade":http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/06/14/ice_age/<br>Hm, finally a good excuse to move to warmer places for good? "Or not":http://www.newscientist.com/blogs/shortsharpscience/2011/06/new-ice-age-dont-count-on-it.html?</li>
<li>"DIY Weapons of the Libyan Rebels":http://www.theatlantic.com/infocus/2011/06/diy-weapons-of-the-libyan-rebels/100086/<br>The creativity of humans when it comes to killing each other never ceases to amaze and sadden me.</li>
<li>"Indian Village Renamed Snapdeal.com. And It's Not A Cheap Marketing Stunt!":http://techcrunch.com/2011/06/17/indian-village-renamed-snapdeal-com-and-its-not-a-cheap-marketing-stunt/<br>IMHO as long as people get helped, it doesn't even matter if it's a marketing stunt or not. More companies should do something for their local communities.</li>
<li>"LulzSec - 1000th tweet statement":http://pastebin.com/HZtH523f<br>Since LulzSec was all over the news this week, I decided to include their open letter. There also was an "answer":http://pastebin.com/pbhBQLKy.</li>
<li>"Translation technology may let humans speak with dolphins":http://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/translation-technology-may-let-humans-speak-with-dolphins/<br>That would be awesome.</li>
<li>"Top 10 media manipulation strategies":http://www.thecompulsiveliar.com/top-10-media-manipulation-strategies.html<br>A list compiled by Noam Chomsky.</li>
<li>"High school grad builds 8-bit computer from scratch, complete with custom OS and Pong":http://www.digitaltrends.com/computing/wow-high-school-grad-builds-8-bit-computer-from-scratch-complete-with-custom-os-and-pong/<br>Simply amazing, an 18 yo builds a computer from scratch and then implements a custom OS and some games.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-05-08]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/05/08/information-overload-2011-05-08/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/05/08/information-overload-2011-05-08</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"Computer says: um, er...":http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2011/apr/30/computers-v-humans-loebner-artificial-intelligence?CMP=twt_iph<br>Very nice article by Brian Christian who participated as a human confederate in the 2009 "Turing Award":http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_Award.</li>
<li>"How Goldman Sachs Created the Food Crisis":http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2011/04/27/how_goldman_sachs_created_the_food_crisis<br>I lack the data and insight to fully judge the truth of this article, but I'm fairly certain that a non-trivial percentage of the world-wide rise in food prices was due to speculation. Isn't it great how cynical humans can be?</li>
<li>"World's largest model airport the Knuffingen goes on show":http://www.news.com.au/travel/news/man-builds-worlds-largest-model-airport-the-knuffingen/story-e6frfq80-1226050348557<br>After 7 years and millions of Euros the world's largest model airport goes on show. This is impressive, make sure to check out the video and photo series in the article!</li>
<li>"Images Reveal Scale Of North Korean Political Prison Camps":http://amnesty.org/en/news-and-updates/images-reveal-scale-north-korean-political-prison-camps-2011-05-03<br>If Amnesty calls something "some of the worst circumstances we've documented in the last 50 years" it must be really, really bad.</li>
<li>"How to Identify and Avoid Spreading Misinformation, Myths, and Urban Legends on the Internet":http://lifehacker.com/?_escaped_fragment_=5798308/how-to-identify-and-avoid-spreading-misinformation-myths-and-urban-legends-on-the-internet<br>I know I've posted links like this one before, but some things really do need to be repeated.</li>
<li>"Das Herz des Attentäters":http://www.freitag.de/wissen/1118-das-herz-des-attentaeters<br>It's probably not as simple as this, but definitely something to think about (in German).</li>
<li>"Google Go boldly goes where no code has gone before":http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/05/05/google_go/<br>While I don't necessarily agree with the title, it's still a nice article on a language we here surprising little about.</li>
<li>"25 Abandoned Yugoslavia Monuments that look like they're from the Future":http://www.cracktwo.com/2011/04/25-abandoned-soviet-monuments-that-look.html<br>I always was attracted to socialist architecture and the monuments in this article are no exception.</li>
<li>"Small areas of the brain go to sleep when we're up too late":http://arstechnica.com/science/news/2011/04/if-you-only-feel-half-awake-you-probably-are.ars<br>Sleep is a strange beast I've been struggling with to varying degrees for almost as long as I can remember, which is one reason why I like reading about it.</li>
<li>"The Neuroscience of the Gut":http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=the-neuroscience-of-gut<br>This is quite interesting, especially since this week I also found out about "fecal transplants":http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fecal_bacteriotherapy.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
