<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mongohq | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/mongohq/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-02T23:06:55-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fun with Sinatra, Heroku and MongoDB]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2009/12/06/fun-with-sinatra-heroku-and-mongodb/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-06T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2009/12/06/fun-with-sinatra-heroku-and-mongodb</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been toying around with the idea for a small website lately, but never actually got around to do it. In an attempt to clear out my personal to do list I finally motivated myself to start yesterday, and I have to say the following combination of tools is not only insanely efficient, but also really fun to work with:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.sinatrarb.com/">Sinatra</a>, <i>&#8220;a DSL for quickly creating web applications in Ruby with minimal effort&#8221;</i>. I recommend using it in combination with <a href="http://mongrel.rubyforge.org/">Mongrel</a>, <a href="http://github.com/rtomayko/shotgun">Shotgun</a> and <a href="http://haml-lang.com/">Haml</a>.</li><br />
<li><a href="http://heroku.com/">Heroku</a>, a Ruby cloud hosting platform. Small sites are for free and Heroku&#8217;s git-based workflow just feels so natural. You can also <a href="http://docs.heroku.com/gems">manage your gem dependencies</a> and <a href="http://docs.heroku.com/config-vars">set up environment variables</a>, which made my life a whole lot easier.</li><br />
<li><a href="http://www.mongodb.org">MongoDB</a>, <i>&#8220;a scalable, high-performance, open source, schema-free, document-oriented database&#8221;</i>. In this specific case I used <a href="http://www.mongohq.com/home">MongoHQ</a> for the database hosting, since they were nice enough to provide me with a beta account. I stored all the connection information for MongoHQ in environment variables as described above:</p>
<script src="http://gist.github.com/250193.js?file=mongohq.rb"></script>
</ul>


<p>With this combination I was able to go from zero to mostly finished (I still need to write some of the content and make/steal a stylesheet) in very little time, while actually having fun! Thanks everybody for providing the Ruby community which such awesome tools! :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
