<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: history | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/history/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-11T23:18:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-01-30]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/01/30/information-overload-2011-01-30/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/01/30/information-overload-2011-01-30</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"Chicks Who Rip: Amy Chen":http://www.engineyard.com/blog/2011/chicks-who-rip-amy-chen/<br>Every initiative that wants to get more women into programming should get our support as male developers. It's frickin 2011, can we get over gender stereotypes and finally accept female steel-workers and male nurses?</li>
<li>"Mauritius: A Glimmer of African Freedom":http://mises.org/daily/4985<br>We don't get good news about Africa often enough, so when they are there, we should share them despite the slightly liberterian undercurrent.</li>
<li>"Cool maps: Measuring growth from outer space":http://aidwatchers.com/2011/01/cool-maps-measuring-growth-from-outer-space/<br>Interesting idea: measuring economic with satellite images analyzing light distribution in a country.</li>
<li>"Bringing Balance to the Force":http://cleancoder.posterous.com/individuals-and-interactions<br>Since I like balanced and balancing opinions, I also like Uncle Bob's post on software craftsmanship.</li>
<li>"Frauen sind auch nur Männer":http://www.zeit.de/zeit-wissen/2007/01/Titel-Frauen-Maenner?page=all<br>Is the real difference between men and women just a resulted of being trained in stereotypes? That's what it looks like (in German).</li>
<li>"Never Use a Warning When you Mean Undo":http://www.alistapart.com/articles/neveruseawarning/<br>Even though I'm no designer, I have a soft spot for articles on UI/UX design and this one is no exception.</li>
<li>"News Desk: Mubarak and the Generals":http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/newsdesk/2011/01/mubarak-and-the-generals.html<br>What role will the army play in the current Egyptian protests?</li>
<li>"How the Internet went out in Egypt":http://www.zdnet.com/blog/networking/how-the-internet-went-out-in-egypt/620<br>If you want to explain to non-techy friends how Egypt "turned off the internet", this is a good resource.</li>
<li>"Political Flags of Extremism":http://www.loeser.us/flags/hate.html<br>Comprehensive collection of flags of far right and extremist groups. Also has a "second part":http://www.loeser.us/flags/hate2.html. Contains interesting information on some pretty obscure groups.</li>
<li>"The Inside Story of How Facebook Responded to Tunisian Hacks":http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2011/01/the-inside-story-of-how-facebook-responded-to-tunisian-hacks/70044/<br>Facebook's role in the Tunisian revolution. More interesting for understanding how Facebook was used by the Tunisians than for the technical content, but still...</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2010-11-14]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2010/11/14/information-overload-2010-11-14/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2010/11/14/information-overload-2010-11-14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"JVM Bytecode for Dummies":http://www.slideshare.net/CharlesNutter/redev-2010-jvm-bytecode-for-dummies<br>Awesome presentation by "Charles Nutter":http://blog.headius.com/ on JVM Bytecode. No matter if you are just curious or want to write your own programming language, this is interesting!</li>
<li>"Cutting out the middle men":http://www.economist.com/node/17420321?story_id=17420321&fsrc=scn/tw/te/rss/pe<br>Great pilot project in the UK, empowering homeless people instead by directly giving them money.</li>
<li>"Can't play, won't play":http://www.hideandseek.net/cant-play-wont-play/<br>Lots of websites and incentive programs nowadays try to "gamify" themselves by adding badges and point systems. Read why in most cases this has nothing to do with real games.</li>
<li>"Obscene Losses":http://www.portfolio.com/culture-lifestyle/culture-inc/arts/2007/10/15/YouPorn-Vivid-Entertainment-Profile/index.html<br>Very detailed article on how YouPorn and other amateur sites damage the business of established adult movie producers.</li>
<li>"Mystery of how cats lap is revealed":http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-11717510<br>Cats even drink in cool ways.</li>
<li>"10 centuries in 5 minutes":http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DrZvn1qckIs<br>Absolutely fantastic 5 minute video of 1000 years of European history. This is fascinating and a good reminder that today's empires may very well be tomorrow's ashes.</li>
<li>"20 Awesomely Untranslatable Words from Around the World":http://matadornetwork.com/abroad/20-awesomely-untranslatable-words-from-around-the-world/2/<br>Interesting collection of untranslatable words from around the world. This made the language geek in me very happy.</li>
<li>"What I Would Do With This: Groceries":http://blog.mrmeyer.com/?p=4646<br>The mathematics of grocery shopping.</li>
<li>"Skateistan: To live and skate Kabul":http://vimeo.com/15841377<br>Short movie about a co-educational Skateboarding school in Kabul, Afghanistan.</li>
<li>"Hubris Versus Humility: The $15 billion Difference":http://steveblank.com/2010/11/08/hubris-versus-humility-the-15-billion-difference/<br>While I think that the comparison in this article is a bit apples and oranges, it's an interesting take on initial market positioning.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2010-09-05]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2010/09/05/information-overload-2010-09-05/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2010/09/05/information-overload-2010-09-05</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"Clojure or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Parentheses":http://nathanmarz.com/blog/clojure-or-how-i-learned-to-stop-worrying-and-love-the-paren.html<br>Blog post explaining what draws the author - and many others - to Clojure.</li>
<li>"tactics, tactics, tactics":http://dlowe-wfh.blogspot.com/2007/06/tactics-tactics-tactics.html<br>How to get better at programming. And chess.</li>
<li>"Die Sankore-Schriften":http://www.wissenslogs.de/wblogs/blog/die-sankore-schriften/wissenschaftsgeschichte/2010-08-19/die-sankor-schriften<br>Little history of the Sankore university in Timbuktu, Mali (in German).</li>
<li>"The Making Of: Little Computer People":http://www.next-gen.biz/features/the-making-of-little-computer-people<br>I love video game history, especially when it deals with games who influenced very successful titles later on.</li>
<li>"Sleep Deprivation May Spur Serious Mental Problems, Study Finds":http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2010-08-31/sleep-deprivation-may-trigger-mental-problems-in-young-people-study-finds.html<br>A little reminder to all us geeks, nerds and hackers that sleep does play an important role in our overall well-being.</li>
<li>"Experience: I spent 29 years in solitary confinement":http://www.guardian.co.uk/lifeandstyle/2010/aug/28/29-years-solitary-confinement-robert-king<br>Robert Kind who spent 29 years in solitary confinement for crimes he didn't commit talks about his experience.</li>
<li>"Why can you turn clothing right-side-out?":http://math.stackexchange.com/questions/2755/why-can-you-turn-clothing-right-side-out<br>Math is everywhere.</li>
<li>"Brazilian agriculture:The miracle of the cerrado":http://www.economist.com/node/16886442?story_id=16886442&CFID=142315524&CFTOKEN=99196615<br>Very interesting article on how Brazil transformed itself into one of the world's biggest food exporters.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
