<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-10T15:45:23-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2012 travel review]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/01/09/2012-travel-review/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T13:25:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/01/09/2012-travel-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know it's a bit late for a 2012 review post, but we spent the last couple of days in a wonderfully isolated place on the Chilean coast without an Internet connection. Anyway, I thought better late than never, so here are some thoughts on the first 3 month of our trip.</p>

<p><em>Favorite places visited</em></p>

<p>This is tough, because we visited a lot of very nice places. If I had to choose 3 though, I'd pick Buenos Aires for being an amazing and amazingly chaotic city, the coast around Pichilemu in Chile for being a magical nature paradise (besides one of the world's best surf spots) and Colonia del Sacramento in Uruguay. Sure, the last one is rather touristy, but it deals with it really well and in the evenings you can have the place almost to yourself. The honorable mention goes to the Iguazu Falls, which are absolutely amazing, but somehow don't conjure up as fond memories as the other places.</p>

<p><em>Favorite places stayed in</em></p>

<p>The "Hostal de la Viuda" in Punta del Diablo (Uruguay) was a great place to stay. It's a bit outside town, run by a lovely couple and incredibly hard to leave, because of the nice garden, great common area and the three cute dogs. We also quite enjoyed the "Mate Hostel" in Cordoba, because it's a place run by travelers (from Argentina, Colombia and Germany) for travelers. I shared lots of mate and good conversations with the staff, and it's a very social place where it's easy to meet other backpackers. Another amazing place was the "Surfarm", which is located about 15 minutes by car from Pichilemu (Chile). It's basically a couple of huts right next to the beach in a pretty isolated area. It's the sort of place where time just has no significance and you fall asleep to the sound of the Pacific after looking at the beautiful night sky. The honorable mention goes to the "Casa Pueblo" in Mendoza (Argentina), which is also slightly out of town (there might be a pattern here) and is owned by a very nice young Russian-Argentinian couple who made our Christmas very enjoyable. There's also a special mention in this category, the "Casa Amarilla" in Aregua (Paraguay), which is basically an old colonial house which was turned into an art space/hostel by the two brothers who run it. I'm not sure how much I enjoyed staying there because of the David Lynch atmosphere, but it's fun to wander around the premises and look at the random art pieces that can be found all over the place.</p>

<p><em>Favorite foods</em></p>

<p>Paraguay had quite a few nice vegetarian dishes, although they were mostly bread-based, so a bit heavy on the carbs. Nonetheless, chipa definitely was a great food discovery. While Uruguay is a bit bland on the food side, there's a very old pizza place in Montevideo called "Subte", which serves delicious pizza and faina. Argentina on the other hand mostly stayed in my mind for its sweets: there's some of the best ice cream outside of Italy, and alfajores as well as chocotorta were rather dangerous for my blood sugar levels. My favorite country for food so far definitely was Chile though, since there's more variety than in the other places and it's full of awesome fresh avocados, which are probably my favorite fruit in the world.</p>

<p><em>Biggest positive surprise</em></p>

<p>Definitely Chile, because before we came we hadn't heard too many good things about the place. People mostly complained about how expensive it is and that the locals are not the most friendly people on the planet. However, we found none of that to be true, Chileans have been incredibly friendly and hospitable so far, and we actually find it easier to stay within our budget here than in Argentina. It's also an easier place to travel as a vegetarian because of the abundance of great fresh fruits and vegetables, which is a definite plus for me.</p>

<p><em>Biggest disappointment</em></p>

<p>Probably Curacao. While I have quite a few good memories related to our two weeks there, it wasn't the mindless beach holiday we were after, but actually a rather exhausting backpacking experience. I don't regret that we went, it was very interesting, but it didn't really live up to our expectations.</p>

<p><em>Best decision made</em></p>

<p>Doing a Spanish course early on was definitely the best decision we made on this trip so far! The two weeks at "El Pasaje" in Buenos Aires were great, since we had a very small group (us and a girl from the U.S.) we could progress at a really fast pace, especially since we didn't start from zero. In only 10 days we managed to cover a lot of grammar and, more importantly, had lots of conversations where we actually could use it. I even started reading a book in Spanish now, and while I'm a bit slow and still miss some vocabulary, I actually manage better than I would have expected. Anyway, being able to have proper conversations in Spanish makes this trip a lot more enjoyable, since we interacted a lot with hostel staff, artesanias, local travelers or random people in the streets.</p>

<p>That's it for now, maybe I'll do a similar post in another three month or so.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feliz Navidad!]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/12/24/feliz-navidad/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-24T10:01:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/12/24/feliz-navidad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I even have a present for you, the long overdue post about Uruguay,
one of the highlights of our trip so far!</p>

<p>Our first destination was Montevideo, a city I basically liked from
the very beginning. Which is strange, because it's not necessarily the
prettiest of places. Let me rephrase that: it's a city for the second
look. There's a lot of ugly architecture around, but also tons of nice
old colonial buildings. Add to that tree-lined streets (occasionally
even with cobblestones) and roughly 22km of coast and you have a
pretty neat mix. On top of that Uruguayans are lovely people, very
relaxed, friendly, talkative and with the highest mate consumption in
the world. What's not to like? We also had some great CouchSurfing
hosts, so we met lots of people and had quite an active social life.</p>

<p>After a week though we decided to leave the city behind for a bit, and
headed to the Atlantic coast, more specifically Punta del Diablo, a
charming little town of about 700 inhabitants. At least during low
season, because once high season hits the places grows to over 20000
people. While some may like that, I'm definitely not one of them and
having kilometers of beautiful beaches to ourselves was a great
experience. It's hard to describe the beauty of this place in words
(and I haven't uploaded our pictures yet), but it was very hard to
leave Punta del Diablo. If you ever get a chance to go there, do it,
especially during mid to late November, when the weather is already
good but the place is not overrun by tourists yet.</p>

<p>From the coast we headed back for another weekend in Montevideo,
before setting off to picturesque Colonia de Sacramento, another place
that was hard to leave. True, it can get quite full of tourists, but
somehow the town absorbs them well. Also a lot of them just come on
day trips from Buenos Aires, which means they leave again in the late
afternoon and the old town full of cobblestones, cute little colonial
houses and the friendliest street dogs in the world is all yours
again.</p>

<p>Uruguay, a love affair. And I can't even tell you exactly why. Is it
because the whole country looks like Hobbit Land? Or because the
people are amazingly friendly and welcoming? Or because of the very
relaxed rhythm of life? Probably all of the above, and a bit more
that's hard to put into words. I know this mail is somewhat shorter
than the others and lacks detailed descriptions, but somehow I find it
hard to write about Uruguay. It's not a flashy country full of things
to do and places to visit, but it's beautiful nonetheless and I had a
wonderful time there. Whenever someone mentions it, something in me
just wants to go back there right away...</p>

<p>Anyway, I hope all of you are doing well, I'll try to be faster with
the post about the month we just spent in Argentina!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A first glimpse of Argentina]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/11/21/a-first-glimpse-of-argentina/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T23:37:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/11/21/a-first-glimpse-of-argentina</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ladies and gentlemen,</p>

<p>with a delay of only 3 weeks I present to you our first impressions of
Argentina! As you know by now, our last destination in Paraguay was
charming little Encarnacion, from where you have an excellent view of
Posadas in Argentina. And when I say "excellent", I mean it:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/8139257884/in/set-72157631893001328">http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/8139257884/in/set-72157631893001328</a></p>

<p>Originally we wanted to take a bus on Thursday morning, but since our
CouchSurfing host had an appointment in Posadas on Wednesday he took
us along and so we suddenly found ourselves in Argentina. That was a
rather special moment for me, because it's a country I wanted to visit
for as long as I can remember. I don't even know why exactly, it just
always held a certain attraction... Anyway, Posadas itself is the
capital of the Misiones province, and while it may not be the most
exciting place in the country, it's rather relaxed and has some pretty
spots. And it feels distinctly more urban than most of the places we
saw in Paraguay, which was a welcome change for city rats like us.</p>

<p>Two nights proved to be enough though, so we followed our trusty
friend the Parana river to San Ignacio Mini, a Jesuit mission similar
to the ones found in Trinidad and Jesus in Paraguay. We managed to
catch a tour of the premises (in Spanish) and while the ruins are very
impressive, I think I preferred their Paraguayan counterparts, if only
for the fact that we had the latter basically to ourselves when we
went there, which is quite different from San Ignacio where domestic
tourists are carted in by the busload. Still, if you are in the area,
try to include the mission in your schedule, it's definitely worth it!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/8202692227/in/set-72157632056336739/">http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/8202692227/in/set-72157632056336739/</a></p>

<p>San Ignacio is also where the first terere withdrawal symptoms kicked
in, but luckily one evening we met a guy called Paco, who not only
offered us some mate, but also proved to be good company and an
engaging conversation partner. Since then numerous encounters like
this followed, and it's one of the big differences to traveling in
Asia for me: once you speak a bit of Spanish, the shared European
cultural heritage allows for a level of interaction I never really
managed to attain in any Asian country. Don't get me wrong, I love
traveling in Asia, people there can be as great and friendly as they
are in South America (or even more), but barely ever did I manage to
have such nice and meaningful conversations with locals...</p>

<p>And then: Iguazu! I saw waterfalls before, or so I thought before I
saw Iguazu. It's like nature put on its best Crocodile Dundee
impression and said: "You call that a waterfall? THIS is a waterfall!"</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/8203664696/in/set-72157632056336739">http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/8203664696/in/set-72157632056336739</a></p>

<p>I never thought I'd be this awed by water falling down some rocks, but
I was, and words can't really describe it. Or maybe one word can,
ridiculous, as in ridiculously big/impressive/awesome. The town of
Puerto Iguazu mostly consists of tourist infrastructure and is nothing
to write home about, but there's a cool tri-border point from which
you can see Paraguay and Brazil. There's also a pretty cool animal
sanctuary close by, so if you find yourself with some free time before
catching an overnight bus, give it a go (it's called Guira Oga).</p>

<p>If you know Argentina, you may have noticed something, namely that we
never ventured to far from the Paraguayan border until now, which
means there still was the Parana, the Guarani influence, chipa and
landscapes and vegetation similar to Paraguay. This was about to
change however, since we embarked on our first longer bus trip in
Argentina, namely a 15 hour ride from Puerto Iguazu to Colon in Entre
Rios provice, which is one of the border towns from where you can
cross into Uruguay, which is just what we did. But let's keep that for
another time and go back a little... Long distance buses in Argentina
are good, bordering on awesome. Our "semicama" had good reclining
seats, ample legroom and they even served food, most of which was
vegetarian to my great surprise. They also are rather determined to
get you to your destination, so while our bus didn't really go to
Colon, it was nice enough to drop us off at the point where the road
into town starts, which is what they told us before they would do.
What they omitted however is that said point will be on the highway,
with no real transport into town. So there we were, confused after not
being awake for too long, by the side of a highway in the blazing sun.
Luckily there weren't too many cars, so we managed to cross the 6
lanes without too much trouble and call a remis (a kind of radio taxi)
which took us into town. Colon itself is quite pretty and seems to be
a rather popular destination for domestic tourists, so it was a
pleasant place to spend a day and night (we rented a room from a nice
old lady) before heading to Montevideo.</p>

<p>We spent the past three weeks in Uruguay, a country I'm madly in love
with by now, and about which I'll tell you more soon! Tomorrow we'll
enjoy our last day here, before heading to Buenos Aires on Friday
where my friend Ezequiel is waiting for us! :-)</p>

<p>Oh yeah, I wouldn't be the language nerd I am without at least
mentioning that the Spanish around here (Español rioplatense) is quite
different from the one in Spain (the use of the Voseo, the
pronunciation of "ll" and "y", the melody), but I have to say I really
quite like it. I'd write more about it, but I'm currently in charming
little Colonia del Sacramento, so I'd rather have a walk and expand on
this thought when I tell you about Uruguay and the rest of Argentina...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In the land of Tereré]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/11/12/in-the-land-of-terere/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-12T19:36:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/11/12/in-the-land-of-terere</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Considering we left Paraguay almost three weeks ago, it's a shame I
haven't told you anything about this wonderful place yet. But let's
backtrack for a second and explore how we got to Paraguay. When we
looked for flights out of Curacao, going to Medellin seemed to be the
most obvious choice, considering the flight with Insel Air is dirt
cheap and takes about an hour. However, obvious choices are boring and
we kinda wanted to work our way up from the South of the continent to
the North, so we started looking into other options like Buenos Aires,
Montevideo or Santiago de Chile. But then I found a reasonably priced
flight to Asunción and given my previous wonderful experience in a
place nobody really goes to (Bangladesh) I started liking the idea. So
I introduced the subject to P. and we decided to go ahead and discover
Paraguay. And I'm glad we did!</p>

<p>Let me get one thing straight right away: Asunción is not the most
beautiful city in the world. In fact it's a bit on the ugly side, at
least around the downtown area. Apparently that's because a paranoid
dictator had all tall buildings torn down because he was afraid of
assassins hiding in them, but I'm not entirely sure that's true. It's
a pretty good story though. There are some beautiful old colonial
buildings left, but since there's not a lot of money to go around,
they are usually in a state of disrepair (or worse). There are however
some nicer modern neighborhoods like Villa Morra where we stayed with
a wonderful CouchSurfing host. Anyway, Asunción's a rather relaxed
South American capital, that feels safe and is full of wonderful,
helpful and welcoming people.</p>

<p>People who drink Tereré, all day, every day. Tereré I hear you ask?
It's basically like Mate, but made with ice-cold water and generally
with some extra herbs like mint added. It's refreshing, delicious, and
since you pass it around it's also a wonderful way to spend a couple
of hours with some friends while drinking and chatting. Which we did
quite a bit, for example with our friend Javier who just opened a
beautiful little <a href="https://www.facebook.com/LaCasitaDeLaAbuelaHostalVerde">hostel</a> close to Asunción's downtown which you
definitely should check out if given the chance! Anyway, for
Paraguayans Tereré is more than just a drink, it's an integral part of
their culture and you'll see lots of people carrying around a thermos
at all times of day. They also always asked us we already had tried it
and were delighted to find out that we did and that we actually love
it!</p>

<p>Another vivid memory of Asunción are the public buses, which are
<a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_dB1Xz3aYcZY/SN6diZeTBWI/AAAAAAAAANQ/gZWIsf_86QE/s400/BUS.JPG">colorful</a> and full of people selling all kinds of things (food, drinks,
little knickknacks). Also they don't really bother to stop for letting
people get on or off, they just kinda slow down and give you a chance
to practice your Ninja skills.</p>

<p>Now for one of my favorite topics, food: Paraguay was surprisingly ok
for a vegetarian. Not great and I had to eat a lot of carbs, but I
managed. While the modern Paraguayan diet is centered around meat, a
lot of the traditional dishes are vegetarian. This means that I
basically lived off <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sopa_paraguaya">Sopa Paraguaya</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chipa_Guasu">Chipa Guasu</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chipa">Chipa</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mbeju">Mbeju</a> and
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Torta_pasqualina">Pasqualina</a>. Fruit juices were ok too, but unfortunately they add sugar to them
unless you stop them, which is common in the region and something I
absolutely don't understand. We also cooked quite a bit for ourselves
which was rather nice since supermarkets are quite well-stocked and
carry lots of Italian-style products. They also offer quite a few
different soy-based "meats", which despite not being my favorite way
of eating soy is a rather convenient way to get some protein in your
diet.</p>

<p>Language-wise Paraguay also was rather interesting. While the city
population mostly speak Spanish (more on that later), Guaraní is still
the most common language in rural areas. The local accent was rather
easy to understand, although a lot of people mix in some Guaraní
words. Anyway, it was a good place to improve my listening skills, and
while I'm still far from being able to hold my own in an interesting
conversation, I'm definitely improving.</p>

<p>From Asunción we did a day trip to Areguá, a nice little village with
a stunning lake, a beautiful church placed on a picturesque hill and
lots of handicrafts. We stayed in the "Casa Amarilla", which is an old
colonial house that's part hostel and part art space and looks like
something out of a David Lynch movie. We also met a couple of nice
Argentinians who not only gave us a lift back to Asunción but also
invited us to stay with them in Corrientes, an offer we might take
them up on next month.</p>

<p>We then moved on to the pretty little border town of Encarnación,
which has a pretty costanera from where you can actually see Posadas
in Argentina. Nearby there are the stunning Jesuit ruins of Trinidad
and Jesús, and since Paraguay isn't exactly overrun by tourists, we
basically had them all to ourselves when we went there, which made me
feel a bit like Indiana Jones. Our CouchSurfing host also took us to
Itacua, a famous local religious site, which had some gorgeous views.
He also was kind enough to drive us over the bridge to Argentina,
which made for one of the more interesting border crossings of my
life. The border guard first looked confused when he got two
Paraguayan ID cards, as well as an Austrian and Italian passport, but
then stamped us in without so much as properly looking at us.</p>

<p>I guess that's enough for now, I'll soon write something about
Northeastern Argentina, where we spent around a week before moving on
to Uruguay from where I'm currently writing this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A quick one for the road]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/10/31/a-quick-one-for-the-road/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-31T19:30:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/10/31/a-quick-one-for-the-road</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a lovely time in Paraguay (a separate post will follow), we explored the Northeast of Argentina a bit (Posadas, San Ignacio,
Iguazu Falls). Today we'll take an overnight bus to Colon were we'll cross into Paysandu (Uruguay) on Friday or so. We don't know how long we'll stay there yet, but after that we'll head back to Argentina to finally visit some cities.</p>

<p>Here's some pictures for now:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157631752795045/">Curacao</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157631893001328/">Paraguay</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
