<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-21T19:07:06-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mix it up!]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/02/13/mix-it-up/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-13T18:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/02/13/mix-it-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know I didn't write in way too long (and I still didn't talk about Argentina and Chile), but that just happens when you are traveling. Especially when that takes you to Bolivia, where Internet connection speeds are still stuck in the 1990s.</p>

<p>Anyway, we made it to our 5th South American country now, and after 3.5 month in the Cono Sur, this feels distinctly more "foreign". That's probably related to the fact that 60% of the population are indigenous, so there are a lot less European looking people than in Argentina or Chile. Many of the women still wear traditional dress, and coca is quite omnipresent, be it in the form of tea (mate de coca), sweets or as leaves. All of them are supposed to help with altitude sickness, and considering that we never really went below 2500m since we got here (and up to 5000m maximum) we've consumed our fair share too. And I strongly deny all rumors that I actually enjoy chewing coca, it's purely for medical purposes... ;-)</p>

<p>But let's go back to the beginning: on February 2nd we crossed into Bolivia at the La Quiaca/Villazon border, and after having heard terrible stories of hour long waits, we considered ourselves lucky to have made it across in roughly 45 minutes. Alas we later realized that the border guards on the Bolivian side had only changed the day on their stamps but not the month, so our entry stamp actually said January 2nd and you only get 30 days when entering overland. We managed to get this fixed in an immigration office afterwards, the guys working there were pretty amused about what the "idiotas" (quote) at the border did.</p>

<p>From Villazon we took a shared cab to Tupiza, where we spoiled ourselves with a stay in a rather nice hotel. Bolivia is cheap though, so we spent less money for it than we did for dorm beds in Argentina, Uruguay or Chile. The landscape around Tupiza is absolutely stunning, and exploring it on horseback definitely made me feel like Butch Cassady or the Sundance Kid, who by the way weren't shot too far from there. After a couple of relaxed days we embarked on a 4 day tour of the so-called South West Circuit, which ended at the Salar de Uyuni, the world's biggest salt flat. It's hard to put what we saw into words, when we get to a place with a faster Internet connection again I'll try to upload some pictures. One really remarkable thing about the tour was Silvia the cook though, who managed to prepare awesome meals with very limited time, space and equipment. She also made some of the best vegetarian food I've had in South America so far, which is why I still kinda regret not having kidnapped her. I definitely could do with my own personal cook who knows how to prepare veggie meals... After the tour we made our way via Potosi to beautiful Sucre, where we have been kicking back since last Saturday. And by "kicking back" I actually mean hiding in our guest house like most gringos, since the local carnival tradition involves water bombs, buckets of water, shaving foam and an utter lack of sympathy for people who have barely any clothes to begin with. Luckily this is over now, so we can actually fully enjoy the city before heading to La Paz.</p>

<p>After almost two weeks in Bolivia, my feelings are a bit mixed. Before we came, everyone told us how awesome it is, and from a landscape point of view I can wholeheartedly agree. What I miss though is interacting with the locals, which was a lot easier in the Cono Sur than it is here. First off there are lots of Quechua and Aymara speakers, but also the Spanish speakers are more reserved than they were further South, so we barely ever manage to have interesting conversations with locals. But that's not the only thing that makes you feel like you are suddenly on the "gringo trail": the restaurants mostly serve a rather uninspired mix of western "favorites" and even the banana pancake found its way from Southeast Asia to here. There's also a lot more younger and/or obnoxious backpackers around, which I mostly attribute to the fact that Bolivia is considerably cheaper than the South, while still boasting a well-developed tourist infrastructure.</p>

<p>One thing I really like about this trip is how diverse it is: we stayed in hostels, hotels, B&amp;Bs, rented a room from an old lady, used CouchSurfing and AirBnB and stayed with friends. We crossed borders via plane, private car (thanks Mencho!), bus, boat and by walking. We dipped our feet in both the Atlantic and the Pacific, saw volcanoes, salt flats and the world's driest desert. I did my first longer trip on horseback, and also took my first surfing lesson. We learned a new language (Spanish) and got to use all the other ones we know, including Turkish, my very limited Swedish and even Mandarin (twice in Buenos Aires). All this variation makes traveling for a long time a lot more interesting and helps with not getting tired of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cono Sur reflections]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/01/25/cono-sur-reflections/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-25T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/01/25/cono-sur-reflections</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know I'm far behind on telling you about the places we visited, but
I will eventually catch up, or at least I hope so. For now I wanted to
reflect a bit on the past 3.5 month, which we spent in the Cono Sur
(Southern Cone), which <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Southern_Cone">according to Wikipedia</a> "has traditionally
comprised Argentina, Chile, Paraguay, and Uruguay".</p>

<p>So, where to start? Let's say, I always thought of myself as an Asia
person. Considering I studied Chinese at university, that may not be
surprising, but whenever I went to Asia, I kinda felt at home. Or more
so than in Europe at least. But in the last 10 or so years my interest
in traveling Latin America steadily increased, and now that I'm
finally here, I'm reconsidering the "Asia person" thing. Sure, I love
travelling there, but Latin America (or more specifically the parts we
saw so far), are very fascinating for a different reason, mainly that
some of them feel a lot like alternative versions of Europe. Maybe
that isn't the best description, but what I mean to say is that
there's a shared cultural heritage between Europe and here, which
makes it much easier to actually have meaningful conversations with
people. On top of that there's only one language you need to learn
(unless you are going to Brazil or the Guyanas) to be able to travel
from almost the Antarctic to the Southern border of the US.</p>

<p>But there are also certain cultural differences that I appreciate:
first off, there's a lot of left-wing politics going on, which makes
me quite happy. Sure, the left may not always be in power, but it has
a good grassroots presence (trade unions, student groups, squats). I
also found that people started to consider Latin America as a global
player in its own right, which can compete with the EU and the US in
the medium term (at least some countries). Anyway, this is not
supposed to turn into a political rant... Another thing I like is how
open people are and how much life takes place in the streets. Any
random walk to a park can turn into an adventure, full of random
conversations and tons of entertainments provided by jugglers and
other street performers. I'm sure the better weather plays a role in
this, but also the general attitude of people to live parts of their
private lives in the open makes a huge difference. You also can see a
lot of enterprising people in the streets, from shoe shiners, over
food stalls, used book sellers, artesanias and fruit sellers to guys
peddling vegan brownies or puppet performances for children. I know a
lot of them do this in lack of better options, but for others
(especially the artensanias) it's a way to do what they really like
while being able to travel. As one girl selling handmade jewelry (and
who has been traveling for almost 10 years) just told us a couple of
days ago: "¡No the preocupes, te ocupes!" (freely translated: "Don't
worry, do something!"). I don't know how to say this exactly, but
there's a certain energy here that I miss back home. Sure, people here
complain a lot too (and they have every right to in some cases), but
they still seem to believe in being able to change their own destiny.
Probably this has to do with one of my pet peeves about Austrian
people, who constantly complain without acknowledging enough that they
are among the luckiest people on this planet for a lot of things. The
bottom line is that i'm rather fond of people here, and while there
obviously are big differences between e.g. Paraguayans and Chileans,
the things I mentioned above could be recognized in all the places we
visited so far to some degree.</p>

<p>Of course not everything is perfect: One of the most disturbing things
is the huge inequality found in basically all societies here. While some people
are incredibly rich, others literally live off their garbage.
Argentina for example is sliding back into a big crisis, and there's a
lot of very visible poverty around, more than in some Asian countries
I visited in the past. Also things don't always run as smoothly as
they could, mostly because in quite a lot of cases you can observe a
"good enough" attitude. Sure, you don't always have to strive for
perfection, but sometimes it just seems like someone started out with
a great idea, but stopped implementing it at about 95% for no apparent
reason. Last but not least people here seem to have a difficult time
with silence, so you are quite likely to end up in a beautiful spot in
the middle of nowhere, just to have a guy turn up with some bad <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tecnocumbia">Cumbia</a>
blasting from the crappy speakers of his mobile phone. Seriously
people, what's wrong with using headphones?</p>

<p>Anyway, I'm quite in love with this part of our planet now, the
combination of beautiful nature, interesting cities and wonderfully
open people is rather hard to beat. We are supposed to arrive in
Bolivia in about a week, let's see how/if my perceptions will change
there.</p>

<p>That's it for now, in case you haven't seen them before, here are the
links to the pictures of the Cono Sur part of our trip:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157631893001328/">Paraguay</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157632358056523/">Uruguay</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157632056336739/">Argentina</a>
(pictures of the first and second stay, the third one is still
missing)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157632598354471/">Chile</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2012 travel review]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/01/09/2012-travel-review/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T13:25:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/01/09/2012-travel-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know it's a bit late for a 2012 review post, but we spent the last couple of days in a wonderfully isolated place on the Chilean coast without an Internet connection. Anyway, I thought better late than never, so here are some thoughts on the first 3 month of our trip.</p>

<p><em>Favorite places visited</em></p>

<p>This is tough, because we visited a lot of very nice places. If I had to choose 3 though, I'd pick Buenos Aires for being an amazing and amazingly chaotic city, the coast around Pichilemu in Chile for being a magical nature paradise (besides one of the world's best surf spots) and Colonia del Sacramento in Uruguay. Sure, the last one is rather touristy, but it deals with it really well and in the evenings you can have the place almost to yourself. The honorable mention goes to the Iguazu Falls, which are absolutely amazing, but somehow don't conjure up as fond memories as the other places.</p>

<p><em>Favorite places stayed in</em></p>

<p>The "Hostal de la Viuda" in Punta del Diablo (Uruguay) was a great place to stay. It's a bit outside town, run by a lovely couple and incredibly hard to leave, because of the nice garden, great common area and the three cute dogs. We also quite enjoyed the "Mate Hostel" in Cordoba, because it's a place run by travelers (from Argentina, Colombia and Germany) for travelers. I shared lots of mate and good conversations with the staff, and it's a very social place where it's easy to meet other backpackers. Another amazing place was the "Surfarm", which is located about 15 minutes by car from Pichilemu (Chile). It's basically a couple of huts right next to the beach in a pretty isolated area. It's the sort of place where time just has no significance and you fall asleep to the sound of the Pacific after looking at the beautiful night sky. The honorable mention goes to the "Casa Pueblo" in Mendoza (Argentina), which is also slightly out of town (there might be a pattern here) and is owned by a very nice young Russian-Argentinian couple who made our Christmas very enjoyable. There's also a special mention in this category, the "Casa Amarilla" in Aregua (Paraguay), which is basically an old colonial house which was turned into an art space/hostel by the two brothers who run it. I'm not sure how much I enjoyed staying there because of the David Lynch atmosphere, but it's fun to wander around the premises and look at the random art pieces that can be found all over the place.</p>

<p><em>Favorite foods</em></p>

<p>Paraguay had quite a few nice vegetarian dishes, although they were mostly bread-based, so a bit heavy on the carbs. Nonetheless, chipa definitely was a great food discovery. While Uruguay is a bit bland on the food side, there's a very old pizza place in Montevideo called "Subte", which serves delicious pizza and faina. Argentina on the other hand mostly stayed in my mind for its sweets: there's some of the best ice cream outside of Italy, and alfajores as well as chocotorta were rather dangerous for my blood sugar levels. My favorite country for food so far definitely was Chile though, since there's more variety than in the other places and it's full of awesome fresh avocados, which are probably my favorite fruit in the world.</p>

<p><em>Biggest positive surprise</em></p>

<p>Definitely Chile, because before we came we hadn't heard too many good things about the place. People mostly complained about how expensive it is and that the locals are not the most friendly people on the planet. However, we found none of that to be true, Chileans have been incredibly friendly and hospitable so far, and we actually find it easier to stay within our budget here than in Argentina. It's also an easier place to travel as a vegetarian because of the abundance of great fresh fruits and vegetables, which is a definite plus for me.</p>

<p><em>Biggest disappointment</em></p>

<p>Probably Curacao. While I have quite a few good memories related to our two weeks there, it wasn't the mindless beach holiday we were after, but actually a rather exhausting backpacking experience. I don't regret that we went, it was very interesting, but it didn't really live up to our expectations.</p>

<p><em>Best decision made</em></p>

<p>Doing a Spanish course early on was definitely the best decision we made on this trip so far! The two weeks at "El Pasaje" in Buenos Aires were great, since we had a very small group (us and a girl from the U.S.) we could progress at a really fast pace, especially since we didn't start from zero. In only 10 days we managed to cover a lot of grammar and, more importantly, had lots of conversations where we actually could use it. I even started reading a book in Spanish now, and while I'm a bit slow and still miss some vocabulary, I actually manage better than I would have expected. Anyway, being able to have proper conversations in Spanish makes this trip a lot more enjoyable, since we interacted a lot with hostel staff, artesanias, local travelers or random people in the streets.</p>

<p>That's it for now, maybe I'll do a similar post in another three month or so.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feliz Navidad!]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/12/24/feliz-navidad/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-24T10:01:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/12/24/feliz-navidad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I even have a present for you, the long overdue post about Uruguay,
one of the highlights of our trip so far!</p>

<p>Our first destination was Montevideo, a city I basically liked from
the very beginning. Which is strange, because it's not necessarily the
prettiest of places. Let me rephrase that: it's a city for the second
look. There's a lot of ugly architecture around, but also tons of nice
old colonial buildings. Add to that tree-lined streets (occasionally
even with cobblestones) and roughly 22km of coast and you have a
pretty neat mix. On top of that Uruguayans are lovely people, very
relaxed, friendly, talkative and with the highest mate consumption in
the world. What's not to like? We also had some great CouchSurfing
hosts, so we met lots of people and had quite an active social life.</p>

<p>After a week though we decided to leave the city behind for a bit, and
headed to the Atlantic coast, more specifically Punta del Diablo, a
charming little town of about 700 inhabitants. At least during low
season, because once high season hits the places grows to over 20000
people. While some may like that, I'm definitely not one of them and
having kilometers of beautiful beaches to ourselves was a great
experience. It's hard to describe the beauty of this place in words
(and I haven't uploaded our pictures yet), but it was very hard to
leave Punta del Diablo. If you ever get a chance to go there, do it,
especially during mid to late November, when the weather is already
good but the place is not overrun by tourists yet.</p>

<p>From the coast we headed back for another weekend in Montevideo,
before setting off to picturesque Colonia de Sacramento, another place
that was hard to leave. True, it can get quite full of tourists, but
somehow the town absorbs them well. Also a lot of them just come on
day trips from Buenos Aires, which means they leave again in the late
afternoon and the old town full of cobblestones, cute little colonial
houses and the friendliest street dogs in the world is all yours
again.</p>

<p>Uruguay, a love affair. And I can't even tell you exactly why. Is it
because the whole country looks like Hobbit Land? Or because the
people are amazingly friendly and welcoming? Or because of the very
relaxed rhythm of life? Probably all of the above, and a bit more
that's hard to put into words. I know this mail is somewhat shorter
than the others and lacks detailed descriptions, but somehow I find it
hard to write about Uruguay. It's not a flashy country full of things
to do and places to visit, but it's beautiful nonetheless and I had a
wonderful time there. Whenever someone mentions it, something in me
just wants to go back there right away...</p>

<p>Anyway, I hope all of you are doing well, I'll try to be faster with
the post about the month we just spent in Argentina!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A first glimpse of Argentina]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/11/21/a-first-glimpse-of-argentina/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T23:37:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/11/21/a-first-glimpse-of-argentina</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ladies and gentlemen,</p>

<p>with a delay of only 3 weeks I present to you our first impressions of
Argentina! As you know by now, our last destination in Paraguay was
charming little Encarnacion, from where you have an excellent view of
Posadas in Argentina. And when I say "excellent", I mean it:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/8139257884/in/set-72157631893001328">http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/8139257884/in/set-72157631893001328</a></p>

<p>Originally we wanted to take a bus on Thursday morning, but since our
CouchSurfing host had an appointment in Posadas on Wednesday he took
us along and so we suddenly found ourselves in Argentina. That was a
rather special moment for me, because it's a country I wanted to visit
for as long as I can remember. I don't even know why exactly, it just
always held a certain attraction... Anyway, Posadas itself is the
capital of the Misiones province, and while it may not be the most
exciting place in the country, it's rather relaxed and has some pretty
spots. And it feels distinctly more urban than most of the places we
saw in Paraguay, which was a welcome change for city rats like us.</p>

<p>Two nights proved to be enough though, so we followed our trusty
friend the Parana river to San Ignacio Mini, a Jesuit mission similar
to the ones found in Trinidad and Jesus in Paraguay. We managed to
catch a tour of the premises (in Spanish) and while the ruins are very
impressive, I think I preferred their Paraguayan counterparts, if only
for the fact that we had the latter basically to ourselves when we
went there, which is quite different from San Ignacio where domestic
tourists are carted in by the busload. Still, if you are in the area,
try to include the mission in your schedule, it's definitely worth it!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/8202692227/in/set-72157632056336739/">http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/8202692227/in/set-72157632056336739/</a></p>

<p>San Ignacio is also where the first terere withdrawal symptoms kicked
in, but luckily one evening we met a guy called Paco, who not only
offered us some mate, but also proved to be good company and an
engaging conversation partner. Since then numerous encounters like
this followed, and it's one of the big differences to traveling in
Asia for me: once you speak a bit of Spanish, the shared European
cultural heritage allows for a level of interaction I never really
managed to attain in any Asian country. Don't get me wrong, I love
traveling in Asia, people there can be as great and friendly as they
are in South America (or even more), but barely ever did I manage to
have such nice and meaningful conversations with locals...</p>

<p>And then: Iguazu! I saw waterfalls before, or so I thought before I
saw Iguazu. It's like nature put on its best Crocodile Dundee
impression and said: "You call that a waterfall? THIS is a waterfall!"</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/8203664696/in/set-72157632056336739">http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/8203664696/in/set-72157632056336739</a></p>

<p>I never thought I'd be this awed by water falling down some rocks, but
I was, and words can't really describe it. Or maybe one word can,
ridiculous, as in ridiculously big/impressive/awesome. The town of
Puerto Iguazu mostly consists of tourist infrastructure and is nothing
to write home about, but there's a cool tri-border point from which
you can see Paraguay and Brazil. There's also a pretty cool animal
sanctuary close by, so if you find yourself with some free time before
catching an overnight bus, give it a go (it's called Guira Oga).</p>

<p>If you know Argentina, you may have noticed something, namely that we
never ventured to far from the Paraguayan border until now, which
means there still was the Parana, the Guarani influence, chipa and
landscapes and vegetation similar to Paraguay. This was about to
change however, since we embarked on our first longer bus trip in
Argentina, namely a 15 hour ride from Puerto Iguazu to Colon in Entre
Rios provice, which is one of the border towns from where you can
cross into Uruguay, which is just what we did. But let's keep that for
another time and go back a little... Long distance buses in Argentina
are good, bordering on awesome. Our "semicama" had good reclining
seats, ample legroom and they even served food, most of which was
vegetarian to my great surprise. They also are rather determined to
get you to your destination, so while our bus didn't really go to
Colon, it was nice enough to drop us off at the point where the road
into town starts, which is what they told us before they would do.
What they omitted however is that said point will be on the highway,
with no real transport into town. So there we were, confused after not
being awake for too long, by the side of a highway in the blazing sun.
Luckily there weren't too many cars, so we managed to cross the 6
lanes without too much trouble and call a remis (a kind of radio taxi)
which took us into town. Colon itself is quite pretty and seems to be
a rather popular destination for domestic tourists, so it was a
pleasant place to spend a day and night (we rented a room from a nice
old lady) before heading to Montevideo.</p>

<p>We spent the past three weeks in Uruguay, a country I'm madly in love
with by now, and about which I'll tell you more soon! Tomorrow we'll
enjoy our last day here, before heading to Buenos Aires on Friday
where my friend Ezequiel is waiting for us! :-)</p>

<p>Oh yeah, I wouldn't be the language nerd I am without at least
mentioning that the Spanish around here (Español rioplatense) is quite
different from the one in Spain (the use of the Voseo, the
pronunciation of "ll" and "y", the melody), but I have to say I really
quite like it. I'd write more about it, but I'm currently in charming
little Colonia del Sacramento, so I'd rather have a walk and expand on
this thought when I tell you about Uruguay and the rest of Argentina...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
