<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-24T23:57:51+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Great, greater, Greater China!]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/09/08/great-greater-greater-china/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-08T00:10:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/09/08/great-greater-greater-china</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By now it&rsquo;s quite standard that my posts lack behind my travels&hellip; This update is no exception, it&rsquo;s about our travels from end of June to end of July.</p>

<p>The topic: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greater_China">Greater China</a>, or more precisely Shanghai, Taiwan and Hong Kong.</p>

<p>But let&rsquo;s start from the beginning. In Cali (Colombia) we figured it&rsquo;s about time to figure out how we&rsquo;d get from the Americas to Asia. It was pretty clear that we&rsquo;d have to go through the US, and since A. and V. were not in San Francisco at the dates we were looking at, we decided to visit C. in Los Angeles. After a bit of searching I found a great flight from LAX to Taipei with a 20h layover in Shanghai. P. had
never considered going to Taiwan before, but to her credit it didn&rsquo;t take much convincing and we booked the flight that same evening. Considering that in a past life (or so it seems) I studied Sinology, I did find this quite exciting, after all I studied Taiwan academically
but had never set foot in the country. I also dreaded using my rusty Mandarin again.</p>

<p>Not looking forward to spending 20h at the airport, I did a little online search and found out that Beijing and Shanghai now have free 72h transit visas on arrival. Jackpot, especially since I studied in Shanghai and was quite stoked to see the city again. So after a couple of awesome and eventful days in LA (thanks again C., especially for taking us to the Bradbury building of Blade Runner fame!) we boarded our flight and arrived in China 14h later. We were quite jetlagged and tired, but we still bothered to go into the city, where we found a
nice little hotel off Nanjing Lu close to the Bund. Before we collapsed we managed to have a nice dinner and a bit of a walk and I remembered why I originally fell in love with this city that I called home for a year. I definitely want to go back for a longer stay at one point&hellip;</p>

<p>The next day we arrived in Taipei where we had booked accommodation via AirBnB and a new love affair started almost immediately (yes, I&rsquo;m a bit of a place whore, deal with it). Over the years I&rsquo;ve heard many great things about the city, but yet it still somehow managed to exceed my expectations. It&rsquo;s cool (teenagers have a pretty Japanese style), it&rsquo;s modern, it&rsquo;s quirky, and the food is awesome. If you need a break, places like Beitou (very cool public library) or Tamsui are an easy MRT ride away, or you just go to a park and watch old people practice Qi Gong or Tai Chi. Coincidentally one of P.&rsquo;s friends was in Taipei at the same time as us and we explored the Confucius temple and some other parts together. After a couple of days my friend Ph. arrived from Vienna and kept us company for the next two weeks.</p>

<p>With him we explored more of Taipei, before heading off to Keelong. Which would be transcribed as Jilong in the official Chinese Hanyu Pinyin system, but the Taiwanese seem to use about 5 different systems at the same time, of which at least 2 appear to have been made up solely for the purpose of confusing foreigners. For the rest of this mail I will just go with the transcriptions most commonly found in travel guides, but I digress&hellip; Anyway, Keelong was fun. Not the prettiest of towns, but some nice things to see and an awesome night food market. We spent the afternoon with a friendly but slightly insane taxi driver, and at night we found a group of breakdancers to watch. What more can you reasonably expect from a day trip?</p>

<p>The next day we went on to Hualien, where once again we stuffed our faces at a night market. Or several, since we first ended up at the wrong one, where 2 young employees at a food stall were so relieved that they managed to deal with 3 foreigners, that they actually high-fived when we walked away with our food. After we finished our meal they got daring and ventured a &ldquo;Good food happy?&rdquo; at us. &ldquo;my friends, "happy happy!&rdquo; indeed. The next day was reserved for the famous Taroko Gorge, but a shitty bus service, bad weather and the unfriendliest bus driver of the country made it a rather disappointing experience. You win some, you lose some&hellip;</p>

<p>Our next stop was Lukang, where we spent a couple of very pleasant days eating (do you see a pattern here?) and exploring old temples. We then headed down to Tainan, where we basically did the same. More food, more temples. Then maybe a snack. How about another temple? My favorite part of Tainan was <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anping_District">Anping</a>, which is definitely worth checking out if you ever make it there.</p>

<p>We now were approaching the end of Ph.&rsquo;s time with us, and I&rsquo;m glad he managed to at least get a glimpse of Kaohsiung, one of my favorite new places. I can&rsquo;t even tell you why exactly, I just really liked it there. Sure, food&rsquo;s awesome, but that&rsquo;s basically a given in Taiwan. The people are amazingly friendly, but that&rsquo;s pretty much standard too. I guess what I like is the overall feel of the place, which is rather relaxed. And artsy. Kaohsiung used to be an industrial town, but most of that industry disappeared. Thanks to a former mayor the
old factories and warehouses on the docks now serve as amazingcontemporary art spaces. We came for 3 days, we stayed for a week, andwho knows, without the flight to Vietnam we had already booked at thattime, I might still be there&hellip;</p>

<p>Our last stop before returning to Taipei for 3 more awesome days wasTaitung, or rather the countryside around it. Taiwan&rsquo;s east coast isfar less developed than other parts of the country, but reallybeautiful. Since our hostel had free bikes we managed to explore thearea a bit, alas a second taifun was about to hit (the first onecaught Ph. in Taipei) and so the weather wasn&rsquo;t exactly great. Atleast we had a great hostel to return to, run by a lovely family,which made us drink way more tea than I thought a human bladder canhold.</p>

<p>If it wasn&rsquo;t obvious enough yet, Taiwan was one of my favoritedestinations on this trip. The people are just amazingly friendly!Sure, not everybody will speak English, but even then they will stilltry to help you. Or at least smile at you. The food is excellent. Yes,I write about food a lot. Food matters! There&rsquo;s plenty of old templesaround, actually more than in most parts of China that I visited. Andalongside the old there&rsquo;s the new. Taiwan has many art and culturespaces, and a vibrant youth culture that borrows liberally from &ldquo;thewest&rdquo; as well as from Japan. In a way, our stay there made merediscover my love for the Chinese world, which had died down a bitafter university. I even got back into speaking Mandarin, and while itwas far from perfect, it usually was good enough (or the Taiwanese arejust amazing at reading body language in combination with nonsensicalphrases.) If you are looking for an intro to the Chinese culturalsphere that&rsquo;s easier than the mainland, I can wholeheartedly recommend Taiwan!</p>

<p>After the weeks of relative tranquillity, Hong Kong (one of myfavorite places ever) was quite the change. It&rsquo;s louder, busier, andmore stressful. On a superficial look it&rsquo;s all modern and businesslike, but if you dig deeper, you&rsquo;ll still find bits and pieces of oldworking-class Hong Kong. And if you want a break, you can always justflee up Hong Kong hill or head out to Lantau to visit the peacefulfishing village of Tai O. We stayed in Chungking Mansions(<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chungking_Mansions">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chungking_Mansions</a>), which despite therecent renovations is still a rather unique place. After all thisplace had a book written about it, the aptly named &ldquo;Ghetto at theCenter of the World&rdquo;. Another nerd dream came true when we visited theonly Studio Ghibli store outside Japan, where we took pictures withTotoro and in the Catbus. Yes, I was inside the Catbus, how cool isthat? Unfortunately the weather was really bad during most of ourstay, so P. didn&rsquo;t get to fully enjoy HK, which is a bit of a shame.Oh well, guess that means I will have to take her back at one point&hellip;</p>

<p>Photos I hear you say? Here you go:<br>
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157635271645014/">Taiwan</a><br>
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157635262034054/">Hong Kong</a></p>

<p>Confucius say &ldquo;Be good and travel more!&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[¡Viva Mexico!]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/07/27/viva-mexico/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-27T20:04:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/07/27/viva-mexico</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh man, this is one overdue post. I wanted to write about Mexico forever, but then we were traveling in Taiwan, and suddenly the whole Latin America experience just seemed so far away already&hellip; Anyway, we are now in Vietnam (Hanoi to be more specific), so I thought I&rsquo;d finally sit down and write up my impressions.</p>

<p>Mexico was one of the places I wanted to visit for a long time, so before we went, I was a bit nervous that it may not live up to my expectations. But not only did it do that, it actually far exceeded them! There are fantastic things to see, the food is exceptionally good (also for vegetarians) and the people amazingly friendly. Also it felt like a really safe and easy place to travel: as opposed to big parts of South America the security situation in Mexico is pretty relaxed, even though stuff does of course happen. On top of that there are good roads everywhere and ADO is a very nice bus company, so we generally didn&rsquo;t dread moving from A to B. With that said it&rsquo;s quite unfortunate we only had 4 weeks there, but we had booked the flight to Taiwan beforehand in order to avoid getting stuck in the Americas for all of our trip. Turns out that was a good idea, because Mexico alone could easily have kept me entertained for several more month.</p>

<p>Our trip started in Tulum, which features a beautiful beach and a cute little set of ruins. Unfortunately Chaak (the Mayan rain god) wasn&rsquo;t on our side, so we only managed to get one and a half proper beach days. On the upside we got to taste tons of good food and also explore the nearby ruins of Coba. We then went to lovely Valladolid and the ruins of Ek Balam, both of which are a bit overlooked by tourists (or just crammed in on day tours). I&rsquo;m glad we stayed there, a super relaxed little town, and the ruins were among my favorites in Mexico. Next stop was Merida, which is a decent place in itself, but also the gateway to the ruins of Uxmal. A decent place, but slightly tainted by the memory of annoyingly obnoxious hostel neighbors. If you&rsquo;ve been to Mexico before and wonder, yes, we did in fact skip Chichen Itza. Based on the feedback of people we met, it really did not seem worth the effort in time and money. Instead we decided to give another little and often overlooked town a chance, and I&rsquo;m definitely happy that we went to Campeche. Quiet, with a small but pretty old town and very down to earth, this is the sort of place I really came to enjoy on this journey, and not only for the lack of a specific type of backpacker I detest. After this brief stop we went on to Palenque, a set of ruins I had heard lots about, and which I found to be a bit disappointing. Letting vendors onto the premises really doesn&rsquo;t add to the atmosphere, even if they don&rsquo;t hassle you&hellip; At least the setting of our hostel was very scenic, in that small cluster of hostels right at the beginning of the national park. The next stop was one of my absolute favorites, San Cristobal de las Casas where we ended up staying almost twice as long as we originally planned. True, it&rsquo;s small, but thanks to several cultural centers there&rsquo;s a surprising lot to do in town. It&rsquo;s also Zapatista heartland, so if you have any interest in the EZLN, this is THE place to be. Our trip to the coast around Puerto Escondido got canceled due to a hurricane, so we went straight to Oaxaca instead, which was also quite nice. Unfortunately P. got sick, so I mostly explored it by myself including a Mezcal factory, a petrified waterfall, and of course more ruins. Last but certainly not least was the D.F. (Distrito Federal), more commonly know as Mexico City outside of the country. You have to understand that I wanted to visit this city since my elementary school days, when I first heard that it&rsquo;s the biggest in the world. It may not be anymore, but it&rsquo;s still one of the most interesting places I ever visited. It&rsquo;s hard to put the city into words, but it has everything: the old, the new, the very poor, the super rich. It&rsquo;s a giant, it&rsquo;s a moloch, and yet, it&rsquo;s lovely. While not all of it is pretty, the parts that are, really are. When you walk into Coyoacan or San Angel for the first time, it&rsquo;s hard to believe that they are part of Mexico City at all. And given the size of the place, it&rsquo;s incredibly how friendly and helpful most of the people still are. BTW, thanks again for dinner and a great chat Hector! It&rsquo;s hard to put Mexico City into words, you better go there yourself!</p>

<p>No post about Mexico could be complete without a separate mention of the food. I always considered Mexican cuisine to be one of my favorites, but I wasn&rsquo;t sure how authentic it was. Turns out that the things we know like tacos, burritos, quesadillas, enchilladas, fajitas, and guacamole traveled rather well to Europe, although unfortunately we can&rsquo;t find them at tasty little street stalls where they are almost ridiculously cheap at times. But there&rsquo;s just so much more: sope, gorditas, molletes, tortas, papadzules, brazo de reina, tlayudas, and a ton of delicious things I can&rsquo;t remember the name of. Just writing about it now makes we want to go back right away&hellip;</p>

<p>Mexico definitely was one of the highlights of this trip for me (actually of all my travels so far), I&rsquo;d instantly go back.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[South America: The summary]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/05/31/south-america-the-summary/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-31T17:52:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/05/31/south-america-the-summary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a three day layover in the U.S., Mexico seems like the perfect place to write up my thoughts and the roughly 7.5 months we spent in South America. I&rsquo;m sure there are plenty of omissions, but it should be enough to give you an idea.</p>

<p><strong>Paraguay</strong><br>
A good place for easing into South America. The strong Guarani influence is very interesting and the Jesuit ruins in Trinidad were one of the more memorable sights of this trip, especially since we had them almost completely to ourselves. The people were more reserved than in other countries, but generally friendly and helpful. We met some amazing young people (thanks for everything Chalo, Javier and Cesar!), which give you lots of hope for the future of this country.</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Chipa, sopa paraguaya, mbeju, chipa guazu, terere.</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> Our introduction to Rioplatense dialect, my favorite Spanish dialect so far.</p>

<p><strong>Argentina</strong><br>
Probably the South American country I wanted to visit for the longest time. Buenos Aires was all that I expected and probably more. Iguazu was amazing, Mendoza was chilled out and very relaxing, the Andean part offered some breath-taking views and some of the best food in the country. People were friendly and chatty (and loud), but have a tendency of making everything about Argentina, which can get a bit tiring at times. Also the food wasn&rsquo;t always that great, since vegetarianism roughly equals treason. They may well have the best ice cream outside of Italy though and there were other great sweets too. I&rsquo;d love to live in Buenos Aires, but as one of our friends once said: &ldquo;In this city everything that can be easy is hard, and everything that can be hard is super-hard&hellip;&rdquo; Oh btw, a special thanks to Eze for hosting us for 10 days or so at his place in Buenos Aires and to all the great teachers at El Pasaje Spanish School!</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Quinoa empanadas, quinoa risotto and goat cheese in Jujuy, empanadas in Buenos Aires, provoleta, vegetarian BBQ at Mate Hostel in Cordoba, chocotorta, alfajores, ice cream. Mate. Red wine.</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> ¡Che, boludo! Different pronunciation, different vocabulary and a rather Italian melody.</p>

<p><strong>Uruguay</strong><br>
Ah, Uruguay, hobbit land. Rolling green hills, cows, mate, more cows, more mate. And another hill or two. Plus lovely little villages on the Atlantic coast and some of the most chilled out people I&rsquo;ve ever met. Montevideo may not be a beauty, but it has its charms (like 22km of coast line, colorful colonial houses, a great weekly flea market) and we stayed much longer than most other travelers. I think I may actually want to live there for a year or so at one point. I can&rsquo;t say too much about the food (which is essentially the same as in Argentina) since we mostly self-catered, but for that there were some excellent fruits and vegetables around.</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Pizza and faina at Subte, Montevideo. Empanadas in the Ciudad Vieja, Montevideo. Alfajores. Mate (everyone, everywhere, all the time). Red wine (surprisingly).</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> Basically like in Argentina.</p>

<p><strong>Chile</strong><br>
Stunning. Due to its unique shape, you are never too far from the Andes AND the Pacific. Yes, both, at the same time. It&rsquo;s totally feasible to start a day with a hike in the mountains, take a bus and still fall asleep to the sound of the ocean. The food was good, with more vegetarian options available. Plus the markets feature some of the nicest fruits and vegetables I ever saw. Also you can buy a kilo of avocados for less money than 2 avocados cost in Vienna. The people were lovely too! I was especially fond of Santiago, which has some great neighborhoods (Bella Vista, Barrio Brasil) and a very active cultural life. Another city I would give a try for living!</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Pizza at Fabrica de Pizza, Santiago. Avocado. A surprising amount of food in San Pedro de Atacama. Red wine. Pisco (Pisco Sour and Piscola).</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> Fast, faster, Chilean. ¿Cachai, huevon?</p>

<p><strong>Bolivia</strong><br>Quite likely my least favorite country of the ones I saw in South America. While it features absolutely stunning landscapes (especially around Tupiza and in the Lipez region), I never warmed to the people. I also expected much more of Sucre after meeting so many people who loved it, but at least La Paz was a rather interesting place. Interesting mind you, not pretty or anything. I absolutely loved the area around Lake Titicaca though, even the people were friendlier. After we talked to so many enthusiastic people, I found Bolivia rather disappointing and wouldn&rsquo;t need to go back anytime soon.</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Vegetarian saltenas in La Paz. Lentil and quinoa burgers in LP. Everything from Tierra Sana in LP. Fries with peanut sauce and mayonnaise at Florin, Sucre. Chicha morada.</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> The first country where the Spanish sounded more like what one is used to from Spain.</p>

<p><strong>Peru</strong><br>
Before we got there, we heard mixed reviews of Peru. It seems to be a place you either love or hate, with us definitely being in the former category. There are some absolutely stunning historical sites (yes, that includes Machu Picchu, although I find it&rsquo;s way overpriced), great food, and incredibly friendly people. Cusco was super touristy yet very nice and relaxed, Lima surprisingly pleasant (not least because of Christian, our amazing CouchSurfing host) and we also had a really good time on the coast and in Huacachina, a little desert oasis (thanks Birgit for the tip!). Chiclayo is quite the shithole but has one of the best museums we saw on this trip and if I had to get stuck somewhere for Easter weekend, worse places than pleasant little Piura come to mind. And let&rsquo;s not forget Arequipa and the amazing Monasterio de Santa Catalina, a sight definitely worth seeing.</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Arroz a la cubana, food stalls at the Mercado Central in Cusco, pizza at &ldquo;La Pizza de Carlo&rdquo; in Cusco, rocoto, palta rellena, queso andino, chocolate cake with dulce de leche. Chicha.</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> Lots, because if you kill a Peruvian, you probably have to kill the mouth separately. Also the perfect tense made a reappearance in spoken language.</p>

<p><strong>Ecuador</strong><br>
Ecuador, how much I like you! From the moment we got into Vilcabamba, I was certain we&rsquo;d have a good time there and that we did. We met some great people, saw some amazing places, lived and worked at a Hare Krishna farm, visited a friend of P.&rsquo;s who lives in Guayaquil, went to the Isla de la plata (aka &ldquo;the poor man&rsquo;s Galapagos&rdquo;), kicked back on the beach in Canoa (where I also won some money in a small poker tournament) and generally just felt very relaxed.</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Everything at the Hare Krishna farm, where for an entire week everything was vegetarian and I didn&rsquo;t have to hunt around for food for once. Arepas and patacones in Puerto Lopez (admittedly Colombian, but they were good), arepas in Quito. Chocolate, oh delicious chocolate that we stocked up on (eating some as I write this).</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> Standard, pleasant, easy to understand.</p>

<p><strong>Colombia</strong><br>
Another place many people love and that has a lot of hype surrounding it. Coming in from Ecuador we drove through some rather heavily militarized zones and had our buses and luggage searched by the army twice, which does leave you with a bit of a strange feeling. I never quite got why everybody seems to like Medellin so much. I liked both Cali and Bogota more. And then there&rsquo;s Cartagena: super touristy, expensive, but still rather relaxed and relaxing and VERY pretty. One of my favorite parts was Santa Marta though (kinda like a more &ldquo;real&rdquo; Cartagena), where we stayed in a hotel that used to be owned by a drug cartel and which was rather incredible. It also was full of nice people and featured a cool swimming pool, so we got stuck there for a bit but at least managed to go to lovely Minca close by.</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Pizza at &ldquo;Los Bohemios&rdquo; in Bogota. Arepas, patacones, fruits and vegetables you&rsquo;ve never heard of. Juices made of the same. Coffee (OMG the coffee).</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> Lots of people love Colombian Spanish, and I can understand why. It&rsquo;s rather standard, easy to understand and some Colombians (e.g. in Antioquia) speak with a great melody. ¡Que bacano, marica!</p>

<p><strong>Regrets</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Not going to Patagonia in either Argentina or Chile. There were reasons, some better than others. While I&rsquo;m sure Argentinian Patagonia is awesome too, I&rsquo;m especially sorry about Torres del Paine, but at least it&rsquo;s a good excuse for going back to one of my favorite countries of this trip.</li>
<li>Not having more time for Bogota. It seems to be a super interesting city, full of life and (free) culture.</li>
<li>Skipping Brazil. We wanted to go, but it&rsquo;s really quite expensive, so for a long trip we considered it to be outside our budget. Also it&rsquo;s huge, you can easily spend several months just there.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Links</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>If you are interested in the Spanish language, you&rsquo;ll find this hilarious: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GmeBt40yltw">Que dificil es hablar es Español</a></li>
<li>The map of our trip so far: <a href="http://www.tripline.net/trip/The_Project_2012-2013-0263666200171006A917F0C8673EFF6C">Tripline</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living with the Hare Krishna]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/04/24/living-with-the-hare-krishna/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-24T18:43:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/04/24/living-with-the-hare-krishna</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know there&rsquo;s lots of other things I could tell you about (like Peru), but we spent last week at a Hare Krishna temple/farm in the Ecuadorian jungle at that&rsquo;s gonna be today&rsquo;s story.</p>

<p>First off, if you want to know more about the Hare Krishna, head of to Wikipedia and read about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gaudiya_Vaishnava">Vaishnavism</a>. How did we come up with the idea of staying there? Well, P. read a blog post by a Canadian woman who stayed for a while at the <a href="http://ecoyogavillages.org/en/peru/lima/eco-truly-park">Eco Truly Park</a> close to Lima, Peru. What she wrote sounded interesting, so we considered going there. For various reasons we didn&rsquo;t though, so we decided to go to a place that&rsquo;s part of the same network, namely the <a href="http://ecoyogavillages.org/en/ecuador/banos/ecological-garden-vrindavan">Finca Vrindavan</a> close to Rio Negro in Ecuador.</p>

<p>I have to admit, before we got there I was rather skeptical. I&rsquo;m not exactly a religious person (actually far from it), and I have a strong dislike for pseudo-hippies who spend too much time talking about &ldquo;energy&rdquo;. But I was willing to give it a try, and I&rsquo;m glad I did. The few permanent residents of the place were believers from various countries (Ecuador, Colombia, the Dominican Republic and Chile to be precise) and generally were extremely friendly and welcoming. Also, and that was important to me, they never tried to convert any of us volunteers, but were always up for answering questions about their believes if one cared to ask, which I did a lot. They did impose a few rules on us though, but they were easy to follow, especially for only a week:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>All the food was lacto-vegetarian (basically only sweets) or vegan (most other food), no meat or eggs allowed on the premises.</p></li>
<li><p>No smoking, alcohol, drugs or intoxicants of any type, including caffeine.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>As a vegetarian, this was great, for an entire week I could eat every single meal, without embarking on an epic hunt beforehand and knowing that there wouldn&rsquo;t be any nasty surprises (&ldquo;It&rsquo;s not meat, only chicken&hellip;&rdquo;). Also, everybody in the place, residents and volunteers alike, was so nice, open and welcoming, that we never really felt like we had to watch our belongings or lock our room (most people didn&rsquo;t).</p>

<p>A typical day at the Finca looked like this:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>6:30am: Morning prayers. I don&rsquo;t know of anyone who attended them, but I&rsquo;m sure some of the more devout Hare Krishnas went there, although one guy explicitly said that he prefers sleeping in instead.</p></li>
<li><p>7am: Yoga classes. Since I don&rsquo;t practice Yoga I didn&rsquo;t bother waking up that early, but a lot of the other volunteers really enjoyed the Hatha and Kundalini Yoga classes.</p></li>
<li><p>Around 8:30am: Breakfast. This consisted of cereals with fruit (no milk) and herbal teas.</p></li>
<li><p>Until lunch (around 1-2pm): Work. Depending on the day, we did between 3 and 4.5h of work every day (except Sunday, which is the free day). I ended up cleaning quite a lot, which isn&rsquo;t my favorite task, but needed to be done. I also did a day of construction work, where we built new lanterns for one of the forest walking paths and cooked lunch on another. Besides that I generally did more than was asked of us (like help with preparing breakfast or washing dishes) because there was a strong community feeling that really made me feel like contributing. In the process I also learned to make my own gluten, which was rather cool. P. spent most of her time working in the garden and the greenhouse, while others worked on installing new showers in the second house or similar tasks.</p></li>
<li><p>Afternoons: Free time. Most people spent that time studying or chatting to other volunteers or the Hare Krishna. Some also gave impromptu classes on topics they know something about, so I ended up doing one on Qi Gong and Chinese philosophy. I loved the afternoons at the Finca! I read a lot, but also had some great conversations with the many interesting people there, which was rather inspiring.</p></li>
<li><p>6:30pm: The evening ceremony. While we were never pushed to attend, the ceremony was open to everyone, and I did attend most of the days. As you&rsquo;d imagine the Hare Krishna spend a lot of their prayer time with singing and chanting mantras, but they also set aside time for a discussion on more philosophical matters, which were also interesting for the non-religious folk.</p></li>
<li><p>Dinner (around 8pm): Another communal vegetarian meal, usually followed by a movie in the library/home cinema (yes, it was a rather modern place). Most of the time I didn&rsquo;t bother with the films but chatted to people or read instead, but occasionally it was nice to just drop in a beanbag and watch something.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>And this is basically how we spent the entire week, in a kind of soothing regularity that had a good mix of meaningful work and idle/study time. I&rsquo;m not sure I could live like this forever, but I certainly could do it for a lot longer than 1 week. It definitely wasn&rsquo;t easy going back to a city after our farm life, and I still miss the calm that permeated the entire place.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Filling in the blanks]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/03/23/filling-in-the-blanks/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-23T17:20:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/03/23/filling-in-the-blanks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As should be clear by now, I&rsquo;m not overly good at writing these things regularly, so I won&rsquo;t even pretend to be sorry it&rsquo;s been over a month
since the last one, and I also won&rsquo;t promise that the next one will come any sooner. I also kinda gave up hope on ever properly filling you in on Argentina part 2 and 3 and Chile, so a very short summary will have to do:</p>

<p><em>Argentina</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Buenos Aires &ndash; a collective <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stockholm_syndrome">Stockholm syndrome</a> and one of the most interesting cities I&rsquo;ve ever visited (see, Stockholm syndrome).</li>
<li>Cordoba &ndash; A nice enough city, surrounded by a very pretty province.</li>
<li>Mendoza &ndash; Lovely city, nice surroundings, spent Christmas in a great
little hostel and had an amazing bus ride to Santiage de Chile from
there.</li>
<li>Salta &ndash; One of my favorite places in Argentina, a pretty, relaxed little town with some great architecture and a very nice and quirky <a href="http://www.museopajchasalta.com.ar/">museum</a>.</li>
<li>Huamahuaca &ndash; While I&rsquo;m not as enamored by it as other people, it&rsquo;s a nice place, with an amazing location in the Quebrada de Humahuaca and
some of Argentina&rsquo;s best food. The nearby <a href="http://www.naturephotos.com/index.php#mi=2&amp;pt=1&amp;pi=10000&amp;s=0&amp;p=15&amp;a=0&amp;at=0">Hornacal</a> mountain range is one of the most amazing things I&rsquo;ve seen on this trip.</li>
</ul>


<p><em>Chile</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Santiago &ndash; While many people don&rsquo;t seem to like it, I do. Good food, good nightlife, an active cultural life and very friendly people.</li>
<li>Valparaiso &ndash; While it didn&rsquo;t live up to my expectations (there&rsquo;s too much hype around it), I did get to like it in the end, since it&rsquo;s
really a haven for street arts.</li>
<li>Pichilemu &ndash; We didn&rsquo;t even stay in the city proper, but at the &ldquo;Surf Farm&rdquo; 15 minutes out of town by car, in the middle of nowhere. A great
place, hard to leave.</li>
<li>La Serena/Coquimbo &ndash; Two nice little beaches at the coast, where we stayed with an amazing CouchSurfing host.</li>
<li>San Pedro de Atacama &ndash; Surreal landscapes and the world&rsquo;s driest desert.</li>
</ul>


<p>The rest of Bolivia and all of Peru (where we got end of February) will have to wait for the next time, whenever that will be. For the time being you can look at some pictures. although a suicidal SD-card took most of our Bolivia pictures with it :&ndash;(</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157633055981028/">Bolivia (or more precisely the Isla del Sol)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157633059002656/">Peru</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
