<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-15T19:48:44+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Around Southeast Asia]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/12/10/around-southeast-asia/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-10T18:27:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/12/10/around-southeast-asia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Still trying to catch up on updates, this one will cover the time from
end of August until late October. The countries: Malaysia, Thailand,
Cambodia.</p>

<p>While we were in Vietnam, we realized we really felt like some beach
(that was before we actually got get quite a bit of that in Vietnam
itself). WWe also remembered that we really liked Malaysia and would
definitely go back there, so we bought a flight to KL with the idea of
visiting some places we missed last time and later going to Perhentian
or Tioman island. KL was chaotic as usual, but I still kinda like the
place. It&rsquo;s nothing special, but we have a guesthouse where we always
stay and some restaurants we really like. Sometimes returning to the
familiar feels good when you are on a long trip&hellip; But because we also
felt like something new we headed down to Melakka, which although
rather touristy is a really nice place, with good food, a relaxed
atmosphere and lots of pretty old houses in the Straigths Chinese
style. Definitely recommended! Next stop: Georgetown. Two years ago we
already spent a couple of days on Penang island, but we never really
bothered with visiting its main city. Turns out that was a great
mistake, because I&rsquo;m absolutely in love with this place now! There&rsquo;s
the usual mix of cultures typical for Malaysia, although Georgetown&rsquo;s
population is primarily of Indian and Chinese descent and Malays are
rather underrepresented. This means that the town is an absolute
foodie heaven, even more so than the rest of the country. On top of
that there&rsquo;s a lot of really nice architecture, a vibrant arts
community, nice cafes and a generally pleasant atmosphere, so the week
we spent there passed really really fast. I think at one point in the
future I want to spent several month in Georgetown&hellip;</p>

<p>Next on our list was going to an island. As I mentioned before our
original plans included some Malaysian islands, but if you are already
in Georgetown, Ko Tao is quite close and in fact easier to reach.
Normally that is, because when we tried to make our way there, there
was a train strike in the south of Thailand, as well as a cancelled
ferry due to bad weather and several roadblocks for various reasons.
This turned our trip into a 24 hour odysee which in retrospect could
be funny. Could, but isn&rsquo;t. This really was one of the hardest and
most frustrating journeys of this trip and if I never have to repeat
it, it still would be to soon. Anyway, all&rsquo;s well that ends well, and
once we reached the beach, we basically dropped to the activity levels
of narcoleptic sloths, put our bodies in basic life support mode and
didn&rsquo;t really bother with questions more complex than &ldquo;Where should we
eat?&rdquo; for the next ten days. Well almost, because we did sign up for a
diving course. I don&rsquo;t quite know what happened there, but somehow our
lazyness (at this point we had been on the road for almost one year
already) combined with limited trust in the instructor made us stop
after the first day. Maybe I&rsquo;ll try diving again at a later point, but
I&rsquo;m really not in a hurry when it comes to that.</p>

<p>With our batteries recharged and a couple of days left to spend in
Thailand we headed to good old Bangkok, one of my favorite cities in
Asia. We stayed at one of our friends' places, celebrated P.&rsquo;s
birthday with a fantastic dinner, had delicious cakes, saw some of my
friends for drinks in the evening and generally had a good time. I
always enjoy being in Bangkok, it&rsquo;s familiar but there&rsquo;s still always
something new to discover.</p>

<p>The next 3.5 weeks we spent in Cambodia, a place I wanted to see for a
long time. And it did not disappoint. Sure, Poi Pet is one of the most
annoying border crossings in the world and the first impression of
Siem Reap is less than favorable, but once you take a deep breath and
relax, Cambodia is just wonderful. Or rather, Cambodians are just
wonderful. They are open, friendly and funny, often speak good English
and enjoy a chat. If you want to know more about the country, there
are plenty of opportunities for that! But not only the locals were
great, we also met a plethora of nice foreigners, who are really
trying to help. But of course it&rsquo;s no paradise on Earth, so there&rsquo;s
also plenty of shady characters, annoying tuk-tuk drivers, sexpats,
opportunists, you name it. Cambodia is a poor country, with a host of
problems, and it seems to bring out both the best and worst in people.
Don&rsquo;t let the former blind and the latter deter you and you are bound
to have a great time.</p>

<p>Anyway, as mentioned our first stop was Siem Reap, and the Angkor
complex (which is way bigger than &ldquo;just&rdquo; Angkor Wat) really is as good
as you probably believe it is. We got the three day ticket and also
explored some of the further away temples, but my personal highlight
was returning to Angkor Wat in the early afternoon and having it
almost to ourselves for some miraculous reason. We also had a good
time exploring the town itself (the &ldquo;other&rdquo; side of the river is much
more quiet), met some nice expats, went out to party with T. and B.
who we met at the border, and had some delicious food. Seriously,
Cambodian food is underrated, they have some great stuff! Personally I
prefer Thai curries, but a good Amok is almost as good.</p>

<p>Our second stop was sleepy little Battambang, which actually is the
second biggest city in the country, but really doesn&rsquo;t feel like it.
Most poeple don&rsquo;t bother going there at all or just spend a day or so
there, but somehow we managed to fill five days without getting overly
bored. Of course there&rsquo;s the standard day trip including the bamboo
train, a cool old temple, and an amazing cave where a million bats fly
out at sunset, but that wasn&rsquo;t even that interesting (although we did
have a great tuk-tuk driver who explained a lot about Cambodia to us).
I really just enjoyed the relaxed vibe of the place, which has a great
cafe (Kinyei), an good restaurant if they feel like it (White Rose)
and a decent pub (Madison Corner). People are friendly and life has a
very slow pace, which I found immensely relaxing.</p>

<p>From there we went to Phnom Penh, a decidely less relaxed place, which
nonetheless has its own charms. I don&rsquo;t like the general backpacker
area of town, so I&rsquo;m glad we decided not to stay there, but instead
opted for a guesthouse closer to the BKK1 area before actually moving
to another one there. Unfortunately there was a series of attacks on
tourists right before we got to PP, but we still walked all over the
place to explore it and it felt fine. In fact some areas are really
enjoyable and the friendly Cambodians make it even better. We also
bumped into two extremely nice Vietnamese guys who were excited to
learn that we had just visited their country, and who invited us for
some fruit and a chat. Of course we also visited the killing fields
and the S21 prison, but I think it&rsquo;s impossible to truly grasp the
horrors that took place in Cambodia. It still was a sombering
experience.</p>

<p>Our original plan included exploring the east of the country, but alas
heavy rains and floodings prevented us from doing that. So we went
straight to lovely little Kampot, a place where we whiled away a week
with our new travel buddy, N. from the UK. I&rsquo;m not sure what it is
with me and small towns in Cambodia, but I enjoyed Kampot even more
than Battambang. For such a small town there was a surprising lot of
good food, they have an excellent and tough pub quiz (which we
surprisingly won), and there&rsquo;s some nice trips you can do from there.
We also explored the small town on the other side of the river as well
as nearby Kep, and spent quite a bit of time on our guesthouse&rsquo;s
terrace looking at amazing sunsets or at one of the nice cafes reading
books. Tough life, I know.</p>

<p>Oops, this got a lot longer than I had originally intended, but I
really like all the countries I just wrote about and writing about
them brought back some good memories.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The missing update]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/11/06/the-missing-update/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-06T14:07:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/11/06/the-missing-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After roughly two months of silence, it&rsquo;s time for another long overdue update. It covers our stay in Vietnam, or the period from end of July until end of August.</p>

<p>Having spent some time in Taiwan and Hong Kong, we were curious to explore Vietnam, a country that&rsquo;s supposed to be a bridge between the Chinese world and Southeast Asia. We arrived in Hanoi and I instantly liked what I saw: chaos, street food, old colonial architecture and more street food. Not to forget the bia hoi, delicious (and cheap) beer which is brewed daily. While the traffic is at times insane, Hanoi is a very likable city, featuring some great cafes, excellent food and nice old French houses. Unfortunately a typhoon stopped us from going to Halong Bay, but the Perfume Pagoda made for a nice day trip too.</p>

<p>While many travelers in Vietnam opt for the cheap &ldquo;Open Bus Ticket&rdquo; from Hanoi to Saigon with various possible stops in between, we felt like going for a more authentic travel experience and took the night train instead. Alas the sleeper compartments were booked out, so we spent the entire 12 or so hours sitting among Vietnamese families on their way to the beaches further South. Not the best night of my life, but I really enjoyed our destination, the old imperial city of Hue. It&rsquo;s a lovely town, and while quite touristy, it&rsquo;s easy enough to get away from it all and enjoy normal Vietnamese life. I also celebrated my birthday there, and the lovely folks of the Moonlight Hotel (yes, we spoiled ourselves there) gave me a super cute Doraemon cake. Thanks guys!</p>

<p>Our next stop was Da Nang, a popular destination for Vietnamese tourists, but apparently not that popular with foreigners. We ended up staying in a suburb close to the beautiful China beach, where English wasn&rsquo;t really spoken, but people were very curious about us and really helpful. Like many Asians the Vietnamese prefer white skin, so we basically had the beach to ourselves until almost 5pm every day.</p>

<p>We then took the local bus to Hoi An, which is a great little place, that could be so much nicer still if the pretty old houses weren&rsquo;t all covered in merchandise. It&rsquo;s still a very nice and likable town though, and we ate some of the best food in all of Vietnam there (check out the Little Menu, it&rsquo;s a really nice restaurant). For me the best parts where the surroundings though, which we explored on the free bikes our home-stay provided. Cycling through green rice paddies to the beach is among my best memories of our time in the country.</p>

<p>Having made our way back to Da Nang, we embarked on another looong train journey to Nha Trang, Vietnam&rsquo;s most popular beach destination. We originally had thought about skipping it, but I found a great looking diving school there, and since getting an Open Water license was part of my plans for this trip, we decided to go after all. What can I say, the place is as bad as I imagined, full of obnoxious tourists, construction sites, generic backpacker hangouts and a general air of seediness. Anyway, I got sick, the diving didn&rsquo;t happen, and while I found that quite annoying, I also was rather relieved to get out of there.</p>

<p>After a relatively short and scenic bus ride we arrived in Da Lat, a pretty little town in a rather picturesque mountain setting. We stayed at Dream Guesthouse, which was a great place and featured one of the nicest breakfasts I ever got in a hostel. They even had Marmite! While the sudden drop in temperature that comes with altitude was slightly annoying at first, the town&rsquo;s pretty setting and relaxed atmosphere really make up for it. Definitely a place I would go back to!</p>

<p>Since we wanted some more beach time, our next stop was Mui Ne. Getting there was quite a pain in the ass though, as our minibus was filled to the brim with over 30 people and various packages that were dropped off at various destinations on our way, making this dreadful ride even longer. But all is well that ends well, and we had a great time on the beach. We also bumped into some guys we first met in Hoi An and had a fun night out with them and their Austrian (apparently some of us DO travel after all) travel buddies. I also signed up for a kite surfing course, but unfortunately the wind stopped about 30 minutes in and didn&rsquo;t really make another appearance before we left. Sports just didn&rsquo;t happen for me in Vietnam&hellip; Anyway, Mui Ne was super relaxing, we extended our stay twice and ended up spending almost a week there. I&rsquo;d almost be tempted to feel silly for that, but we met several other people who did the same.</p>

<p>Our last stop in the country was Saigon, a very different beast from Hanoi. While I seem to prefer the food in Northern Vietnam, I definitely have a thing for the people from the South. They just seem a lot more friendly and open and we had a couple of good random conversations during our stay. We also visited the Cuchi tunnels, but instead of doing it with a boring half-day tour, we did it using public transport, which took about twice as long, but was way more fun (take bus #13 from the terminal and #79 from where it drops you off). I really enjoyed Saigon, it felt a lot more relaxed that Hanoi.</p>

<p>Writing this made me realize just how much I enjoyed Vietnam. Before we went I was curious about the type of experience we&rsquo;d have, since many people seem to find it a pretty hard country to travel in. However, I found it no harder to deal with than many other places I&rsquo;ve visited over the years. Sure, some of the sellers are rather pushy, but it doesn&rsquo;t take too much to get rid of them. And in all fairness, they bother other Vietnamese people even more than they bother tourists. You also often hear that nothing in Vietnam comes at a fixed price and that foreigners often end up paying a premium, but once again I found that they do the same to Vietnamese domestic tourists too. Also I don&rsquo;t mind paying a couple of cents more every so often, especially when they mean a lot more to the seller than to me. My advice, forget everything you&rsquo;ve heard about Vietnam before you go there, and approach the country with an open mind and a positive attitude. I&rsquo;m sure you&rsquo;ll have a great time!</p>

<p>Oh, in case you wonder, I wrote this in Bagan, Myanmar, but I&rsquo;m afraid it will take a bit longer before my updates have caught up with my whereabouts&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Great, greater, Greater China!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/09/08/great-greater-greater-china/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-08T00:10:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/09/08/great-greater-greater-china</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By now it&rsquo;s quite standard that my posts lack behind my travels&hellip; This update is no exception, it&rsquo;s about our travels from end of June to end of July.</p>

<p>The topic: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greater_China">Greater China</a>, or more precisely Shanghai, Taiwan and Hong Kong.</p>

<p>But let&rsquo;s start from the beginning. In Cali (Colombia) we figured it&rsquo;s about time to figure out how we&rsquo;d get from the Americas to Asia. It was pretty clear that we&rsquo;d have to go through the US, and since A. and V. were not in San Francisco at the dates we were looking at, we decided to visit C. in Los Angeles. After a bit of searching I found a great flight from LAX to Taipei with a 20h layover in Shanghai. P. had
never considered going to Taiwan before, but to her credit it didn&rsquo;t take much convincing and we booked the flight that same evening. Considering that in a past life (or so it seems) I studied Sinology, I did find this quite exciting, after all I studied Taiwan academically
but had never set foot in the country. I also dreaded using my rusty Mandarin again.</p>

<p>Not looking forward to spending 20h at the airport, I did a little online search and found out that Beijing and Shanghai now have free 72h transit visas on arrival. Jackpot, especially since I studied in Shanghai and was quite stoked to see the city again. So after a couple of awesome and eventful days in LA (thanks again C., especially for taking us to the Bradbury building of Blade Runner fame!) we boarded our flight and arrived in China 14h later. We were quite jetlagged and tired, but we still bothered to go into the city, where we found a
nice little hotel off Nanjing Lu close to the Bund. Before we collapsed we managed to have a nice dinner and a bit of a walk and I remembered why I originally fell in love with this city that I called home for a year. I definitely want to go back for a longer stay at one point&hellip;</p>

<p>The next day we arrived in Taipei where we had booked accommodation via AirBnB and a new love affair started almost immediately (yes, I&rsquo;m a bit of a place whore, deal with it). Over the years I&rsquo;ve heard many great things about the city, but yet it still somehow managed to exceed my expectations. It&rsquo;s cool (teenagers have a pretty Japanese style), it&rsquo;s modern, it&rsquo;s quirky, and the food is awesome. If you need a break, places like Beitou (very cool public library) or Tamsui are an easy MRT ride away, or you just go to a park and watch old people practice Qi Gong or Tai Chi. Coincidentally one of P.&rsquo;s friends was in Taipei at the same time as us and we explored the Confucius temple and some other parts together. After a couple of days my friend Ph. arrived from Vienna and kept us company for the next two weeks.</p>

<p>With him we explored more of Taipei, before heading off to Keelong. Which would be transcribed as Jilong in the official Chinese Hanyu Pinyin system, but the Taiwanese seem to use about 5 different systems at the same time, of which at least 2 appear to have been made up solely for the purpose of confusing foreigners. For the rest of this mail I will just go with the transcriptions most commonly found in travel guides, but I digress&hellip; Anyway, Keelong was fun. Not the prettiest of towns, but some nice things to see and an awesome night food market. We spent the afternoon with a friendly but slightly insane taxi driver, and at night we found a group of breakdancers to watch. What more can you reasonably expect from a day trip?</p>

<p>The next day we went on to Hualien, where once again we stuffed our faces at a night market. Or several, since we first ended up at the wrong one, where 2 young employees at a food stall were so relieved that they managed to deal with 3 foreigners, that they actually high-fived when we walked away with our food. After we finished our meal they got daring and ventured a &ldquo;Good food happy?&rdquo; at us. &ldquo;my friends, "happy happy!&rdquo; indeed. The next day was reserved for the famous Taroko Gorge, but a shitty bus service, bad weather and the unfriendliest bus driver of the country made it a rather disappointing experience. You win some, you lose some&hellip;</p>

<p>Our next stop was Lukang, where we spent a couple of very pleasant days eating (do you see a pattern here?) and exploring old temples. We then headed down to Tainan, where we basically did the same. More food, more temples. Then maybe a snack. How about another temple? My favorite part of Tainan was <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anping_District">Anping</a>, which is definitely worth checking out if you ever make it there.</p>

<p>We now were approaching the end of Ph.&rsquo;s time with us, and I&rsquo;m glad he managed to at least get a glimpse of Kaohsiung, one of my favorite new places. I can&rsquo;t even tell you why exactly, I just really liked it there. Sure, food&rsquo;s awesome, but that&rsquo;s basically a given in Taiwan. The people are amazingly friendly, but that&rsquo;s pretty much standard too. I guess what I like is the overall feel of the place, which is rather relaxed. And artsy. Kaohsiung used to be an industrial town, but most of that industry disappeared. Thanks to a former mayor the
old factories and warehouses on the docks now serve as amazingcontemporary art spaces. We came for 3 days, we stayed for a week, andwho knows, without the flight to Vietnam we had already booked at thattime, I might still be there&hellip;</p>

<p>Our last stop before returning to Taipei for 3 more awesome days wasTaitung, or rather the countryside around it. Taiwan&rsquo;s east coast isfar less developed than other parts of the country, but reallybeautiful. Since our hostel had free bikes we managed to explore thearea a bit, alas a second taifun was about to hit (the first onecaught Ph. in Taipei) and so the weather wasn&rsquo;t exactly great. Atleast we had a great hostel to return to, run by a lovely family,which made us drink way more tea than I thought a human bladder canhold.</p>

<p>If it wasn&rsquo;t obvious enough yet, Taiwan was one of my favoritedestinations on this trip. The people are just amazingly friendly!Sure, not everybody will speak English, but even then they will stilltry to help you. Or at least smile at you. The food is excellent. Yes,I write about food a lot. Food matters! There&rsquo;s plenty of old templesaround, actually more than in most parts of China that I visited. Andalongside the old there&rsquo;s the new. Taiwan has many art and culturespaces, and a vibrant youth culture that borrows liberally from &ldquo;thewest&rdquo; as well as from Japan. In a way, our stay there made merediscover my love for the Chinese world, which had died down a bitafter university. I even got back into speaking Mandarin, and while itwas far from perfect, it usually was good enough (or the Taiwanese arejust amazing at reading body language in combination with nonsensicalphrases.) If you are looking for an intro to the Chinese culturalsphere that&rsquo;s easier than the mainland, I can wholeheartedly recommend Taiwan!</p>

<p>After the weeks of relative tranquillity, Hong Kong (one of myfavorite places ever) was quite the change. It&rsquo;s louder, busier, andmore stressful. On a superficial look it&rsquo;s all modern and businesslike, but if you dig deeper, you&rsquo;ll still find bits and pieces of oldworking-class Hong Kong. And if you want a break, you can always justflee up Hong Kong hill or head out to Lantau to visit the peacefulfishing village of Tai O. We stayed in Chungking Mansions(<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chungking_Mansions">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chungking_Mansions</a>), which despite therecent renovations is still a rather unique place. After all thisplace had a book written about it, the aptly named &ldquo;Ghetto at theCenter of the World&rdquo;. Another nerd dream came true when we visited theonly Studio Ghibli store outside Japan, where we took pictures withTotoro and in the Catbus. Yes, I was inside the Catbus, how cool isthat? Unfortunately the weather was really bad during most of ourstay, so P. didn&rsquo;t get to fully enjoy HK, which is a bit of a shame.Oh well, guess that means I will have to take her back at one point&hellip;</p>

<p>Photos I hear you say? Here you go:<br>
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157635271645014/">Taiwan</a><br>
<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157635262034054/">Hong Kong</a></p>

<p>Confucius say &ldquo;Be good and travel more!&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[¡Viva Mexico!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/07/27/viva-mexico/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-27T20:04:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/07/27/viva-mexico</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Oh man, this is one overdue post. I wanted to write about Mexico forever, but then we were traveling in Taiwan, and suddenly the whole Latin America experience just seemed so far away already&hellip; Anyway, we are now in Vietnam (Hanoi to be more specific), so I thought I&rsquo;d finally sit down and write up my impressions.</p>

<p>Mexico was one of the places I wanted to visit for a long time, so before we went, I was a bit nervous that it may not live up to my expectations. But not only did it do that, it actually far exceeded them! There are fantastic things to see, the food is exceptionally good (also for vegetarians) and the people amazingly friendly. Also it felt like a really safe and easy place to travel: as opposed to big parts of South America the security situation in Mexico is pretty relaxed, even though stuff does of course happen. On top of that there are good roads everywhere and ADO is a very nice bus company, so we generally didn&rsquo;t dread moving from A to B. With that said it&rsquo;s quite unfortunate we only had 4 weeks there, but we had booked the flight to Taiwan beforehand in order to avoid getting stuck in the Americas for all of our trip. Turns out that was a good idea, because Mexico alone could easily have kept me entertained for several more month.</p>

<p>Our trip started in Tulum, which features a beautiful beach and a cute little set of ruins. Unfortunately Chaak (the Mayan rain god) wasn&rsquo;t on our side, so we only managed to get one and a half proper beach days. On the upside we got to taste tons of good food and also explore the nearby ruins of Coba. We then went to lovely Valladolid and the ruins of Ek Balam, both of which are a bit overlooked by tourists (or just crammed in on day tours). I&rsquo;m glad we stayed there, a super relaxed little town, and the ruins were among my favorites in Mexico. Next stop was Merida, which is a decent place in itself, but also the gateway to the ruins of Uxmal. A decent place, but slightly tainted by the memory of annoyingly obnoxious hostel neighbors. If you&rsquo;ve been to Mexico before and wonder, yes, we did in fact skip Chichen Itza. Based on the feedback of people we met, it really did not seem worth the effort in time and money. Instead we decided to give another little and often overlooked town a chance, and I&rsquo;m definitely happy that we went to Campeche. Quiet, with a small but pretty old town and very down to earth, this is the sort of place I really came to enjoy on this journey, and not only for the lack of a specific type of backpacker I detest. After this brief stop we went on to Palenque, a set of ruins I had heard lots about, and which I found to be a bit disappointing. Letting vendors onto the premises really doesn&rsquo;t add to the atmosphere, even if they don&rsquo;t hassle you&hellip; At least the setting of our hostel was very scenic, in that small cluster of hostels right at the beginning of the national park. The next stop was one of my absolute favorites, San Cristobal de las Casas where we ended up staying almost twice as long as we originally planned. True, it&rsquo;s small, but thanks to several cultural centers there&rsquo;s a surprising lot to do in town. It&rsquo;s also Zapatista heartland, so if you have any interest in the EZLN, this is THE place to be. Our trip to the coast around Puerto Escondido got canceled due to a hurricane, so we went straight to Oaxaca instead, which was also quite nice. Unfortunately P. got sick, so I mostly explored it by myself including a Mezcal factory, a petrified waterfall, and of course more ruins. Last but certainly not least was the D.F. (Distrito Federal), more commonly know as Mexico City outside of the country. You have to understand that I wanted to visit this city since my elementary school days, when I first heard that it&rsquo;s the biggest in the world. It may not be anymore, but it&rsquo;s still one of the most interesting places I ever visited. It&rsquo;s hard to put the city into words, but it has everything: the old, the new, the very poor, the super rich. It&rsquo;s a giant, it&rsquo;s a moloch, and yet, it&rsquo;s lovely. While not all of it is pretty, the parts that are, really are. When you walk into Coyoacan or San Angel for the first time, it&rsquo;s hard to believe that they are part of Mexico City at all. And given the size of the place, it&rsquo;s incredibly how friendly and helpful most of the people still are. BTW, thanks again for dinner and a great chat Hector! It&rsquo;s hard to put Mexico City into words, you better go there yourself!</p>

<p>No post about Mexico could be complete without a separate mention of the food. I always considered Mexican cuisine to be one of my favorites, but I wasn&rsquo;t sure how authentic it was. Turns out that the things we know like tacos, burritos, quesadillas, enchilladas, fajitas, and guacamole traveled rather well to Europe, although unfortunately we can&rsquo;t find them at tasty little street stalls where they are almost ridiculously cheap at times. But there&rsquo;s just so much more: sope, gorditas, molletes, tortas, papadzules, brazo de reina, tlayudas, and a ton of delicious things I can&rsquo;t remember the name of. Just writing about it now makes we want to go back right away&hellip;</p>

<p>Mexico definitely was one of the highlights of this trip for me (actually of all my travels so far), I&rsquo;d instantly go back.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[South America: The summary]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/05/31/south-america-the-summary/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-31T17:52:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.citizen428.net/blog/2013/05/31/south-america-the-summary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a three day layover in the U.S., Mexico seems like the perfect place to write up my thoughts and the roughly 7.5 months we spent in South America. I&rsquo;m sure there are plenty of omissions, but it should be enough to give you an idea.</p>

<p><strong>Paraguay</strong><br>
A good place for easing into South America. The strong Guarani influence is very interesting and the Jesuit ruins in Trinidad were one of the more memorable sights of this trip, especially since we had them almost completely to ourselves. The people were more reserved than in other countries, but generally friendly and helpful. We met some amazing young people (thanks for everything Chalo, Javier and Cesar!), which give you lots of hope for the future of this country.</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Chipa, sopa paraguaya, mbeju, chipa guazu, terere.</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> Our introduction to Rioplatense dialect, my favorite Spanish dialect so far.</p>

<p><strong>Argentina</strong><br>
Probably the South American country I wanted to visit for the longest time. Buenos Aires was all that I expected and probably more. Iguazu was amazing, Mendoza was chilled out and very relaxing, the Andean part offered some breath-taking views and some of the best food in the country. People were friendly and chatty (and loud), but have a tendency of making everything about Argentina, which can get a bit tiring at times. Also the food wasn&rsquo;t always that great, since vegetarianism roughly equals treason. They may well have the best ice cream outside of Italy though and there were other great sweets too. I&rsquo;d love to live in Buenos Aires, but as one of our friends once said: &ldquo;In this city everything that can be easy is hard, and everything that can be hard is super-hard&hellip;&rdquo; Oh btw, a special thanks to Eze for hosting us for 10 days or so at his place in Buenos Aires and to all the great teachers at El Pasaje Spanish School!</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Quinoa empanadas, quinoa risotto and goat cheese in Jujuy, empanadas in Buenos Aires, provoleta, vegetarian BBQ at Mate Hostel in Cordoba, chocotorta, alfajores, ice cream. Mate. Red wine.</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> ¡Che, boludo! Different pronunciation, different vocabulary and a rather Italian melody.</p>

<p><strong>Uruguay</strong><br>
Ah, Uruguay, hobbit land. Rolling green hills, cows, mate, more cows, more mate. And another hill or two. Plus lovely little villages on the Atlantic coast and some of the most chilled out people I&rsquo;ve ever met. Montevideo may not be a beauty, but it has its charms (like 22km of coast line, colorful colonial houses, a great weekly flea market) and we stayed much longer than most other travelers. I think I may actually want to live there for a year or so at one point. I can&rsquo;t say too much about the food (which is essentially the same as in Argentina) since we mostly self-catered, but for that there were some excellent fruits and vegetables around.</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Pizza and faina at Subte, Montevideo. Empanadas in the Ciudad Vieja, Montevideo. Alfajores. Mate (everyone, everywhere, all the time). Red wine (surprisingly).</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> Basically like in Argentina.</p>

<p><strong>Chile</strong><br>
Stunning. Due to its unique shape, you are never too far from the Andes AND the Pacific. Yes, both, at the same time. It&rsquo;s totally feasible to start a day with a hike in the mountains, take a bus and still fall asleep to the sound of the ocean. The food was good, with more vegetarian options available. Plus the markets feature some of the nicest fruits and vegetables I ever saw. Also you can buy a kilo of avocados for less money than 2 avocados cost in Vienna. The people were lovely too! I was especially fond of Santiago, which has some great neighborhoods (Bella Vista, Barrio Brasil) and a very active cultural life. Another city I would give a try for living!</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Pizza at Fabrica de Pizza, Santiago. Avocado. A surprising amount of food in San Pedro de Atacama. Red wine. Pisco (Pisco Sour and Piscola).</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> Fast, faster, Chilean. ¿Cachai, huevon?</p>

<p><strong>Bolivia</strong><br>Quite likely my least favorite country of the ones I saw in South America. While it features absolutely stunning landscapes (especially around Tupiza and in the Lipez region), I never warmed to the people. I also expected much more of Sucre after meeting so many people who loved it, but at least La Paz was a rather interesting place. Interesting mind you, not pretty or anything. I absolutely loved the area around Lake Titicaca though, even the people were friendlier. After we talked to so many enthusiastic people, I found Bolivia rather disappointing and wouldn&rsquo;t need to go back anytime soon.</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Vegetarian saltenas in La Paz. Lentil and quinoa burgers in LP. Everything from Tierra Sana in LP. Fries with peanut sauce and mayonnaise at Florin, Sucre. Chicha morada.</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> The first country where the Spanish sounded more like what one is used to from Spain.</p>

<p><strong>Peru</strong><br>
Before we got there, we heard mixed reviews of Peru. It seems to be a place you either love or hate, with us definitely being in the former category. There are some absolutely stunning historical sites (yes, that includes Machu Picchu, although I find it&rsquo;s way overpriced), great food, and incredibly friendly people. Cusco was super touristy yet very nice and relaxed, Lima surprisingly pleasant (not least because of Christian, our amazing CouchSurfing host) and we also had a really good time on the coast and in Huacachina, a little desert oasis (thanks Birgit for the tip!). Chiclayo is quite the shithole but has one of the best museums we saw on this trip and if I had to get stuck somewhere for Easter weekend, worse places than pleasant little Piura come to mind. And let&rsquo;s not forget Arequipa and the amazing Monasterio de Santa Catalina, a sight definitely worth seeing.</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Arroz a la cubana, food stalls at the Mercado Central in Cusco, pizza at &ldquo;La Pizza de Carlo&rdquo; in Cusco, rocoto, palta rellena, queso andino, chocolate cake with dulce de leche. Chicha.</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> Lots, because if you kill a Peruvian, you probably have to kill the mouth separately. Also the perfect tense made a reappearance in spoken language.</p>

<p><strong>Ecuador</strong><br>
Ecuador, how much I like you! From the moment we got into Vilcabamba, I was certain we&rsquo;d have a good time there and that we did. We met some great people, saw some amazing places, lived and worked at a Hare Krishna farm, visited a friend of P.&rsquo;s who lives in Guayaquil, went to the Isla de la plata (aka &ldquo;the poor man&rsquo;s Galapagos&rdquo;), kicked back on the beach in Canoa (where I also won some money in a small poker tournament) and generally just felt very relaxed.</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Everything at the Hare Krishna farm, where for an entire week everything was vegetarian and I didn&rsquo;t have to hunt around for food for once. Arepas and patacones in Puerto Lopez (admittedly Colombian, but they were good), arepas in Quito. Chocolate, oh delicious chocolate that we stocked up on (eating some as I write this).</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> Standard, pleasant, easy to understand.</p>

<p><strong>Colombia</strong><br>
Another place many people love and that has a lot of hype surrounding it. Coming in from Ecuador we drove through some rather heavily militarized zones and had our buses and luggage searched by the army twice, which does leave you with a bit of a strange feeling. I never quite got why everybody seems to like Medellin so much. I liked both Cali and Bogota more. And then there&rsquo;s Cartagena: super touristy, expensive, but still rather relaxed and relaxing and VERY pretty. One of my favorite parts was Santa Marta though (kinda like a more &ldquo;real&rdquo; Cartagena), where we stayed in a hotel that used to be owned by a drug cartel and which was rather incredible. It also was full of nice people and featured a cool swimming pool, so we got stuck there for a bit but at least managed to go to lovely Minca close by.</p>

<p><em>Memorable foods and drinks:</em> Pizza at &ldquo;Los Bohemios&rdquo; in Bogota. Arepas, patacones, fruits and vegetables you&rsquo;ve never heard of. Juices made of the same. Coffee (OMG the coffee).</p>

<p><em>Spanish:</em> Lots of people love Colombian Spanish, and I can understand why. It&rsquo;s rather standard, easy to understand and some Colombians (e.g. in Antioquia) speak with a great melody. ¡Que bacano, marica!</p>

<p><strong>Regrets</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Not going to Patagonia in either Argentina or Chile. There were reasons, some better than others. While I&rsquo;m sure Argentinian Patagonia is awesome too, I&rsquo;m especially sorry about Torres del Paine, but at least it&rsquo;s a good excuse for going back to one of my favorite countries of this trip.</li>
<li>Not having more time for Bogota. It seems to be a super interesting city, full of life and (free) culture.</li>
<li>Skipping Brazil. We wanted to go, but it&rsquo;s really quite expensive, so for a long trip we considered it to be outside our budget. Also it&rsquo;s huge, you can easily spend several months just there.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Links</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>If you are interested in the Spanish language, you&rsquo;ll find this hilarious: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GmeBt40yltw">Que dificil es hablar es Español</a></li>
<li>The map of our trip so far: <a href="http://www.tripline.net/trip/The_Project_2012-2013-0263666200171006A917F0C8673EFF6C">Tripline</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
