<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-25T00:06:16-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Living with the Hare Krishna]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/04/24/living-with-the-hare-krishna/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-24T18:43:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/04/24/living-with-the-hare-krishna</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know there's lots of other things I could tell you about (like Peru), but we spent last week at a Hare Krishna temple/farm in the Ecuadorian jungle at that's gonna be today's story.</p>

<p>First off, if you want to know more about the Hare Krishna, head of to Wikipedia and read about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gaudiya_Vaishnava">Vaishnavism</a>. How did we come up with the idea of staying there? Well, P. read a blog post by a Canadian woman who stayed for a while at the <a href="http://ecoyogavillages.org/en/peru/lima/eco-truly-park">Eco Truly Park</a> close to Lima, Peru. What she wrote sounded interesting, so we considered going there. For various reasons we didn't though, so we decided to go to a place that's part of the same network, namely the <a href="http://ecoyogavillages.org/en/ecuador/banos/ecological-garden-vrindavan">Finca Vrindavan</a> close to Rio Negro in Ecuador.</p>

<p>I have to admit, before we got there I was rather skeptical. I'm not exactly a religious person (actually far from it), and I have a strong dislike for pseudo-hippies who spend too much time talking about "energy". But I was willing to give it a try, and I'm glad I did. The few permanent residents of the place were believers from various countries (Ecuador, Colombia, the Dominican Republic and Chile to be precise) and generally were extremely friendly and welcoming. Also, and that was important to me, they never tried to convert any of us volunteers, but were always up for answering questions about their believes if one cared to ask, which I did a lot. They did impose a few rules on us though, but they were easy to follow, especially for only a week:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>All the food was lacto-vegetarian (basically only sweets) or vegan (most other food), no meat or eggs allowed on the premises.</p></li>
<li><p>No smoking, alcohol, drugs or intoxicants of any type, including caffeine.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>As a vegetarian, this was great, for an entire week I could eat every single meal, without embarking on an epic hunt beforehand and knowing that there wouldn't be any nasty surprises ("It's not meat, only chicken..."). Also, everybody in the place, residents and volunteers alike, was so nice, open and welcoming, that we never really felt like we had to watch our belongings or lock our room (most people didn't).</p>

<p>A typical day at the Finca looked like this:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>6:30am: Morning prayers. I don't know of anyone who attended them, but I'm sure some of the more devout Hare Krishnas went there, although one guy explicitly said that he prefers sleeping in instead.</p></li>
<li><p>7am: Yoga classes. Since I don't practice Yoga I didn't bother waking up that early, but a lot of the other volunteers really enjoyed the Hatha and Kundalini Yoga classes.</p></li>
<li><p>Around 8:30am: Breakfast. This consisted of cereals with fruit (no milk) and herbal teas.</p></li>
<li><p>Until lunch (around 1-2pm): Work. Depending on the day, we did between 3 and 4.5h of work every day (except Sunday, which is the free day). I ended up cleaning quite a lot, which isn't my favorite task, but needed to be done. I also did a day of construction work, where we built new lanterns for one of the forest walking paths and cooked lunch on another. Besides that I generally did more than was asked of us (like help with preparing breakfast or washing dishes) because there was a strong community feeling that really made me feel like contributing. In the process I also learned to make my own gluten, which was rather cool. P. spent most of her time working in the garden and the greenhouse, while others worked on installing new showers in the second house or similar tasks.</p></li>
<li><p>Afternoons: Free time. Most people spent that time studying or chatting to other volunteers or the Hare Krishna. Some also gave impromptu classes on topics they know something about, so I ended up doing one on Qi Gong and Chinese philosophy. I loved the afternoons at the Finca! I read a lot, but also had some great conversations with the many interesting people there, which was rather inspiring.</p></li>
<li><p>6:30pm: The evening ceremony. While we were never pushed to attend, the ceremony was open to everyone, and I did attend most of the days. As you'd imagine the Hare Krishna spend a lot of their prayer time with singing and chanting mantras, but they also set aside time for a discussion on more philosophical matters, which were also interesting for the non-religious folk.</p></li>
<li><p>Dinner (around 8pm): Another communal vegetarian meal, usually followed by a movie in the library/home cinema (yes, it was a rather modern place). Most of the time I didn't bother with the films but chatted to people or read instead, but occasionally it was nice to just drop in a beanbag and watch something.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>And this is basically how we spent the entire week, in a kind of soothing regularity that had a good mix of meaningful work and idle/study time. I'm not sure I could live like this forever, but I certainly could do it for a lot longer than 1 week. It definitely wasn't easy going back to a city after our farm life, and I still miss the calm that permeated the entire place.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Filling in the blanks]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/03/23/filling-in-the-blanks/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-23T17:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/03/23/filling-in-the-blanks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As should be clear by now, I'm not overly good at writing these things regularly, so I won't even pretend to be sorry it's been over a month
since the last one, and I also won't promise that the next one will come any sooner. I also kinda gave up hope on ever properly filling you in on Argentina part 2 and 3 and Chile, so a very short summary will have to do:</p>

<p><em>Argentina</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Buenos Aires - a collective <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stockholm_syndrome">Stockholm syndrome</a> and one of the most interesting cities I've ever visited (see, Stockholm syndrome).</li>
<li>Cordoba - A nice enough city, surrounded by a very pretty province.</li>
<li>Mendoza - Lovely city, nice surroundings, spent Christmas in a great
little hostel and had an amazing bus ride to Santiage de Chile from
there.</li>
<li>Salta - One of my favorite places in Argentina, a pretty, relaxed little town with some great architecture and a very nice and quirky <a href="http://www.museopajchasalta.com.ar/">museum</a>.</li>
<li>Huamahuaca - While I'm not as enamored by it as other people, it's a nice place, with an amazing location in the Quebrada de Humahuaca and
some of Argentina's best food. The nearby <a href="http://www.naturephotos.com/index.php#mi=2&amp;pt=1&amp;pi=10000&amp;s=0&amp;p=15&amp;a=0&amp;at=0">Hornacal</a> mountain range is one of the most amazing things I've seen on this trip.</li>
</ul>


<p><em>Chile</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Santiago - While many people don't seem to like it, I do. Good food, good nightlife, an active cultural life and very friendly people.</li>
<li>Valparaiso - While it didn't live up to my expectations (there's too much hype around it), I did get to like it in the end, since it's
really a haven for street arts.</li>
<li>Pichilemu - We didn't even stay in the city proper, but at the "Surf Farm" 15 minutes out of town by car, in the middle of nowhere. A great
place, hard to leave.</li>
<li>La Serena/Coquimbo - Two nice little beaches at the coast, where we stayed with an amazing CouchSurfing host.</li>
<li>San Pedro de Atacama - Surreal landscapes and the world's driest desert.</li>
</ul>


<p>The rest of Bolivia and all of Peru (where we got end of February) will have to wait for the next time, whenever that will be. For the time being you can look at some pictures. although a suicidal SD-card took most of our Bolivia pictures with it :-(</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157633055981028/">Bolivia (or more precisely the Isla del Sol)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157633059002656/">Peru</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mix it up!]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/02/13/mix-it-up/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-13T18:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/02/13/mix-it-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know I didn't write in way too long (and I still didn't talk about Argentina and Chile), but that just happens when you are traveling. Especially when that takes you to Bolivia, where Internet connection speeds are still stuck in the 1990s.</p>

<p>Anyway, we made it to our 5th South American country now, and after 3.5 month in the Cono Sur, this feels distinctly more "foreign". That's probably related to the fact that 60% of the population are indigenous, so there are a lot less European looking people than in Argentina or Chile. Many of the women still wear traditional dress, and coca is quite omnipresent, be it in the form of tea (mate de coca), sweets or as leaves. All of them are supposed to help with altitude sickness, and considering that we never really went below 2500m since we got here (and up to 5000m maximum) we've consumed our fair share too. And I strongly deny all rumors that I actually enjoy chewing coca, it's purely for medical purposes... ;-)</p>

<p>But let's go back to the beginning: on February 2nd we crossed into Bolivia at the La Quiaca/Villazon border, and after having heard terrible stories of hour long waits, we considered ourselves lucky to have made it across in roughly 45 minutes. Alas we later realized that the border guards on the Bolivian side had only changed the day on their stamps but not the month, so our entry stamp actually said January 2nd and you only get 30 days when entering overland. We managed to get this fixed in an immigration office afterwards, the guys working there were pretty amused about what the "idiotas" (quote) at the border did.</p>

<p>From Villazon we took a shared cab to Tupiza, where we spoiled ourselves with a stay in a rather nice hotel. Bolivia is cheap though, so we spent less money for it than we did for dorm beds in Argentina, Uruguay or Chile. The landscape around Tupiza is absolutely stunning, and exploring it on horseback definitely made me feel like Butch Cassady or the Sundance Kid, who by the way weren't shot too far from there. After a couple of relaxed days we embarked on a 4 day tour of the so-called South West Circuit, which ended at the Salar de Uyuni, the world's biggest salt flat. It's hard to put what we saw into words, when we get to a place with a faster Internet connection again I'll try to upload some pictures. One really remarkable thing about the tour was Silvia the cook though, who managed to prepare awesome meals with very limited time, space and equipment. She also made some of the best vegetarian food I've had in South America so far, which is why I still kinda regret not having kidnapped her. I definitely could do with my own personal cook who knows how to prepare veggie meals... After the tour we made our way via Potosi to beautiful Sucre, where we have been kicking back since last Saturday. And by "kicking back" I actually mean hiding in our guest house like most gringos, since the local carnival tradition involves water bombs, buckets of water, shaving foam and an utter lack of sympathy for people who have barely any clothes to begin with. Luckily this is over now, so we can actually fully enjoy the city before heading to La Paz.</p>

<p>After almost two weeks in Bolivia, my feelings are a bit mixed. Before we came, everyone told us how awesome it is, and from a landscape point of view I can wholeheartedly agree. What I miss though is interacting with the locals, which was a lot easier in the Cono Sur than it is here. First off there are lots of Quechua and Aymara speakers, but also the Spanish speakers are more reserved than they were further South, so we barely ever manage to have interesting conversations with locals. But that's not the only thing that makes you feel like you are suddenly on the "gringo trail": the restaurants mostly serve a rather uninspired mix of western "favorites" and even the banana pancake found its way from Southeast Asia to here. There's also a lot more younger and/or obnoxious backpackers around, which I mostly attribute to the fact that Bolivia is considerably cheaper than the South, while still boasting a well-developed tourist infrastructure.</p>

<p>One thing I really like about this trip is how diverse it is: we stayed in hostels, hotels, B&amp;Bs, rented a room from an old lady, used CouchSurfing and AirBnB and stayed with friends. We crossed borders via plane, private car (thanks Mencho!), bus, boat and by walking. We dipped our feet in both the Atlantic and the Pacific, saw volcanoes, salt flats and the world's driest desert. I did my first longer trip on horseback, and also took my first surfing lesson. We learned a new language (Spanish) and got to use all the other ones we know, including Turkish, my very limited Swedish and even Mandarin (twice in Buenos Aires). All this variation makes traveling for a long time a lot more interesting and helps with not getting tired of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cono Sur reflections]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/01/25/cono-sur-reflections/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-25T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/01/25/cono-sur-reflections</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know I'm far behind on telling you about the places we visited, but
I will eventually catch up, or at least I hope so. For now I wanted to
reflect a bit on the past 3.5 month, which we spent in the Cono Sur
(Southern Cone), which <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Southern_Cone">according to Wikipedia</a> "has traditionally
comprised Argentina, Chile, Paraguay, and Uruguay".</p>

<p>So, where to start? Let's say, I always thought of myself as an Asia
person. Considering I studied Chinese at university, that may not be
surprising, but whenever I went to Asia, I kinda felt at home. Or more
so than in Europe at least. But in the last 10 or so years my interest
in traveling Latin America steadily increased, and now that I'm
finally here, I'm reconsidering the "Asia person" thing. Sure, I love
travelling there, but Latin America (or more specifically the parts we
saw so far), are very fascinating for a different reason, mainly that
some of them feel a lot like alternative versions of Europe. Maybe
that isn't the best description, but what I mean to say is that
there's a shared cultural heritage between Europe and here, which
makes it much easier to actually have meaningful conversations with
people. On top of that there's only one language you need to learn
(unless you are going to Brazil or the Guyanas) to be able to travel
from almost the Antarctic to the Southern border of the US.</p>

<p>But there are also certain cultural differences that I appreciate:
first off, there's a lot of left-wing politics going on, which makes
me quite happy. Sure, the left may not always be in power, but it has
a good grassroots presence (trade unions, student groups, squats). I
also found that people started to consider Latin America as a global
player in its own right, which can compete with the EU and the US in
the medium term (at least some countries). Anyway, this is not
supposed to turn into a political rant... Another thing I like is how
open people are and how much life takes place in the streets. Any
random walk to a park can turn into an adventure, full of random
conversations and tons of entertainments provided by jugglers and
other street performers. I'm sure the better weather plays a role in
this, but also the general attitude of people to live parts of their
private lives in the open makes a huge difference. You also can see a
lot of enterprising people in the streets, from shoe shiners, over
food stalls, used book sellers, artesanias and fruit sellers to guys
peddling vegan brownies or puppet performances for children. I know a
lot of them do this in lack of better options, but for others
(especially the artensanias) it's a way to do what they really like
while being able to travel. As one girl selling handmade jewelry (and
who has been traveling for almost 10 years) just told us a couple of
days ago: "¡No the preocupes, te ocupes!" (freely translated: "Don't
worry, do something!"). I don't know how to say this exactly, but
there's a certain energy here that I miss back home. Sure, people here
complain a lot too (and they have every right to in some cases), but
they still seem to believe in being able to change their own destiny.
Probably this has to do with one of my pet peeves about Austrian
people, who constantly complain without acknowledging enough that they
are among the luckiest people on this planet for a lot of things. The
bottom line is that i'm rather fond of people here, and while there
obviously are big differences between e.g. Paraguayans and Chileans,
the things I mentioned above could be recognized in all the places we
visited so far to some degree.</p>

<p>Of course not everything is perfect: One of the most disturbing things
is the huge inequality found in basically all societies here. While some people
are incredibly rich, others literally live off their garbage.
Argentina for example is sliding back into a big crisis, and there's a
lot of very visible poverty around, more than in some Asian countries
I visited in the past. Also things don't always run as smoothly as
they could, mostly because in quite a lot of cases you can observe a
"good enough" attitude. Sure, you don't always have to strive for
perfection, but sometimes it just seems like someone started out with
a great idea, but stopped implementing it at about 95% for no apparent
reason. Last but not least people here seem to have a difficult time
with silence, so you are quite likely to end up in a beautiful spot in
the middle of nowhere, just to have a guy turn up with some bad <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tecnocumbia">Cumbia</a>
blasting from the crappy speakers of his mobile phone. Seriously
people, what's wrong with using headphones?</p>

<p>Anyway, I'm quite in love with this part of our planet now, the
combination of beautiful nature, interesting cities and wonderfully
open people is rather hard to beat. We are supposed to arrive in
Bolivia in about a week, let's see how/if my perceptions will change
there.</p>

<p>That's it for now, in case you haven't seen them before, here are the
links to the pictures of the Cono Sur part of our trip:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157631893001328/">Paraguay</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157632358056523/">Uruguay</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157632056336739/">Argentina</a>
(pictures of the first and second stay, the third one is still
missing)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157632598354471/">Chile</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2012 travel review]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/01/09/2012-travel-review/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T13:25:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/01/09/2012-travel-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know it's a bit late for a 2012 review post, but we spent the last couple of days in a wonderfully isolated place on the Chilean coast without an Internet connection. Anyway, I thought better late than never, so here are some thoughts on the first 3 month of our trip.</p>

<p><em>Favorite places visited</em></p>

<p>This is tough, because we visited a lot of very nice places. If I had to choose 3 though, I'd pick Buenos Aires for being an amazing and amazingly chaotic city, the coast around Pichilemu in Chile for being a magical nature paradise (besides one of the world's best surf spots) and Colonia del Sacramento in Uruguay. Sure, the last one is rather touristy, but it deals with it really well and in the evenings you can have the place almost to yourself. The honorable mention goes to the Iguazu Falls, which are absolutely amazing, but somehow don't conjure up as fond memories as the other places.</p>

<p><em>Favorite places stayed in</em></p>

<p>The "Hostal de la Viuda" in Punta del Diablo (Uruguay) was a great place to stay. It's a bit outside town, run by a lovely couple and incredibly hard to leave, because of the nice garden, great common area and the three cute dogs. We also quite enjoyed the "Mate Hostel" in Cordoba, because it's a place run by travelers (from Argentina, Colombia and Germany) for travelers. I shared lots of mate and good conversations with the staff, and it's a very social place where it's easy to meet other backpackers. Another amazing place was the "Surfarm", which is located about 15 minutes by car from Pichilemu (Chile). It's basically a couple of huts right next to the beach in a pretty isolated area. It's the sort of place where time just has no significance and you fall asleep to the sound of the Pacific after looking at the beautiful night sky. The honorable mention goes to the "Casa Pueblo" in Mendoza (Argentina), which is also slightly out of town (there might be a pattern here) and is owned by a very nice young Russian-Argentinian couple who made our Christmas very enjoyable. There's also a special mention in this category, the "Casa Amarilla" in Aregua (Paraguay), which is basically an old colonial house which was turned into an art space/hostel by the two brothers who run it. I'm not sure how much I enjoyed staying there because of the David Lynch atmosphere, but it's fun to wander around the premises and look at the random art pieces that can be found all over the place.</p>

<p><em>Favorite foods</em></p>

<p>Paraguay had quite a few nice vegetarian dishes, although they were mostly bread-based, so a bit heavy on the carbs. Nonetheless, chipa definitely was a great food discovery. While Uruguay is a bit bland on the food side, there's a very old pizza place in Montevideo called "Subte", which serves delicious pizza and faina. Argentina on the other hand mostly stayed in my mind for its sweets: there's some of the best ice cream outside of Italy, and alfajores as well as chocotorta were rather dangerous for my blood sugar levels. My favorite country for food so far definitely was Chile though, since there's more variety than in the other places and it's full of awesome fresh avocados, which are probably my favorite fruit in the world.</p>

<p><em>Biggest positive surprise</em></p>

<p>Definitely Chile, because before we came we hadn't heard too many good things about the place. People mostly complained about how expensive it is and that the locals are not the most friendly people on the planet. However, we found none of that to be true, Chileans have been incredibly friendly and hospitable so far, and we actually find it easier to stay within our budget here than in Argentina. It's also an easier place to travel as a vegetarian because of the abundance of great fresh fruits and vegetables, which is a definite plus for me.</p>

<p><em>Biggest disappointment</em></p>

<p>Probably Curacao. While I have quite a few good memories related to our two weeks there, it wasn't the mindless beach holiday we were after, but actually a rather exhausting backpacking experience. I don't regret that we went, it was very interesting, but it didn't really live up to our expectations.</p>

<p><em>Best decision made</em></p>

<p>Doing a Spanish course early on was definitely the best decision we made on this trip so far! The two weeks at "El Pasaje" in Buenos Aires were great, since we had a very small group (us and a girl from the U.S.) we could progress at a really fast pace, especially since we didn't start from zero. In only 10 days we managed to cover a lot of grammar and, more importantly, had lots of conversations where we actually could use it. I even started reading a book in Spanish now, and while I'm a bit slow and still miss some vocabulary, I actually manage better than I would have expected. Anyway, being able to have proper conversations in Spanish makes this trip a lot more enjoyable, since we interacted a lot with hostel staff, artesanias, local travelers or random people in the streets.</p>

<p>That's it for now, maybe I'll do a similar post in another three month or so.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
