<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: review | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/review/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-21T23:50:43-02:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Ruby and MongoDB Web Development]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/07/28/review-ruby-and-mongodb-web-development/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-28T10:15:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/07/28/review-ruby-and-mongodb-web-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Disclaimer:</em> I was one of the technical editors of this book, so I may be biased.</p>

<p>While I haven't received <a href="http://www.packtpub.com/ruby-and-mongodb-web-development-beginners-guide/book">the book</a> in its final form yet, I've read all of it, and I can say that the author does a good job at introducing inexperienced programmers to web development with Ruby and MongoDB.</p>

<p>This is a hands-on book and you'll get most out of it by following all the exercises and doing them on your own. From getting all the necessary components and installing them, to developing apps with Sinatra and Rails, a lot of ground is covered.</p>

<p>While the author does tackle some more advanced topics, they are clearly not the focus of this book (it's subtitled "Beginner's Guide" for a reason) which will leave more experienced developers wanting for more. However, the presented material is well written, chapters build on each other and if you are new to web development with Ruby/RoR and/or MongoDB, this is a good title to get you up to speed in just 300 pages.</p>

<p>If you are a more experienced Ruby developer or are already very familiar with MongoDB, this is probably not the book for you, even though you'll probably still get something out of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: The Tangled Web]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/06/20/review-the-tangled-web/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-20T15:05:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/06/20/review-the-tangled-web</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Disclaimer 1: The good folks of No Starch Press were kind enough to provide me with a review copy of this book, but this did not influence the following text.</em></p>

<p><em>Disclaimer 2: Links to books are Amazon affiliate links.</em></p>

<p>I've been interested in IT security for a long time, but obviously even more so since I started working professionally in this area. Since web applications have become ubiquitous in recent years, they constitute a big part of our penetration testing work. This is a very broad topic, so <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1593273886/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag=citizen4blog-20&linkCode=as2&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=1593273886">The Tangled Web: A Guide to Securing Modern Web Applications</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=citizen4blog-20&l=as2&o=1&a=1593273886" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /> by Michal Zalewski is an ambitious project.</p>

<p>The first thing I noticed was that the book is comparatively thin. At around 300 pages it's only about one third of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1118026470/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag=citizen4blog-20&linkCode=as2&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=1118026470">The Web Application Hacker's Handbook: Finding and Exploiting Security Flaws</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=citizen4blog-20&l=as2&o=1&a=1118026470" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />. Don't let that fool you though, this book is not a lightweight by any means. It's logically structured in three parts, the first of which explores the various components that constitute the web as we know it today (URLs, HTTP, HTML, CSS etc.) and their security implications. This is followed by a look at the security features — and their shortcomings — of current browsers. After this part 3 deals with current developments and the future of browser and web application security. This is rounded off by a list of common security problems including references to the chapters of the book that cover them, as well as an epilogue with a surprisingly philosophical outlook on IT security and trust in human societies.</p>

<p>The writing was clear and to the point, with tons of footnotes and references to provide the interested reader with the chance to further research the presented topics. The author clearly knows what he's talking about and manages to present it in a very approachable way. Due to it's limited size the book still has to be a bit dense though, so I never really felt like reading more than one chapter at a time, otherwise it'd have been to much information to take in at once.</p>

<p>Whether you work in IT security or are a web application developer, this definitely is a book you don't want to miss.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[28C3 day 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/30/28c3-day-4/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-30T13:01:00-02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/30/28c3-day-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4828.en.html">Antiforensik</a><br>How to work against forensics. Nothing revolutionary, but a solid talk.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4587.en.html">bup: Git for backups</a><br>An interesting backup project using git, this is open source and still needs help in case you are looking for something to work on.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4856.en.html">The engineering part of social engineering</a><br>I wasn't entirely convinced by this talk. While there were some interesting points, the speaker was quite full of himself and frankly the talk wasn't so different from other SE talks that I've seen before.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4754.en.html">Smart Hacking For Privacy</a><br>This started off rather bad when  one of the 2 speakers couldn't get over this nervousness, but ended up being a really funny and interesting talk, which was later joined by the CEO of the company whose product got hacked.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[28C3 day 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/29/28c3-day-3/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-29T16:24:00-02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/29/28c3-day-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4767.en.html">Security Log Visualization with a Correlation Engine</a><br>Nothing too special, but still rather interesting, especially since I need this for work at the moment.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4746.en.html">Bitcoin - An Analysis</a><br>This was a great talk about the current state of Bitcoin, highly recommended if you have any interest in the topic.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4663.en.html">Cellular protocol stacks for Internet</a><br>Harald Welte's talks on mobile related stuff are usually great, but I didn't get much out of this one, which felt a bit like acronym bullshit bingo (which is not Harald's fault of course).</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4780.en.html">Print Me If You Dare</a><br>One of my favorite talks of this year's congress, you definitely want to watch this. Update your printer firmware first though ;-)</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4814.en.html">Behind the scenes of a C64 demo</a><br>The C64 is the reason I became a software developer, so obviously I really enjoyed this talk. <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LH6_1dEVWds">The demo</a> is really good too!</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4866.en.html">Fnord-Jahresrückblick</a><br>Fun as always.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[28C3 day 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/29/28c3-day-2/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-29T14:00:00-02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/29/28c3-day-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4770.en.html">Don't scan, just ask</a><br>This sounded a lot more interesting than it actually was, especially since the tool that was introduced is not publicly available (as far as I know that is).</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4680.en.html">Effective Denial of Service attacks against web application platforms</a><br>Great talk, solid presentation, this is the type of talk you want to download the video for.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4763.en.html">The Science of Insecurity</a><br>Another great presentation, another definite recommendation.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4800.en.html">How governments have tried to block Tor</a><br>An inspiring and insightful presentation about government surveillance and Tor.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4676.en.html">Apple vs. Google Client Platforms</a><br>A security comparison of iOS and Android and the repective vendor's app markets.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4756.en.html">Quantified-Self and OpenBCI Neurofeedback Mind-Hacking</a><br>One big WTF and I definitely would have left, but unfortunately one of the 2 speakers had to borrow my ThinkPad power supply so I was stuck in this talk until the bitter end.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4775.en.html">Hacker Jeopardy</a><br>Fun as always, but this year's questions seemed a lot easier than the ones I remember from previous years.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
