<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: pyschology | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/pyschology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-04T19:20:22+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2012-02-19]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/02/19/information-overload-2012-02-19/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/02/19/information-overload-2012-02-19</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>You could run an entire campaign if you’re Barack Obama with ads using nothing but Republicans saying things about finance that you’d never hear two months ago. It’s an amazing thing.</p><footer><strong>Dick Bove quoted by Gabriel Sherman</strong> <cite><a href='http://nymag.com/news/features/wall-street-2012-2/'>The End of Wall Street as They Knew It</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1119282/">Instinctive sleeping and resting postures</a><br>Is it just me, or is there something weird about this article? It's rather interesting either way...</li>
<li><a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/02/meetings-where-work-goes-to-die.html">Meetings: Where Work Goes to Die</a><br>I couldn't agree more. Sometimes meetings are necessary, but please keep them short, to the point and clearly scoped.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2012/01/30/120130fa_fact_lehrer?currentPage=all">Groupthink — The brainstorming myth</a><br>Several studies show that brainstorming doesn't work, but there are other ways to unlock people's creative potential.</li>
<li><a href="http://nymag.com/news/features/wall-street-2012-2/">The End of Wall Street As They Knew It</a><br>A very long article on post-crisis Wall Street.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2012-02-15/google-as-benevolent-dictator-yanks-smartphone-apps-with-kill-switch-tech.html">Google as Benevolent Dictator Yanks Apps</a><br>A good summary of remote kill switches on smart phones and computers.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/kashmirhill/2012/02/16/how-target-figured-out-a-teen-girl-was-pregnant-before-her-father-did/">How Target Figured Out A Teen Girl Was Pregnant Before Her Father Did</a><br>This is how much some companies track their customers. But don't pay cash instead, you could be suspected of <a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/02/14/fbi-says-paying-cash-for-coffe.html">being a terrorist</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-16681630">The man who hears colour</a><br>A British artist with a rare vision disorder wears a device that allows him to hear colors.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.datapointed.net/2009/09/distance-to-nearest-mcdonalds/">Where The Buffalo Roamed</a><br>How far can you get from a McDonald's in the contiguous United States?</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2012/03/how-your-cat-is-making-you-crazy/8873/?single_page=true">How Your Cat Is Making You Crazy</a><br>Are bacteria transmitted by cats messing with our brains? This one is a fascinating read.</li>
<li><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052970204795304577223200657284394.html">How Habits Hold Us</a><br>On the importance of habits for humans.</li>
</ul>


<p><blockquote><p>As he pointed out, the intelligence of humans is inseparable from our reliance on habits, the most mindless of behaviors. That's because they let us reserve brainpower for those things that can't be predicted in advance, those situations without relevant cues.</p><footer><strong>Jonah Lehrer</strong> <cite><a href='http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052970204795304577223200657284394.html'>How Habits Hold Us</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2012-01-22]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/01/22/information-overload-2012-01-22/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/01/22/information-overload-2012-01-22</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>We defeat SOPA today, only to face it again tomorrow. It's like trying to stop a cold by blowing your nose. It's time we go after the virus.</p><footer><strong>Maddox</strong> <cite><a href='http://maddox.xmission.com/'>I Hope SOPA Passes</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://werebuild.eu/wiki/Blue_cabinet">Blue cabinet</a><br>A project that wants "to name, shame and expose those who profit on selling the surveillance equipment that enables the intimidation, harassment and killing of innocent people".</li>
<li><a href="http://acko.net/blog/making-love-to-webkit/">Making Love To WebKit</a><br><a href="http://acko.net">Acko.net</a> always had awesome design, but his newest one is absolutely mindblowing.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.tangledwilderness.org/pdfs/saidthepottothekettle-web.pdf">said the pot to the kettle</a><br>This PDf subtitled "feminist theory for anarchist men" is a good read for everyone who's interested in overcoming antiquated gender stereotypes, be they male or female.</li>
<li><a href="http://maddox.xmission.com/">I hope SOPA passes</a><br>Typical Maddox style.</li>
<li><a href="http://jeffdechambeau.com/friending-fast-and-slow.html">Behavioral economics and facebook conspiracy theories</a><br>While the author talks about a conspiracy theory, I think it's fair to assume that the big web companies do use behavioral psychology when trying to get us to click on ads.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2012/jan/20/iran-war-brewing-simon-tisdall">An Iran war is brewing from mutual ignorance and chronic miscalculation</a><br>I still have the naive hope that war is evitable.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.spiegel.de/netzwelt/netzpolitik/0,1518,773495,00.html">US-Copyright-Cops greifen weltweit zu</a><br>If you have German speaking friends who you want to educate about SOPA/PIPA, point them to this article by "Der Spiegel".</li>
<li><a href="http://prezi.com/2lanmqb0nnkj/paredit-emacs-minor-mode/">Paredit - emacs minor mode</a><br>A neat presentation on Paredit, a great Emacs minor mode for Lisp hackers.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/in-which-i-fix-my-girlfriends-grandparents-wifi-and-am-hailed-as-a-conquering-hero">In Which I Fix My Girlfriend’s Grandparents’ WIFI And Am Hailed As A Conquering Hero.</a><br>We've all been there, but this is brilliantly told.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.good.is/post/people-are-awesome-the-south-carolina-coffee-shop-where-everyone-pays-for-everyone-else-s-drinks">People Are Awesome: The Coffee Shop Where Everyone Pays for Everyone Else's Drinks</a><br>It's not often enough that I get to post something nice here.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-11-06]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/11/06/information-overload-2011-11-06/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-06T20:36:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/11/06/information-overload-2011-11-06</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://motherjones.com/kevin-drum/2011/10/climate-skepticism-takes-another-hit">Climate Skeptics Take Another Hit</a><br>A scientist who was skeptical about climate change set out to prove others wrong and found out that they actually were right.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.geekwire.com/2011/gates-tells-uw-students-billionaire-overrated">Gates to students: Don’t try to be a billionaire, it’s overrated</a><br>Shorthand notes from a Q&amp;A session with Bill Gates at the University of Washington.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.infoq.com/presentations/Simple-Made-Easy">Simple Made Easy</a><br>Another excellent presentation by Clojure's Rich Hickey. This is not really Clojure specific, but something most programmers should watch!</li>
<li><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052970203476804576613284007315072.html">Secret Orders Target Email</a><br>Since it's harder to get search warrants for property or postal mail, US law enforcements seems to target electronic communications more and more. Maybe the Electronics Communication Privacy Act is due for an update, it's been a while since 1986...</li>
<li><a href="http://www.slaveryfootprint.org/">Slavery Footprint</a><br>Find out how many slaves work for you. Great campaign for raising awareness about human trafficking and slave labor worldwide.</li>
<li><a href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/notrocketscience/2011/10/31/man-with-schizophrenia-has-out-of-body-experience-in-lab-gains-knowledge-controls-his-psychosis/">Man with schizophrenia has out-of-body experience in lab, gains knowledge, controls his psychosis</a><br>The title is maybe a bit dramatic, but the article itself is still interesting.</li>
<li><a href="http://sourcefabric.org/en/community/blog/788">TagesWoche portrays new future for Swiss media </a><br>A great new publication from Switzerland: online journalism with user participation, version history, micro payments etc., as well as an accompanying weekly magazine.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.businessweek.com/magazine/apples-supplychain-secret-hoard-lasers-11032011.html">Apple's Supply-Chain Secret? Hoard Lasers</a><br>Interesting piece on Apple's supply chain management. Like so many things related to Apple, this triggered a mix of awe and unease in me.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.businessweek.com/magazine/todd-rider-has-a-kill-switch-for-viruses-11032011.html">Todd Rider Has a Kill Switch for Viruses</a><br>A scarily clever man — look at his academic credentials in the article — may have revolutionized who we treat virus-caused illnesses.</li>
<li><a href="http://idlewords.com/2011/08/why_arabic_is_terrific.htm">Why Arabic is Terrific</a><br>The language nerd in me loved this article.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
