<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hardware | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/hardware/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-18T00:39:54+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Power users?]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/04/27/power-users/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-27T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/04/27/power-users</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm really interested to get some opinions on this particular topic: is there a conncection between how people perceive their own knowledge of computers and what kind of hardware they buy?</p>

<p>I'm wondering because I've just been reading a discussion about the new Intel based notebooks, especially the new Mac Books which will be released in June. With 13,3" it will be the smallest of Apple's new offerings, and a lot of people have cried loud for a MacBook Pro - ok, the name really sounds stupid - with the same form factor. But will they really feel a difference? Or do they just want them because the "Pro" makes them feel better (no insult intended)? My own hardware almost always has been pretty old, and I have never much felt the need to own something better just because I'm a "power user" (periods of "decadence kills depression" excluded of course ;) ). And what's a power user anyway?</p>

<p>When my last notebook broke, I ressurected my old desktop machine (an Athlon 650 with 320MB RAM). Although not blazingly fast, I was able to do everything I wanted. My computing needs may be really simple, but given that I was able to read my mails, surf the web and working/coding in several terminal windows while listening to my MP3s or web radio, why should I bother buying new hardware? The same goes for the Mac Mini which will hopefully get delivered next week: why pay a lot more money for a Core Duo, when the Core Solo is already way better than the machine I had before that and which did everything I wanted? With all the money I have already saved by not buying computers I won't really use to their full potential anyway, I can easily buy complete new systems when I don't want to upgrade the current ones anymore...</p>

<p>How about you guys out there? Do you buy fancy new hardware because it makes you feel "1337"? Or are you still using your 486 because as a real hacker you know how to squeeze out every percent of performance possible?</p>

<p>Boomtime, Discord 44, 3172 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
