<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: private | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/private/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-02T22:41:03-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feliz Navidad!]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/12/24/feliz-navidad/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-24T10:01:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/12/24/feliz-navidad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I even have a present for you, the long overdue post about Uruguay,
one of the highlights of our trip so far!</p>

<p>Our first destination was Montevideo, a city I basically liked from
the very beginning. Which is strange, because it's not necessarily the
prettiest of places. Let me rephrase that: it's a city for the second
look. There's a lot of ugly architecture around, but also tons of nice
old colonial buildings. Add to that tree-lined streets (occasionally
even with cobblestones) and roughly 22km of coast and you have a
pretty neat mix. On top of that Uruguayans are lovely people, very
relaxed, friendly, talkative and with the highest mate consumption in
the world. What's not to like? We also had some great CouchSurfing
hosts, so we met lots of people and had quite an active social life.</p>

<p>After a week though we decided to leave the city behind for a bit, and
headed to the Atlantic coast, more specifically Punta del Diablo, a
charming little town of about 700 inhabitants. At least during low
season, because once high season hits the places grows to over 20000
people. While some may like that, I'm definitely not one of them and
having kilometers of beautiful beaches to ourselves was a great
experience. It's hard to describe the beauty of this place in words
(and I haven't uploaded our pictures yet), but it was very hard to
leave Punta del Diablo. If you ever get a chance to go there, do it,
especially during mid to late November, when the weather is already
good but the place is not overrun by tourists yet.</p>

<p>From the coast we headed back for another weekend in Montevideo,
before setting off to picturesque Colonia de Sacramento, another place
that was hard to leave. True, it can get quite full of tourists, but
somehow the town absorbs them well. Also a lot of them just come on
day trips from Buenos Aires, which means they leave again in the late
afternoon and the old town full of cobblestones, cute little colonial
houses and the friendliest street dogs in the world is all yours
again.</p>

<p>Uruguay, a love affair. And I can't even tell you exactly why. Is it
because the whole country looks like Hobbit Land? Or because the
people are amazingly friendly and welcoming? Or because of the very
relaxed rhythm of life? Probably all of the above, and a bit more
that's hard to put into words. I know this mail is somewhat shorter
than the others and lacks detailed descriptions, but somehow I find it
hard to write about Uruguay. It's not a flashy country full of things
to do and places to visit, but it's beautiful nonetheless and I had a
wonderful time there. Whenever someone mentions it, something in me
just wants to go back there right away...</p>

<p>Anyway, I hope all of you are doing well, I'll try to be faster with
the post about the month we just spent in Argentina!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[28C3 day 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/30/28c3-day-4/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-30T13:01:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/30/28c3-day-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4828.en.html">Antiforensik</a><br>How to work against forensics. Nothing revolutionary, but a solid talk.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4587.en.html">bup: Git for backups</a><br>An interesting backup project using git, this is open source and still needs help in case you are looking for something to work on.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4856.en.html">The engineering part of social engineering</a><br>I wasn't entirely convinced by this talk. While there were some interesting points, the speaker was quite full of himself and frankly the talk wasn't so different from other SE talks that I've seen before.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4754.en.html">Smart Hacking For Privacy</a><br>This started off rather bad when  one of the 2 speakers couldn't get over this nervousness, but ended up being a really funny and interesting talk, which was later joined by the CEO of the company whose product got hacked.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[28C3 day 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/29/28c3-day-3/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-29T16:24:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/29/28c3-day-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4767.en.html">Security Log Visualization with a Correlation Engine</a><br>Nothing too special, but still rather interesting, especially since I need this for work at the moment.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4746.en.html">Bitcoin - An Analysis</a><br>This was a great talk about the current state of Bitcoin, highly recommended if you have any interest in the topic.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4663.en.html">Cellular protocol stacks for Internet</a><br>Harald Welte's talks on mobile related stuff are usually great, but I didn't get much out of this one, which felt a bit like acronym bullshit bingo (which is not Harald's fault of course).</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4780.en.html">Print Me If You Dare</a><br>One of my favorite talks of this year's congress, you definitely want to watch this. Update your printer firmware first though ;-)</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4814.en.html">Behind the scenes of a C64 demo</a><br>The C64 is the reason I became a software developer, so obviously I really enjoyed this talk. <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LH6_1dEVWds">The demo</a> is really good too!</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4866.en.html">Fnord-Jahresrückblick</a><br>Fun as always.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[28C3 day 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/29/28c3-day-2/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-29T14:00:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/29/28c3-day-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4770.en.html">Don't scan, just ask</a><br>This sounded a lot more interesting than it actually was, especially since the tool that was introduced is not publicly available (as far as I know that is).</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4680.en.html">Effective Denial of Service attacks against web application platforms</a><br>Great talk, solid presentation, this is the type of talk you want to download the video for.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4763.en.html">The Science of Insecurity</a><br>Another great presentation, another definite recommendation.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4800.en.html">How governments have tried to block Tor</a><br>An inspiring and insightful presentation about government surveillance and Tor.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4676.en.html">Apple vs. Google Client Platforms</a><br>A security comparison of iOS and Android and the repective vendor's app markets.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4756.en.html">Quantified-Self and OpenBCI Neurofeedback Mind-Hacking</a><br>One big WTF and I definitely would have left, but unfortunately one of the 2 speakers had to borrow my ThinkPad power supply so I was stuck in this talk until the bitter end.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4775.en.html">Hacker Jeopardy</a><br>Fun as always, but this year's questions seemed a lot easier than the ones I remember from previous years.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[28C3 day 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/27/28c3-day-1/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-27T16:19:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/27/28c3-day-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a quick summary of the talks I saw on day 1 (powered by <a href="http://www.flora-power.de/">Flora Power</a>, since I already started this year's congress with a lack of sleep).</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4897.en.html">Marriage From Hell</a><br> Authoritarian governments using surveillance technologies provided by Western companies is not exactly news. Not a bad talk, although it was a bit from the "No shit, Sherlock" department. Not worthy of a keynote in my opinion.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4711.en.html">The Atari 2006 Video Computer System</a><br>Since I love hearing about old hardware and its limitations, this was an awesome talk. The speaker definitely knew what he was talking about and the presentation was very solid.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4799.en.html">Can trains be hacked?</a><br>Another good talk, but understandably there was no information on actually hacking the train system. If you want more info on this topic, listen to <a href="http://cre.fm/cre171">Chaos Radio Express #171</a> from December last year.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4661.en.html">SCADA and PLC Vulnerabilities in Correctional Facilities</a><br>Since I wanted to charge my notebook, I watched this one as a stream. This of course led to web surfing and IRC, so I didn't pay as much attention as this talk would have deserved.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4913.en.html">Almighty DNA?</a><br>Why collecting DNA is also a form of data retention. If you've been to similar talks before you probable knew most of the stories they told, if not the video and <a href="http://cre.fm/cre143">Chaos Radio Express #143</a> should be good resources to catch up.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4713.en.html">What is in a name?</a><br>The history of names and identity regimes from 1500 until today. Pretty interesting, but unfortunately I was in a bit of a post-dinner food coma.</li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4736.en.html">Defending mobile phones</a><br>This talk was really full and unfortunately the stream didn't work either, so I ended up watching the second half of  <a href="Macro%20dragnets:%20Why%20trawl%20the%20river%20when%20you%20can%20do%20the%20whole%20ocean">Macro dragnets: Why trawl the river when you can do the whole ocean</a> which had some interesting info on avoiding face recognition and other things.<br></li>
<li><a href="http://events.ccc.de/congress/2011/Fahrplan/events/4817.en.html">String Oriented Programming</a><br>A talk about evading ASLR, DEP and other security measures with <code>printf</code> exploits.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
