<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: books | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-03T11:00:07-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2012 reading list]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/01/02/2012-reading-list/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-02T20:44:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2013/01/02/2012-reading-list</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Once again here's a list of all the books I read in the past year, in
reading order. I'm surprised I made it to 52 again, since there were
several periods where I didn't read much for various reasons.</p>

<p>I also got to work on two books, first as technical reviewer for <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1849515026/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=1849515026">Ruby and MongoDB Web Development Beginner's Guide</a>
and then as the author of the Metasploit chapter for
<a href="http://www.sicherheitsforschung-magdeburg.de/buecher.html">Informationstechnologie und Sicherheitspolitik</a>.</p>

<p>Mukoma wa Ngugi: <em>Nairobi Heat</em><br>
Antoinette Bergin: <em>Bedtime Stories for Children You Hate</em><br>
Margaret Killjoy: <em>Mythmakers and Lawbreakers: Anarchist Writers on Fiction</em><br>
Roberto Ierusalimschy: <em>Programming in Lua</em><br>
Tobias Klein: <em>A Bug Hunter's Diary: A Guided Tour Through the Wilds of Software Security</em><br>
Salman Rushdie: <em>The Satanic Verses</em><br>
Banana Yoshimoto: <em>Kitchen</em><br>
Jens Bjørneboe: <em>Haie: die Geschichte eines Schiffsunterganges</em><br>
Henry David Thoreau: <em>Civil Disobedience</em><br>
Terry Pratchett: <em>Reaper Man</em><br>
Dean Wampler: <em>Programming Scala</em><br>
Brendan Behan: <em>After the Wake</em><br>
Bruce Sterling: <em>Black Swan</em><br>
Lewis Shiner: <em>Slam</em><br>
Peter Godwin: <em>When a Crocodile Eats the Sun: A Memoir of Africa</em><br>
Ron Currie Jr.: <em>God Is Dead</em><br>
Kurt Vonnegut: <em>Cat's Cradle</em><br>
Aravind Adiga: <em>Between The Assassinations</em><br>
Jonathan Safran Foer: <em>Eating Animals</em><br>
Chuck Palahniuk: <em>Nonfiction</em><br>
Gautam Rege: <em>Ruby and MongoDB Web Development</em><br>
Terry Pratchett: <em>The Fifth Elephant</em><br>
Herbert Rosendorfer: <em>Großes Solo für Anton</em><br>
Brian P. Hogan: <em>tmux: Productive Mouse-Free Development</em><br>
Charles Bukowski: <em>Ham on Rye</em><br>
Thomas Marcinko: <em>Astronauts and Heretics</em><br>
Avdi Grimm: <em>Exceptional Ruby: Master the Art of Handling Failure in Ruby</em><br>
Michal Zalewski: <em>The Tangled Web: A Guide to Securing Modern Web Applications</em><br>
Haruki Murakami: <em>1Q84</em><br>
Jesse Storimer: <em>Working with UNIX Processes</em><br>
Qiu Xiaolong: <em>When Red Is Black</em><br>
Lao Tzu: <em>Tao Te King</em><br>
Kim Wright: <em>City of Darkness</em><br>
Joyce Carol Oates: <em>Rape. A Love Story</em><br>
Joseph Heller: <em>Catch-22</em><br>
Hugh Howey: <em>I, Zombie</em><br>
Nury Vittachi: <em>Mr. Wong Goes West</em><br>
Douglas Adams: <em>Dirk Gently's Holistic Detective Agency</em><br>
p.m.: <em>bolo’ bolo</em><br>
Kenneth S. Cohen: <em>Qigong. Grundlagen, Methoden, Anwendung</em><br>
David Wong: <em>John Dies at the End</em><br>
Terry Pratchett: <em>Lords and Ladies</em><br>
Julia Alvarez: <em>How The Garcia Girls Lost Their Accents</em><br>
T. E. Klemm: <em>100 Chess Problems for the Rest of Us</em><br>
Robert A. Heinlein: <em>6xH</em><br>
Gao Xingjian: <em>Soul Mountain</em><br>
Junot Díaz: <em>The Brief Wondrous Life of Oscar Wao</em><br>
Matt Ruff: <em>Bad Monkeys</em><br>
Richard Wilhelm: <em>The Secret of the Golden Flower: A Chinese Book of Life</em><br>
Uzodinma Iweala: <em>Beasts of No Nation</em><br>
James Bracken: <em>¡Che Boludo!: A gringo's guide to understanding the Argentines</em><br>
Terry Pratchett: <em>The Light Fantastic</em><br></p>

<p>There also were several programming books I didn't finish, either because I didn't have time, didn't find them interesting enough or because I got all the information I needed before the book was over:</p>

<p>Martin Logan: <em>Erlang and OTP in Action</em><br>
Leo Brodie: <em>Starting FORTH</em><br>
Timothy Perrett: <em>Lift in Action</em><br>
Kees Doets: <em>The Haskell Road to Logic, Maths and Programming</em><br>
Ivo Balbaert: <em>The Way to Go</em><br></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Ruby and MongoDB Web Development]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/07/28/review-ruby-and-mongodb-web-development/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-28T10:15:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/07/28/review-ruby-and-mongodb-web-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Disclaimer:</em> I was one of the technical editors of this book, so I may be biased.</p>

<p>While I haven't received <a href="http://www.packtpub.com/ruby-and-mongodb-web-development-beginners-guide/book">the book</a> in its final form yet, I've read all of it, and I can say that the author does a good job at introducing inexperienced programmers to web development with Ruby and MongoDB.</p>

<p>This is a hands-on book and you'll get most out of it by following all the exercises and doing them on your own. From getting all the necessary components and installing them, to developing apps with Sinatra and Rails, a lot of ground is covered.</p>

<p>While the author does tackle some more advanced topics, they are clearly not the focus of this book (it's subtitled "Beginner's Guide" for a reason) which will leave more experienced developers wanting for more. However, the presented material is well written, chapters build on each other and if you are new to web development with Ruby/RoR and/or MongoDB, this is a good title to get you up to speed in just 300 pages.</p>

<p>If you are a more experienced Ruby developer or are already very familiar with MongoDB, this is probably not the book for you, even though you'll probably still get something out of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: The Tangled Web]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/06/20/review-the-tangled-web/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-20T15:05:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/06/20/review-the-tangled-web</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Disclaimer 1: The good folks of No Starch Press were kind enough to provide me with a review copy of this book, but this did not influence the following text.</em></p>

<p><em>Disclaimer 2: Links to books are Amazon affiliate links.</em></p>

<p>I've been interested in IT security for a long time, but obviously even more so since I started working professionally in this area. Since web applications have become ubiquitous in recent years, they constitute a big part of our penetration testing work. This is a very broad topic, so <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1593273886/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag=citizen4blog-20&linkCode=as2&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=1593273886">The Tangled Web: A Guide to Securing Modern Web Applications</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=citizen4blog-20&l=as2&o=1&a=1593273886" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /> by Michal Zalewski is an ambitious project.</p>

<p>The first thing I noticed was that the book is comparatively thin. At around 300 pages it's only about one third of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1118026470/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag=citizen4blog-20&linkCode=as2&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=1118026470">The Web Application Hacker's Handbook: Finding and Exploiting Security Flaws</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=citizen4blog-20&l=as2&o=1&a=1118026470" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />. Don't let that fool you though, this book is not a lightweight by any means. It's logically structured in three parts, the first of which explores the various components that constitute the web as we know it today (URLs, HTTP, HTML, CSS etc.) and their security implications. This is followed by a look at the security features — and their shortcomings — of current browsers. After this part 3 deals with current developments and the future of browser and web application security. This is rounded off by a list of common security problems including references to the chapters of the book that cover them, as well as an epilogue with a surprisingly philosophical outlook on IT security and trust in human societies.</p>

<p>The writing was clear and to the point, with tons of footnotes and references to provide the interested reader with the chance to further research the presented topics. The author clearly knows what he's talking about and manages to present it in a very approachable way. Due to it's limited size the book still has to be a bit dense though, so I never really felt like reading more than one chapter at a time, otherwise it'd have been to much information to take in at once.</p>

<p>Whether you work in IT security or are a web application developer, this definitely is a book you don't want to miss.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2012-02-26]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/02/26/information-overload-2012-02-26/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-26T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/02/26/information-overload-2012-02-26</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>To us, the Web is a sort of shared external memory. We do not have to remember unnecessary details: dates, sums, formulas, clauses, street names, detailed definitions. It is enough for us to have an abstract, the essence that is needed to process the information and relate it to others.</p><footer><strong>Piotr Czerski (translated by Marta Szreder)</strong> <cite><a href='http://pastebin.com/0xXV8k7k'>We, the Web Kids</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://pastebin.com/0xXV8k7k">We, the Web Kids</a><br>While I'm probably a bit too old to qualify as a "web kid", I agree with most of this post.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2009/03/09/090309fa_fact_max?currentPage=all">The Unfinished</a><br>This very long article on David Foster Wallace is not only interesting, but also serves as a reminder to myself to finally read <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0316066524/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=citizen4blog-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0316066524">Infinite Jest</a> (affiliate link).</li>
<li><a href="http://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2012/02/life-with-and-without-animated.html">Life With and Without Animated Ducks: The Future Is Gender Distributed</a><br>Sexism shows in many ways, I hadn't really considered this angle before.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.mercurynews.com/ci_16291970">Craig Silverstein, Google's first employee</a><br>An interview with Google's first employee. This is a bit older, but still interesting.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.wired.com/wiredscience/2011/10/why-do-some-people-learn-faster-2/">Why Do Some People Learn Faster?</a><br>Articles about the brain and/or learning make a regular appearance in this blog series, here we go for another one.</li>
<li><a href="http://grist.org/living/dont-hate-the-player-how-fun-and-games-can-encourage-sustainable-choices/">Don’t hate the player: How fun and games can encourage sustainable choices</a><br>I like the example encouragements shown in this article.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.zeit.de/wissen/gesundheit/2012-02/geboren-2012-ernaehrung">Essen 2032: Da sagt der Kühlschrank etwas anderes </a><br>One thing I like about articles trying to predict the future is imagining how naive they will look later (in German).</li>
<li><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/02/13/bittorrent-live/">BitTorrent Live: Cheap, Real-Time P2P Video Streaming That Will Kill TV</a><br>In case you missed this last week.</li>
<li><a href="http://exclaim.ca/Features/Timeline/leonard_cohen-beautiful_loser">Leonard Cohen — Beautiful Loser</a><br>A timeline of Leonard Cohen's life.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.good.is/post/regulators-mount-up-what-happens-to-the-coke-in-coca-cola/">What Happens to the Coke in Coca-Cola?</a><br>Coca-Cola is still made with coca leaves, but happens to the cocaine in them? Read this article to find out.</li>
</ul>


<p><blockquote><p>The future is not evenly distributed. Not along cultural lines, along language lines, along political, economic, class, or generational lines. And most certainly not along gender lines.</p><footer><strong>Cat Valente</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2012/02/life-with-and-without-animated.html'>Life With and Without Animated Ducks: The Future Is Gender Distributed</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: A Bug Hunter's Diary]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/02/01/review-a-bug-hunters-diary/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-01T22:03:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/02/01/review-a-bug-hunters-diary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very good read! In each chapter the author introduces one bug he found in a popular software package, always following the same structure: discovery, exploitation, remediation, lessons learned from the bug and a timeline of the bug's lifetime (disclosure, fix, etc).</p>

<p>The writing is engaging and to the point, but still contains a lot of technical detail. Be warned though, if reading C and disassembly is not your type of thing, you probably won't enjoy this too much. The author tries hard to make everything as easy to understand as possible, but there's only so much you can do with limited space.</p>

<p>If there's anything to criticize about this book, it's that the chapters are fairly repetitive, so I never really felt like reading more than one in a single sitting. But then it's also not the type of book that needs to be read cover to cover as fast as possible.</p>

<p>Link: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1593273851/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&tag=citizen4blog-20&linkCode=as2&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=1593273851">Tobias Klein: A Bug Hunter's Diary</a> (Amazon affiliate link)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
