<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: freedom | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/freedom/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-20T16:10:52+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Tor, no more customer]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/04/18/no-tor/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-18T00:10:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/04/18/no-tor</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Update:</em> Server4You rebooted the server into a recovery system for me. I removed the Tor packages and the system is back up again, which means at least the <a href="http://tor.blingblingsquad.net/">mirror</a> is back. I'd also like to state explicitly that this whole post is based on a single phone conversation with a Server4You support employee, so it's hard to tell if the company per se really considers Tor to be illegal in Germany. Personally I think it's just a bad excuse for shutting down the service on shared hosts, which is just as bad in my book.</p>

<p>I've been running a <a href="https://www.torproject.org/">Tor</a> relay since sometime in early 2006. There's many good reasons for doing so, but what motivated me personally was my experience of studying in China for one year and having to live with a censored Internet connection myself (theoretically, as there was an <a href="http://embraceubuntu.com/2006/12/08/ssh-tunnel-socks-proxy-forwarding-secure-browsing/">easy way around it</a> if you had a server outside of China to SSH to). Alas our system hasn't been an exit node in a while, but it's still better than nothing.</p>

<p>Today I was contacted by my <a href="http://server4you.de">hosting provider</a>'s abuse team, telling me that my server has been shut down because of a ToS violation. I <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/citizen428/status/192189329177718784">immediately was afraid</a> that they might complain about the Tor relay, but still had hope that I might be wrong. Ten hours later, after I got no reply to about five support requests, I decided to call their hotline. The employee first told me that he has no way to see why the abuse team blocked my server, but then said that running a Tor node may have been the reason. What ensued was a five minute conversation full of WTFs, facepalms and headdesks on my part, but the bottom line is that Server4You is of the opinion that it is illegal to run a Tor relay in Germany because of the <a href="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hackerparagraf">"Hackerparagraf"</a>. If you don't know what that is, <a href="http://hackingexpose.blogspot.com/2012/04/watch-out-white-hats-european-union_3977.html">read up</a> on recent pushes to enforce similar legislation EU wide.</p>

<p>After a fruitless discussion of said law, the — admittely nice — guy on the phone reassured me that my server will be restarted if I agree to disable the Tor node. I politely told him that I have no interest in using their services at all if I can't use them the way I want to, so I'll cancel my contract with Server4You as soon as possible. For the time being I donated some money to Tor, moved my blog over to <a href="http://www.heroku.com/">Heroku</a> (yay <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>) and started evaluating hosting providers in countries with saner legislation (as long as there still are some).</p>

<p>Sure, there's probably a lot of really bad things happening over the Tor network, but those shouldn't be used to discredit the tool's legitimate uses. If we start blaming technology instead of people, we might as well turn off the Internet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2012-02-05]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/02/05/information-overload-2012-02-05/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/02/05/information-overload-2012-02-05</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>[T]oday's strangeness, while only a few mouse-clicks away from anyone, becomes difficult to find because it has to occur to you to Google it. You may be able to Google everything, but the trick is figuring what you need to Google.</p><footer><strong>William Gibson</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.theverge.com/2012/1/24/2724370/william-gibson-intervie'>An Interview With William Gibson</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.wired.com/geekdad/2012/01/everything-about-learning/">Everything You Thought You Knew About Learning Is Wrong</a><br>I like articles on learning, this one has a few good tips.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2012/1/24/2724370/william-gibson-interview">An interview with William Gibson</a><br>Title says it all.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-13886440">Netherlands makes net neutrality a law</a><br>This is not the first sensible law the Netherlands pass.</li>
<li><a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/news/2012/01/internet-awash-in-inaccurate-anti-acta-arguments.ars">As Anonymous protests, Internet drowns in inaccurate anti-ACTA arguments</a><br>If you are following the current ACTA debate (and you should be), this one is a must read.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.wired.com/magazine/2011/12/ff_riots/all/1">#Riot: Self-Organized, Hyper-Networked Revolts&mdash;Coming to a City Near You</a><br>The second Wired article in this week's issue, a very interesting piece on crowds, flash mobs and riots in connection with Social Media.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.vice.com/read/interview-with-ketamine-chemist-704-v18n2">Interview With A Ketamine Chemist</a><br>Fascinating interview with the creator of some <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dissociative">dissociative drugs</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2012/01/03/the_myth_of_europe?page=full">The Myth of Europe</a><br>A very thorough and interesting take on the EU and European identity. I for one would be sad if the Union failed, because I really enjoy a Europe with almost no borders, the right to work and live in any of the 27 member states and so on. I don't think that the level of centralization this has reached is the way to go though...</li>
<li><a href="http://www.lettersofnote.com/2012/01/to-my-old-master.html">To My Old Master</a><br>A letter from a former slave to his old "master".</li>
<li><a href="http://www.zephoria.org/thoughts/archives/2011/12/12/questions-bullying-suicide.html">Four Difficult Questions Regarding Bullying and Youth Suicide</a><br>Interesting questions for a necessary debate.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/insertcoin/2012/02/03/you-will-never-kill-piracy-and-piracy-will-never-kill-you/">You Will Never Kill Piracy, and Piracy Will Never Kill You</a><br>Despite the headline, this has been published by Forbes. BTW: I think the proposed "Movie Steam" is a fantastic idea and I'd love to use something like that.</li>
</ul>


<p><blockquote><p>The only other thing you could get the internet to agree on was if they tried to institute a ban on cat pictures.</p><footer><strong>Paul Tassi</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.forbes.com/sites/insertcoin/2012/02/03/you-will-never-kill-piracy-and-piracy-will-never-kill-you/'>You Will Never Kill Piracy, and Piracy Will Never Kill You</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2012-01-29]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/01/29/information-overload-2012-01-29/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/01/29/information-overload-2012-01-29</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://benwerd.com/blog/2012/01/22/die-hollywood-die/">Die, Hollywood, die!</a><br>A voice of reason in the <a href="http://ycombinator.com/rfs9.html">"Kill Hollywood"</a> discussion.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.wired.com/magazine/2012/01/ff_ux/all/1">The New French Hacker-Artist Underground</a><br>The French group UX sneaks into places to restore them (or the art inside them). A fascinating read.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.wienerzeitung.at/nachrichten/kultur/medien/?em_cnt=427905">Die Opfer von Niklaas und Perrine</a><br>Granted, this article makes most sense if you were born in the 1970s (or early 1980s) and grew up in Austria, but I still wanted to include it here (in German).</li>
<li><a href="https://blog.torproject.org/blog/tale-new-censors-vodafone-uk-t-mobile-uk-o2-uk-and-t-mobile-usa">A tale of new censors - Vodafone UK, T-Mobile UK, O2 UK, and T-Mobile USA</a><br>If you think only China and dictatorships in the Middle East censor the internet, think again.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.humbledmba.com/public-speaking-for-normal-people">Public speaking for normal people</a><br>Public speaking is a difficult topic for me. I like doing it, but tend to be rather nervous. Once I'm done I always feel like my talks were horrible, but feedback usually suggests they weren't. This post has some interesting ideas which I'm eager to try out.</li>
<li><a href="http://whorulesamerica.net/power/investment_manager.html">An Investment Manager's View on the Top 1%</a><br>Seems like the "Occupy" movement should have adopted we are the 99.9% as a slogan.</li>
<li><a href="http://danielmiessler.com/study/infosec_interview_questions/">Information Security Interview Questions</a><br>If you want to get into information security, you should read this article for a little self assessment.</li>
<li><a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/news/2012/01/mega-man-the-bizarre-rise-and-sudden-downfall-of-kim-dotcom.ars/1">Mega-man: The fast, fabulous, fraudulent life of Megaupload's Kim Dotcom</a><br>Interesting portrait of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kim_Dotcom">Kim Dotcom</a>, the man who's all over the news again.</li>
<li><a href="http://lists.busybox.net/pipermail/busybox/2010-December/074114.html">Understanding the bin, sbin, usr/bin , usr/sbin split</a><br>This mailing list post is an interesting bit of Unix trivia.</li>
<li><a href="http://reason.com/archives/2012/01/26/how-much-is-an-astronauts-life-worth">How Much Is an Astronaut’s Life Worth?</a><br>Some interesting points on a controversial topic.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2012-01-22]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/01/22/information-overload-2012-01-22/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/01/22/information-overload-2012-01-22</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>We defeat SOPA today, only to face it again tomorrow. It's like trying to stop a cold by blowing your nose. It's time we go after the virus.</p><footer><strong>Maddox</strong> <cite><a href='http://maddox.xmission.com/'>I Hope SOPA Passes</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://werebuild.eu/wiki/Blue_cabinet">Blue cabinet</a><br>A project that wants "to name, shame and expose those who profit on selling the surveillance equipment that enables the intimidation, harassment and killing of innocent people".</li>
<li><a href="http://acko.net/blog/making-love-to-webkit/">Making Love To WebKit</a><br><a href="http://acko.net">Acko.net</a> always had awesome design, but his newest one is absolutely mindblowing.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.tangledwilderness.org/pdfs/saidthepottothekettle-web.pdf">said the pot to the kettle</a><br>This PDf subtitled "feminist theory for anarchist men" is a good read for everyone who's interested in overcoming antiquated gender stereotypes, be they male or female.</li>
<li><a href="http://maddox.xmission.com/">I hope SOPA passes</a><br>Typical Maddox style.</li>
<li><a href="http://jeffdechambeau.com/friending-fast-and-slow.html">Behavioral economics and facebook conspiracy theories</a><br>While the author talks about a conspiracy theory, I think it's fair to assume that the big web companies do use behavioral psychology when trying to get us to click on ads.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2012/jan/20/iran-war-brewing-simon-tisdall">An Iran war is brewing from mutual ignorance and chronic miscalculation</a><br>I still have the naive hope that war is evitable.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.spiegel.de/netzwelt/netzpolitik/0,1518,773495,00.html">US-Copyright-Cops greifen weltweit zu</a><br>If you have German speaking friends who you want to educate about SOPA/PIPA, point them to this article by "Der Spiegel".</li>
<li><a href="http://prezi.com/2lanmqb0nnkj/paredit-emacs-minor-mode/">Paredit - emacs minor mode</a><br>A neat presentation on Paredit, a great Emacs minor mode for Lisp hackers.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/in-which-i-fix-my-girlfriends-grandparents-wifi-and-am-hailed-as-a-conquering-hero">In Which I Fix My Girlfriend’s Grandparents’ WIFI And Am Hailed As A Conquering Hero.</a><br>We've all been there, but this is brilliantly told.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.good.is/post/people-are-awesome-the-south-carolina-coffee-shop-where-everyone-pays-for-everyone-else-s-drinks">People Are Awesome: The Coffee Shop Where Everyone Pays for Everyone Else's Drinks</a><br>It's not often enough that I get to post something nice here.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2012-01-15]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/01/15/information-overload-2012-01-15/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/01/15/information-overload-2012-01-15</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>As Reuters points out, diplomats are particularly upset by assassination plots against . . . diplomats.</p><footer><strong>Juan Cole</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.juancole.com/2012/01/a-murder-in-tehran.html'>A Murder in Tehran</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://owni.eu/2012/01/10/twitter-the-new-frontline-in-global-cyber-jihad-al-qaeda-somalia/">Twitter: The New Frontline In Global Cyber Jihad"</a><br>I despise terminology like "cyber war" and "cyber jihad", but the article is still rather interesting.</li>
<li><a href="http://gravityandlevity.wordpress.com/2009/07/08/your-body-wasnt-built-to-last-a-lesson-from-human-mortality-rates/">Your body wasn’t built to last: a lesson from human mortality rates</a><br>I've never heard of Gompertz' law before, but it's rather intriguing.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.juancole.com/2012/01/a-murder-in-tehran.html">A Murder in Tehran</a><br>Being a scientist in Iran can be dangerous if you work in the "wrong" field.</li>
<li><a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/01/13/google-fraudulently-solicits-f.html">The Google-Kenya ripoff</a><br>I can't believe that Google would be this stupid, but I'll keep an eye on this. Here's the <a href="http://blog.mocality.co.ke/2012/01/13/google-what-were-you-thinking/">blog post</a> by the company that raised the allegations.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.chinaafricarealstory.com/2012/01/zambezi-valley-chinas-first.html">"The Zambezi Valley: China's First Agricultural Colony?" Fiction or Fact?</a><br>I don't know all the research, but this seems like an interesting topic to investigate.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.sueddeutsche.de/leben/ethik-in-der-ernaehrung-nicht-fisch-nicht-fleisch-1.53590">Nicht Fisch! Nicht Fleisch!</a><br>This article about the various problems related to meat consumption is 2 years old and at least as relevant today as it was back then (in German).</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2086392/Syria-Secrets-city-siege.html">Secrets from the city under siege</a><br>Smuggled pictures from the Syrian city of Homs and an interesting article to go with them.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law/2012/jan/13/tvshack-student-founder-extradition">TVShack's student founder can be extradited to US, court rules</a><br>Whatever became of protecting your citizens? If he broke UK law try him there.</li>
<li><a href="http://news.travel.aol.com/2011/02/28/why-did-tsa-pat-down-kids-adults-getting-off-train/">Why Did TSA Pat Down Kids, Adults Getting Off Train?</a><br>Welcome to the police state. Terrorists win.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/01/15/opinion/sunday/the-rise-of-the-new-groupthink.html?_r=3&amp;hp=&amp;pagewanted=all">The Rise of the New Groupthink</a><br>I'm always in favor of pro-introvert artciles.</li>
</ul>


<p><blockquote><p>[I]ntroverts are comfortable working alone — and solitude is a catalyst to innovation.</p><footer><strong>Susan Cain</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.nytimes.com/2012/01/15/opinion/sunday/the-rise-of-the-new-groupthink.html?_r=3&amp;hp=&amp;pagewanted=all'>The Rise of the New Groupthink</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
