<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ubuntu | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/ubuntu/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-29T22:35:06+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[linuxConverts++]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2005/11/23/linuxconverts/"/>
    <updated>2005-11-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2005/11/23/linuxconverts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While my girlfriend was visiting her sister in Rotterdam, I finally set up her notebook to dual boot Windows XP and Ubuntu Linux. Before you think bad of me: I didn't sneakily do this without her knowing, but instead because she once mentioned that she'd like to try out another OS.</p>

<p>Now you may wonder why I chose Ubuntu over Gentoo, but I'm afraid the answer is rather pragmatic and uninspired: I had a magazine CD of the current release, so I dind't have to download an ISO. Also installation is fast and painless and there are lots of nice HOWTOs. Besides that I've aleady used Ubuntu to convert one of my non-techy friends to Linux and it has worked pretty good. To sum it up: I think Ubuntu is a decent distro, but I maybe wouldn't use it on one of my own boxes.</p>

<p>Back to the original topic: I'm really curious to see how well my girlfriend will get along with her new operating system... So far it seems she'll have a smooth transition. There are free alternatives for all the programs she uses on a regular basis and I found a nice explanation of how to "share Firefox and Thunderbird profiles on a dual boot system":http://www.plaintivemewling.com/?p=20 (the link doesn't contain anything surprising, but it's a nice reference anyway). Additionally I'm really curious to see how she will like "GNOME":http://www.gnome.org/ and if she finds it as user-friendly as I do.</p>

<p>Boomtime, The Aftermath 35, 3171 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
