<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: youtube | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/youtube/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-03T21:35:14+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Videos for the masses]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/09/24/videos-for-the-masses/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/09/24/videos-for-the-masses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the last few weeks the ongoing struggle between good (aka going out to party) and evil (aka work) has led to a severe lack of sleep and a general feeling of exhaustion. That's why yesterday evening I only had some running sushi with friends and a few beers afterwards, before returning home before midnight. But instead of going to bed immediately, I made the fatal mistake of visiting "YouTube":http://www.youtube.com/ to watch the videos "Lotussteve":http://www.cargal.org, "m3":http://www.leyrer.priv.at/martin/ and "Red":http://red667.org/ have recommended. Here are some of my favorites, thanks guys!</p>

<ul>
<li>"Live Super Mario Bros.":http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E3IwiynxE3A - A bunch of high school students doing a rendition of Super Mario Bros. Great stuff and very funny.</li>
<li>"The Internet Is A Series of Tubes":http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1lYiDo0DjSk - "The Daily Show's":http://www.comedycentral.com/shows/the_daily_show/index.jhtml Jon Stewart explains how the internet works. You shouldn't miss that one!</li>
<li>"New Super Mario Bros. Final Castle 105 seconds World Record":http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jVXNL4n73-E - Amazing!</li>
<li>"PS3 vs. Wii":http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QpYgNz6W6Gs - I'm intending to buy a Wii anyway, but this video is just hilarious.</li>
<li>"Almost - Cheese & Crackers":http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aZtmrunVXs4 - Coolest miniramp skate session ever. Read my lips: EVER!</li>
</ul>


<p>When I finished watching the stuff my friends had recommended, I started browsing around the site and found the following gem I immediately subscribed to:</p>

<p>"Happy Slip Productions":http://www.youtube.com/profile?user=HappySlip - A Filipina actress who is doing some seriously funny stuff.</p>

<p>After I freed myself from the black hole that YouTube is for one's free time, I decided to finally watch "Elephants Dream":http://orange.blender.org/, an animated movie realized entirely with free software, which I downloaded a few weeks ago but never had time to watch before. It's really great and of course CC licensed.</p>

<p>Boomtime, Bureaucracy 48, 3172 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
