<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: poker | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/poker/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-25T17:51:05+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drawing dead]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2007/02/21/drawing-dead/"/>
    <updated>2007-02-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2007/02/21/drawing-dead</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In poker the term "drawing dead" refers to the process of drawing to a hand which will lose even if you make it, e.g. drawing to a flush when your opponent already has a full house. Learning to identify such situations will save you a lot of money and make you sleep better.</p>

<p>But I think it's pretty important to apply this principle - and many others found in poker - to your real life as well. Don't waste your time and energy chasing something that won't win you the pot (e.g. make you happy) anyway. Don't feel committed to something or someone because you've already made a big investment in terms of time, money, feelings or whatever, when you realize that you're essentially drawing dead. Learning to let go at the right moment is a very important skill, and even if it hurts quite badly at times, it will spare you from far more serious trouble in the long run.</p>

<p>Boomtime, Chaos 52, 3173 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In the poker game of life, women are the rake man.]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2007/02/03/in-the-poker-game-of-life-women-are-the-rake-man/"/>
    <updated>2007-02-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2007/02/03/in-the-poker-game-of-life-women-are-the-rake-man</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished watching "Rounders":http://imdb.com/title/tt0128442/ about half an hour ago, which is a really nice Poker movie and quite entertaining in general. Although the plot is a little too predictable at times, the great cast including Matt Damon, Edward Norton, John Turturro and John Malkovich more than makes up for it. The soundtrack was pretty cool too, so I decided to also order it along with a DVD of "The Cincinnati Kid":http://imdb.com/title/tt0059037/.</p>

<p>For additional Poker entertainment season 3 of "High Stakes Poker":http://www.gsn.com/hsp started not too long ago and the first three episodes have been pretty good, although I'm already quite fed up by Mike Matusow's constant babbling. I'm just not that happy with the player selection for the current season, since Phil Ivey and Gus Hansen are missing and I'd also love to see one of my personal favorites, Chris Esfandiari. Nonetheless I find HSP a lot more entertaining than NBC's "Poker After Dark":http://www.nbcsports.com/poker/index.html, which had a great start when Phil Hellmuth was going ballistic in the very first episode.</p>

<p>I also found a really interesting thread on the 2+2 forums, where "Nate." took on the challenge in turning $5 into $1000 in less than a week on PokerStars. I really wonder if the $5 Stars recently transferred to my account - I've only been playing Party and FullTilt lately - should be treated as a sign to try the same? ;)</p>

<p>Oh, and for the title of this post: It's a quote from Rounders, and it's as true as it gets.</p>

<p>Setting Orange, Chaos 35, 3173 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally...]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/11/05/finally/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/11/05/finally</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>...some random stuff I wanted to blog about for quite some time already:</p>

<ul>
<li>*Pearl Jam concert (September 25th@Wiener Stadthalle):* I have to admit that I'm not the biggest "PJ":http://pearljam.com/ fan, but since Silvia was nice enough to invite me (thanks by the way!), I went to see one of the best concerts in a long time! The band and the atmosphere was great and I was quite surprised to see the traditionally rather lame crowd in Vienna so excited! (<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157594302284739">pics@flickr</a>)</li>

<li>*Internet Explorer on Linux:* As we all know, IE sucks donkey balls. But some sites who don't care about standards - and whose developers definitely should be first against the wall when the revolution comes - only work with Microsoft's browser. But don't despair, help is available in form of "IEs4Linux":http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page, a shellscript which downloads IE and automatically configures Wine for it. Flash 9 is also included and if you really insist on it, you can run 3 different versions of IE at the same time (5, 5.5 and 6), which is pretty handy for web developers. I have IE6 installed on my Kubuntu system for quite a while now, and in the rare cases I really need it, it works like a charm.</li>

<li>*Pokerstars client on Linux:* Most online Poker sites don't seem to be interested in Linux users, since the clients they offer are mostly only available for Windows. Some of them at least offer Java clients, but with my general dislike for most things Java and my strong preference of "Pokerstars":http://www.pokerstars.com/ over other Poker sites, I gave the client a shot under Wine and was really pleased to find out that it just works (tm). Of course it would be much nicer to have a native client, but for the time being I'm happy enough with this workaround.</li>

<li>*UEFA cup Pasching vs. Livorno@Pasching:* Went with some other Sportclub fans to see the UEFA cup match Pasching vs. Livorno in Pasching. It was a great day, and I still laugh my ass off when I think about the policemen and -women who found our little group of around 25 people rooting for the away team  (as Austrian you were only able to buy tickets for the home sectors) so frightening, that they not only surrounded us for the whole match, but even put on their riot gear. And there I was, thinking every policeman in Austria already knows that we are only dangerous to ourselves. ;)</li>

<li>*man pages:* Read them! You know you should! Even if you believe you know an application. E.g.: "man sshd", section "AUTHORIZED_KEYS FILE FORMAT". Or am I really the only person who didn't know about all the useful options like "from", "command", "no-port-forwarding", "no-pty" etc.?

<li>*Mac stuff:* Here's some cool widgets and plugins which make the OS X experience even nicer: "iTunesShut":http://homepage.mac.com/WebObjects/FileSharing.woa/wa/iTunesShut.zip.zip?a=downloadFile&user=gugulino1&path=.Public/iTunesShut.zip, "VI Input Manager":http://www.corsofamily.net/jcorso/vi/, "Application Update Widget":http://www.dashboardwidgets.com/showcase/details.php?wid=1510 (thanks Moose!), "AppleScript Shell":http://hayne.net/MacDev/Ash/, "Doug's AppleScripts for iTunes":http://www.dougscripts.com/itunes/index.php
</ul>




<br />


<p>Last but not least here are some funny/interesting things I found over the past few weeks:</p>

<ul>
<li>"Programming Language Inventor or Serial Killer":http://www.malevole.com/mv/misc/killerquiz (via <a href="http://metalab.at/wiki/Hauptseite">metalab-members</a>)</li>

<li>*Robot chicken:* Great stop motion animation. Examples: "1":http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-2660802447916665129&q=robot+chicken, "2":http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=4651757054772769361&q=robot+chicken, "3":http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=5395083952125133994&q=robot+chicken (thanks <a href="http://gnulords.org/~colo/serendipity/">colo</a>!)</li>

<li>"ELP Laser Turntable":http://elpj.com/: "bonki":http://bonki.net/blog/ posted this a while back, but I never came around to post it here.</li>

<li>"Bruce Schreier facts":http://geekz.co.uk/schneierfacts/fact/128: 'cause Chuck Norris isn't as cool as Bruce! And as we all know: Bruce Schneier tapdances in Morse Code. (via <a href="http://berq.net/">berq</a>)</li>

<li>"China Makes a Sexy, Slutty Robot":http://www.gizmodo.com/gadgets/robots/china-makes-a-sexy-slutty-robot-210802.php: What can I say... (thanks <a href="http://www.leyrer.priv.at/martin/">m3</a>)</li>
</ul>


<p>Prickle-Prickle, The Aftermath 17, 3172 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hold'em tightly]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/08/23/holdem-tightly/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/08/23/holdem-tightly</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I spent a great evening playing Texas Hold'em with some friends. Sure, I've lost some money, but it wasn't much and I was prepared for that anyway. I could have stopped after I won some nice pots, but netting a profit definitly didn't seem to be on my agenda yesterday. Instead I thought a lot about the game and came to conclude the following.</p>

<p>*) Relax and look forward, things will get a lot easier that way.</p>

<p>*) Most things in life depend on luck. However, it's up to you how you deal with it.</p>

<p>*) Don't get cocky if you're succesful, otherwise you'll most probably fall hard.</p>

<p>*) Being unpredictable really may pay off in tense situations.</p>

<p>*) You have to take risks if you want to win big. And you'll never really feel the rush of winning if you didn't take the risk to lose in the first place.</p>

<p>*) You don't really have to be good. The others just need to believe you are.</p>

<p>*) Money attracts more money. Gambling is easy if loosing doesn't hurt.</p>

<p>I had a lot more of this, but I guess by now you get what I'm aiming at: Better to have loved and lost, than never loved at all. Am I still talking about Poker? I guess so.</p>

<p>Setting Orange, Bureaucracy 16, 3172 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
