<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: gnome | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.github.io/blog/categories/gnome/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-07T21:25:16+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[linuxConverts++]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.github.io/blog/2005/11/23/linuxconverts/"/>
    <updated>2005-11-23T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.github.io/blog/2005/11/23/linuxconverts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While my girlfriend was visiting her sister in Rotterdam, I finally set up her notebook to dual boot Windows XP and Ubuntu Linux. Before you think bad of me: I didn&rsquo;t sneakily do this without her knowing, but instead because she once mentioned that she&rsquo;d like to try out another OS.</p>

<p>Now you may wonder why I chose Ubuntu over Gentoo, but I&rsquo;m afraid the answer is rather pragmatic and uninspired: I had a magazine CD of the current release, so I dind&rsquo;t have to download an ISO. Also installation is fast and painless and there are lots of nice HOWTOs. Besides that I&rsquo;ve aleady used Ubuntu to convert one of my non-techy friends to Linux and it has worked pretty good. To sum it up: I think Ubuntu is a decent distro, but I maybe wouldn&rsquo;t use it on one of my own boxes.</p>

<p>Back to the original topic: I&rsquo;m really curious to see how well my girlfriend will get along with her new operating system&hellip; So far it seems she&rsquo;ll have a smooth transition. There are free alternatives for all the programs she uses on a regular basis and I found a nice explanation of how to &ldquo;share Firefox and Thunderbird profiles on a dual boot system&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.plaintivemewling.com/?p=20">http://www.plaintivemewling.com/?p=20</a> (the link doesn&rsquo;t contain anything surprising, but it&rsquo;s a nice reference anyway). Additionally I&rsquo;m really curious to see how she will like &ldquo;GNOME&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.gnome.org/">http://www.gnome.org/</a> and if she finds it as user-friendly as I do.</p>

<p>Boomtime, The Aftermath 35, 3171 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[So what's the word? RUBY!]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.github.io/blog/2005/11/18/so-whats-the-word-ruby/"/>
    <updated>2005-11-18T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.github.io/blog/2005/11/18/so-whats-the-word-ruby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week I finally had a little more time to work on Gentoo related things again, so I commited some overdue packages to the tree.</p>

<p>The action started on Tuesday, when I commited the 20+ ebuilds from &ldquo;ruby-gnome-0.14.1&rdquo;:<a href="http://ruby-gnome2.sourceforge.jp/">http://ruby-gnome2.sourceforge.jp/</a> (mostly version bumps plus a few new packages like &ldquo;ruby-gtkmozembed&rdquo;:<a href="http://ruby-gnome2.sourceforge.jp/hiki.cgi?RubyZilla">http://ruby-gnome2.sourceforge.jp/hiki.cgi?RubyZilla</a>). Quite a lot of users have been waiting for this, as the previous version we had in the tree (0.12.0) didn&rsquo;t play nicely with GTK+ 2.8/GNOME 2.12. This problems are now sorted, so that quite a few bugs could be closed and marked fixed. :)</p>

<p>And then &ldquo;George released Nitro 0.25.0&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.gmosx.com/article/2">http://www.gmosx.com/article/2</a> yesterday, which found its way into the tree only hours later. This has mainly to do with the fact that I already had everything in place from the 0.24.0 release, which I then never commited because George said that there soon will be a release focussed on bug fixes and code clean-up. Apparently this has worked out nicely, so go ahaed, emerge &ldquo;Nitro&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.nitrohq.com/">http://www.nitrohq.com/</a> and play around with it, I&rsquo;m sure you&rsquo;ll like it.</p>

<p>In the evening &ldquo;we&rdquo;:<a href="http://aglug.net">http://aglug.net</a> had our montly Viennese Gentoo users meetup, which as always was really funny. I came home pretty late and my head still hurts, but it definitely was among the most entertaining evenings in the last few weeks. Thanks guys!</p>

<p>Boomtime, The Aftermath 30, 3171 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lazy sunday afternoon]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.github.io/blog/2005/09/11/lazy-sunday-afternoon/"/>
    <updated>2005-09-11T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.github.io/blog/2005/09/11/lazy-sunday-afternoon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today is the perfect example of a nice and lazy afternoon, and I just love it! After having a great brunch at &ldquo;HighTea&rdquo;:<a href="http://hightea.at/">http://hightea.at/</a> where we had toasties, antipasti, bagles and lots of other really good stuff, I&rsquo;m just hanging around in front of my PC reading, doing some Gentoo work and generally having a good time. Live can be so easy&hellip; :)</p>

<p>Now let&rsquo;s see if I have anything interesting to tell you:<!--more-->
* &ldquo;OSNews&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.osnews.com/">http://www.osnews.com/</a> had a &ldquo;review of GNOME 2.12&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.osnews.com/story.php?news_id=11800">http://www.osnews.com/story.php?news_id=11800</a> and Eugenia seems to enjoy the new release as much as I do. Although she also points out some drawbacks of the desktop environment as lacking good API docs and a RAD tool, she concludes that &ldquo;[&hellip;] Gnome 2.12 is the best X11 DE there is&rdquo;. You wonder why? Because &ldquo;all in all, Gnome is today more powerful, better integrated to the underlying system with DBUS and HAL, looks good, behaves as expected and, most of all, it&rsquo;s simple and clean&rdquo;. I couldn&rsquo;t agree more! (via &ldquo;FootNotes&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.gnomedesktop.org">http://www.gnomedesktop.org</a>)
<br>
* A fellow Gentoo developer convinced me to start hanging out on IRC regularly, which I now do despite being a little reluctant at first. But after two or three weeks I can see all the positive effects this has had for my dev work, which may also have to do with my further increased feeling of being part of a larger community. Directly (as in chat vs. mail) communicating with people really can do wonders for understanding each other better&hellip; If you got something you want to tell me, you&rsquo;ll find me as &lsquo;citizen428&rsquo; (surprising, huh?) on Freenode where I usually can be found in #gentoo-bsd, #gentoo-dev, #gentoo-ruby and #nitro.
<br>
* I&rsquo;ve been looking for new Linux games and have found &ldquo;OpenAnno&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.lanadminsystem.de/cgi-bin/Lanas.pl?OPENANNO">http://www.lanadminsystem.de/cgi-bin/Lanas.pl?OPENANNO</a> and &ldquo;The Mana World&rdquo;:<a href="http://themanaworld.org/,">http://themanaworld.org/,</a> which both look promising but are still in early stages of development.
<br>
* Read a &ldquo;shocking account&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.filmstadtinferno.de/offener_kanal.htm">http://www.filmstadtinferno.de/offener_kanal.htm</a> (in German) of how the &ldquo;Livorno&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.livornocalcio.it/">http://www.livornocalcio.it/</a> &ldquo;Ultras&rdquo;:<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultras">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ultras</a> and their German visitors got treated by the police in Rome after the game against Lazio. Carabinieri vaffanculo!
<br>
* Want to create your own first person shooter? Have fun with &ldquo;FPS Creator&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.fpscreator.com/!">http://www.fpscreator.com/!</a> It uses DirectX though, so you&rsquo;re stuck to Windows&hellip; :(
<br>
* For all you music lovers out there, make sure to check out the Flash magazine &ldquo;Music Hurts&rdquo;:<a href="http://musichurts.com/!">http://musichurts.com/!</a> I got the link from the current print issue of &ldquo;de:bug&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.de-bug.de/,">http://www.de-bug.de/,</a> a magazine you definitely should check out when you&rsquo;re into electronic music!</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for today, see you at the next episode of &ldquo;citizen428&rsquo;s random link dump&rdquo;!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A first look at GNOME 2.12_rc1]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.github.io/blog/2005/09/06/a-first-look-at-gnome-2-12_rc1/"/>
    <updated>2005-09-06T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.github.io/blog/2005/09/06/a-first-look-at-gnome-2-12_rc1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve &ldquo;already blogged&rdquo;:<a href="http://citizen428.net/archives/198-GNOME-goodness.html">http://citizen428.net/archives/198-GNOME-goodness.html</a> about this &ldquo;preview of GNOME 2.12&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.gnome.org/~davyd/gnome-2-12/">http://www.gnome.org/~davyd/gnome-2-12/</a> a while ago and talked about how eager I am to try out this new release. So when Gentoo developer John N. Laliberte &ldquo;asked&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.mail-archive.com/gentoo-dev@lists.gentoo.org/msg04235.html">http://www.mail-archive.com/gentoo-dev@lists.gentoo.org/msg04235.html</a> for some people willing to test the ebuilds for GNOME-2.12_rc1, I immediately went ahead and installed them.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Thanks to the <i>package.keywords</i>, <i>package.unmask</i> and testing instructions Nathaniel &ldquo;provides&rdquo;:<a href="http://dev.gentoo.org/~allanonjl/gnome/2.12_rc/,">http://dev.gentoo.org/~allanonjl/gnome/2.12_rc/,</a> the whole process is really straight forward, although I had to add <i>x11-libs/libsvg-cairo</i> and <i>sys-apps/pmount</i> to aforementioned config files. After this I just removed &ldquo;Epiphany&rdquo;:<a href="http://dev.gentoo.org/~allanonjl/gnome/2.12_rc/">http://dev.gentoo.org/~allanonjl/gnome/2.12_rc/</a> and everything related to &ldquo;Evolution&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.novell.com/products/desktop/features/evolution.html">http://www.novell.com/products/desktop/features/evolution.html</a> from the meta-ebuild, as I&rsquo;m really happy with &ldquo;Firefox&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.mozilla.org/products/firefox/">http://www.mozilla.org/products/firefox/</a> and &ldquo;Sylpheed-claws&rdquo;:<a href="http://claws.sylpheed.org/,">http://claws.sylpheed.org/,</a> especially since I use a version of the latter that is linked against &ldquo;GTK+-2.8.3&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.gtk.org/">http://www.gtk.org/</a> and therefore not only looks better, but finally has good support for Unicode thanks to &ldquo;Pango&rdquo;:<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pango.">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pango.</a> I&rsquo;m glad that Gentoo&rsquo;s flexible nature gives me the possibility to leave out exactly they 3 or 4 packages I don&rsquo;t need, without loosing the ability to install GNOME via Portage!</p>

<p>Installation went smoothly, but when i first started my new desktop my two panels didn&rsquo;t work. I soon found out that this had to do with GTK+-2.8.3 and that this &ldquo;bug&rdquo;:<a href="http://bugs.gentoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=104820">http://bugs.gentoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=104820</a> has been fixed in <i>gtk+-2.8.3-r1.ebuild</i>. And indeed, re-emerging gtk, gnome-desktop and gnome-panel (just to be sure) really fixed this issues, and I now have this shiny new GNOME 2.12 that I <em>really</em> love! :)</p>

<p>The new default theme called &ldquo;Clearlooks&rdquo; is really neat, especially in combination with my currently favorite icon theme called &ldquo;Kreski Lines&rdquo;:<a href="http://art.gnome.org/themes/icon/1008.">http://art.gnome.org/themes/icon/1008.</a> But there&rsquo;s another reason why GNOME 2.12 looks as good as it does: the underlying toolkit GTK+ is now linked against the vector graphics library &ldquo;Cairo&rdquo;:<a href="http://cairographics.org/introduction,">http://cairographics.org/introduction,</a> which - to quote the preview - allows for &ldquo;smoother edges, RGBA translucency and better looking, more flexible theming&rdquo;. Additionally this also offers the possibility to accelerate graphics through OpenGL via &ldquo;Glitz&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.freedesktop.org/Software/glitz.">http://www.freedesktop.org/Software/glitz.</a> I also like the new spatial tree view in Nautilus (maybe I&rsquo;ll start using it now), as well as all the other cool small changes and feature additions. And I&rsquo;m sure there&rsquo;s some more nice stuff I haven&rsquo;t discovered yet&hellip; Unfortunately the much anticipated &ldquo;Evince&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.gnome.org/projects/evince/">http://www.gnome.org/projects/evince/</a> doesn&rsquo;t work for me, it only shows some garbled up text when looking at a PDF that works perfectly fine in &ldquo;GPdf&rdquo;:<a href="http://freshmeat.net/projects/gpdf/.">http://freshmeat.net/projects/gpdf/.</a></p>

<p>Once again the GNOME team has been very active and put lots of nice stuff into this new release, and I really like the overall direction of the project, viz providing users with a desktop that is easy and intuitive to use and which doesn&rsquo;t get in your way. At the same time it is offering a nice framework for application developers, especially since we have Mono. Thanks to all the people who make this possible!</p>

<p>BTW: a screenshot of my current setup can be seen at the top of the right sidebar, where from now on I wil regularly post pictures of my desktops.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mono: A Developer's Notebook]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.github.io/blog/2005/08/24/mono-a-developers-notebook/"/>
    <updated>2005-08-24T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.github.io/blog/2005/08/24/mono-a-developers-notebook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yeah, today my copy of &ldquo;Mono: A Developer&rsquo;s Notebook&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0596007922/qid=1124917941/sr=8-1/ref=pd_bbs_1/002-4699908-2098445?v=glance&amp;s=books&amp;n=507846">http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0596007922/qid=1124917941/sr=8-1/ref=pd_bbs_1/002-4699908-2098445?v=glance&amp;s=books&amp;n=507846</a> finally arrived! I ordered this book because I&rsquo;m a fan of &ldquo;Mono&rdquo;:<a href="http://www.mono-project.com/Main_Page">http://www.mono-project.com/Main_Page</a> pretty much since I&rsquo;ve first heard about it, and examples like this &ldquo;tutorial on writing a web browser&rdquo;:<a href="http://primates.ximian.com/~edasque/projects/Tutorial/glade2.html">http://primates.ximian.com/~edasque/projects/Tutorial/glade2.html</a> show that the framework is quite capable. Additionally there are all this cool new GNOME apps like Blam!, Beagle, f-spot, Tomboy etc., that demonstrate the possibilites of Mono.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s why I ordered this book that has gotten pretty good reviews everywhere and which was modelled after the important FOSS mantra &ldquo;Show me the code!&rdquo;. Instead of long-winded syntactical explanations, the author uses lots of annotated examples to get his point across. I hope that this weekend I&rsquo;ll have some free time to get started with reading&hellip;. :)</p>

<p>A last note: it&rsquo;s incredibly cool that Amazon gives you the possibility to buy books from alternative   dealers via their site! I can go to Amazon, look for the books I&rsquo;m interested in, read the reviews etc. and then compare if it may be cheaper to buy this book somewhere else. And if it really is, I can still buy the book as if I would have bought it from Amazon. But guess what? Of all the books I&rsquo;ve ordered there, only 2 so far were from alternative dealers, because most of the time the extra shipment costs make the book more expensive than the ad itself makes you believe. But for the &ldquo;Developer&rsquo;s Notebook&rdquo; it really made sense to buy it from &ldquo;Caiman&rdquo;:<a href="http://caiman.com/,">http://caiman.com/,</a> because it was not only cheaper, I also got the book after 7 days (from Florida!) compared to 10 to 13 days Amazon.de states as delivery time for this article.</p>

<p>P.S. I&rsquo;m tired. My English probably sucks because of that. Live with it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
