<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tips | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/tips/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-25T19:19:13+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Event tip: Coded Cultures 2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/09/15/event-tip-coded-cultures-2011/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/09/15/event-tip-coded-cultures-2011</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The awesome folks of "5uper.net":http://5uper.net/ are organizing the "Coded Cultures":http://codedcultures.net/ festival, an event I highly recommend! Here's their press release:</p>

<blockquote>
CODED CULTURES
CITY AS INTERFACE
FESTIVAL 21/09 - 02/10/2011
TALKS.EXHIBITIONS.WORKSHOPS.

Vom 21. September bis 2. Oktober 2011 wird in Wien das Festival CODED CULTURES von der Gruppe 5uper.net veranstaltet. CODED CULTURES thematisiert die Schnittstellen von zeitgen&ouml;ssischer Kunst, Medien, neuen Technologien und deren Auswirkungen auf Gesellschaft und Kultur. Im Mittelpunkt stehen europ&auml;ische Positionen einer aktuellen Kunstpraxis, die sich auf Medien und deren (Re-)Konfiguration zwischen urbanem und virtuellem Raum konzentriert.

Im Zeitraum von zwei Wochen wird von &uuml;ber 100 K&uuml;nstlern, Kulturschaffenden und Mitarbeitenden das gr&ouml;&szlig;te Wiener Medienkunstfestival an 13 Locations in Wien pr&auml;sentiert.

CITY AS INTERFACE
Im Jahr 2011 konzentriert sich das Festival mit dem Untertitel "City as Interface" auf die Stadt als Austragungsort k&uuml;nstlerischer Interventionen. Dabei wird die Stadt als experimentelles Areal f&uuml;r neue k&uuml;nstlerische Anwendungen gesehen, als Ort an dem k&uuml;nstlerische Prozesse in unterschiedlichsten Formen der Interaktion eingreifen k&ouml;nnen.

K&uuml;nstlergruppen, Kuratoren und Forschende setzen sich mit &ouml;ffentlichem Raum au&szlig;erhalb der "gesicherten" Strukturen dezidierter Kunstareale auseinander. Digitale und mediale Kunstproduktionen spielen mit den Bereichen an der Schnittstelle zwischen realen und virtuellen R&auml;umen und vermitteln, wie neue Medientechnologien die Art und Weise unserer Orientierung und die Prozesse unserer Umweltwahrnehmung ver&auml;ndern.

AUS DEM PROGRAMM
21.09.2011: Er&ouml;ffnung und Pecha Kucha Night: ODEON Serapionstheater
22.09.2011: Fokustag Donaukanal: Badeschiff, Adria, Urania, Central Garden
23.09.2011: Fokustag MuseumsQuartier: RaumD, Electric Avenue, quartier21
24.09.2011: Fokustag 1020: LABfactory, This.Play Space, Glockengasse
No9, MAGAZIN, Lust Gallery
27.09.-30.09.2011: Talks / Workshops: Urania (Mittlerer Saal), This.Play Space
01.10.2011: Lange Nacht der Museen / Abschlussveranstaltung
</blockquote>


<p>Unfortunately I don't know if I'll really make it, since the next two weeks will be super busy. I'll definitely try to drop by though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OpenSolaris cheat sheet]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2010/01/26/opensolaris-cheat-sheet/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2010/01/26/opensolaris-cheat-sheet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've always been a big fan of the handy little utility <a href="http://cheat.errtheblog.com">cheat</a> and recently became interested in <a href="http://hub.opensolaris.org/bin/view/Main/">OpenSolaris</a> (which btw runs fine on my Thinkpad x200s), so I did the obvious and created an OpenSolaris cheat sheet:</p>

<p><a href="http://cheat.errtheblog.com/s/open_solaris">http://cheat.errtheblog.com/s/open_solaris</a></p>

<p>It's still missing information regarding ZFS, but I guess I'll eventually add that too. And who knows, maybe I even get motivated enough for a nicely formatted Latex version...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some more movie recommendations]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2007/07/09/some-more-movie-recommendations/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2007/07/09/some-more-movie-recommendations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some more good movies I've recently (re-)watched:</p>

<p>"American Hardcore":http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0419434/
"Choyonghan kajok":http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0188503/
"Bijitâ Q":http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0290329/
"Katakuri-ke no kôfuku":http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0304262/
"Herz aus Glas":http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0074626/
"Tideland":http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0410764/</p>

<p>Setting Orange, Confusion 44, 3173 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finally...]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/11/05/finally/"/>
    <updated>2006-11-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/11/05/finally</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>...some random stuff I wanted to blog about for quite some time already:</p>

<ul>
<li>*Pearl Jam concert (September 25th@Wiener Stadthalle):* I have to admit that I'm not the biggest "PJ":http://pearljam.com/ fan, but since Silvia was nice enough to invite me (thanks by the way!), I went to see one of the best concerts in a long time! The band and the atmosphere was great and I was quite surprised to see the traditionally rather lame crowd in Vienna so excited! (<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157594302284739">pics@flickr</a>)</li>

<li>*Internet Explorer on Linux:* As we all know, IE sucks donkey balls. But some sites who don't care about standards - and whose developers definitely should be first against the wall when the revolution comes - only work with Microsoft's browser. But don't despair, help is available in form of "IEs4Linux":http://www.tatanka.com.br/ies4linux/page/Main_Page, a shellscript which downloads IE and automatically configures Wine for it. Flash 9 is also included and if you really insist on it, you can run 3 different versions of IE at the same time (5, 5.5 and 6), which is pretty handy for web developers. I have IE6 installed on my Kubuntu system for quite a while now, and in the rare cases I really need it, it works like a charm.</li>

<li>*Pokerstars client on Linux:* Most online Poker sites don't seem to be interested in Linux users, since the clients they offer are mostly only available for Windows. Some of them at least offer Java clients, but with my general dislike for most things Java and my strong preference of "Pokerstars":http://www.pokerstars.com/ over other Poker sites, I gave the client a shot under Wine and was really pleased to find out that it just works (tm). Of course it would be much nicer to have a native client, but for the time being I'm happy enough with this workaround.</li>

<li>*UEFA cup Pasching vs. Livorno@Pasching:* Went with some other Sportclub fans to see the UEFA cup match Pasching vs. Livorno in Pasching. It was a great day, and I still laugh my ass off when I think about the policemen and -women who found our little group of around 25 people rooting for the away team  (as Austrian you were only able to buy tickets for the home sectors) so frightening, that they not only surrounded us for the whole match, but even put on their riot gear. And there I was, thinking every policeman in Austria already knows that we are only dangerous to ourselves. ;)</li>

<li>*man pages:* Read them! You know you should! Even if you believe you know an application. E.g.: "man sshd", section "AUTHORIZED_KEYS FILE FORMAT". Or am I really the only person who didn't know about all the useful options like "from", "command", "no-port-forwarding", "no-pty" etc.?

<li>*Mac stuff:* Here's some cool widgets and plugins which make the OS X experience even nicer: "iTunesShut":http://homepage.mac.com/WebObjects/FileSharing.woa/wa/iTunesShut.zip.zip?a=downloadFile&user=gugulino1&path=.Public/iTunesShut.zip, "VI Input Manager":http://www.corsofamily.net/jcorso/vi/, "Application Update Widget":http://www.dashboardwidgets.com/showcase/details.php?wid=1510 (thanks Moose!), "AppleScript Shell":http://hayne.net/MacDev/Ash/, "Doug's AppleScripts for iTunes":http://www.dougscripts.com/itunes/index.php
</ul>




<br />


<p>Last but not least here are some funny/interesting things I found over the past few weeks:</p>

<ul>
<li>"Programming Language Inventor or Serial Killer":http://www.malevole.com/mv/misc/killerquiz (via <a href="http://metalab.at/wiki/Hauptseite">metalab-members</a>)</li>

<li>*Robot chicken:* Great stop motion animation. Examples: "1":http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-2660802447916665129&q=robot+chicken, "2":http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=4651757054772769361&q=robot+chicken, "3":http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=5395083952125133994&q=robot+chicken (thanks <a href="http://gnulords.org/~colo/serendipity/">colo</a>!)</li>

<li>"ELP Laser Turntable":http://elpj.com/: "bonki":http://bonki.net/blog/ posted this a while back, but I never came around to post it here.</li>

<li>"Bruce Schreier facts":http://geekz.co.uk/schneierfacts/fact/128: 'cause Chuck Norris isn't as cool as Bruce! And as we all know: Bruce Schneier tapdances in Morse Code. (via <a href="http://berq.net/">berq</a>)</li>

<li>"China Makes a Sexy, Slutty Robot":http://www.gizmodo.com/gadgets/robots/china-makes-a-sexy-slutty-robot-210802.php: What can I say... (thanks <a href="http://www.leyrer.priv.at/martin/">m3</a>)</li>
</ul>


<p>Prickle-Prickle, The Aftermath 17, 3172 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Videos for the masses]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/09/24/videos-for-the-masses/"/>
    <updated>2006-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/09/24/videos-for-the-masses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the last few weeks the ongoing struggle between good (aka going out to party) and evil (aka work) has led to a severe lack of sleep and a general feeling of exhaustion. That's why yesterday evening I only had some running sushi with friends and a few beers afterwards, before returning home before midnight. But instead of going to bed immediately, I made the fatal mistake of visiting "YouTube":http://www.youtube.com/ to watch the videos "Lotussteve":http://www.cargal.org, "m3":http://www.leyrer.priv.at/martin/ and "Red":http://red667.org/ have recommended. Here are some of my favorites, thanks guys!</p>

<ul>
<li>"Live Super Mario Bros.":http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E3IwiynxE3A - A bunch of high school students doing a rendition of Super Mario Bros. Great stuff and very funny.</li>
<li>"The Internet Is A Series of Tubes":http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1lYiDo0DjSk - "The Daily Show's":http://www.comedycentral.com/shows/the_daily_show/index.jhtml Jon Stewart explains how the internet works. You shouldn't miss that one!</li>
<li>"New Super Mario Bros. Final Castle 105 seconds World Record":http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jVXNL4n73-E - Amazing!</li>
<li>"PS3 vs. Wii":http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QpYgNz6W6Gs - I'm intending to buy a Wii anyway, but this video is just hilarious.</li>
<li>"Almost - Cheese & Crackers":http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aZtmrunVXs4 - Coolest miniramp skate session ever. Read my lips: EVER!</li>
</ul>


<p>When I finished watching the stuff my friends had recommended, I started browsing around the site and found the following gem I immediately subscribed to:</p>

<p>"Happy Slip Productions":http://www.youtube.com/profile?user=HappySlip - A Filipina actress who is doing some seriously funny stuff.</p>

<p>After I freed myself from the black hole that YouTube is for one's free time, I decided to finally watch "Elephants Dream":http://orange.blender.org/, an animated movie realized entirely with free software, which I downloaded a few weeks ago but never had time to watch before. It's really great and of course CC licensed.</p>

<p>Boomtime, Bureaucracy 48, 3172 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
