<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: games | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-08T18:02:01+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2012-06-24]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/06/24/information-overload-2012-06-24/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/06/24/information-overload-2012-06-24</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>It was like finding out your husband didn't just cheat, but had a frequent-flier account with every brothel in North America for the past 10 years.</p><footer><strong>Matt Taibbi</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/news/the-scam-wall-street-learned-from-the-mafia-20120620'>The Scam Wall Street Learned From the Mafia</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.vice.com/read/i-dont-get-art">I Don't "Get" Art</a><br>More than once I found myself at an exhibition with exactly the same thoughts.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/uxpil/ive_been_playing_the_same_game_of_civilization_ii/">I've been playing the same game of Civilization II for almost 10 years. This is the result.</a><br>A Redditor describes the in-game worl of a game of Civilization II he's been playing for 10 years. Also see the <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/theeternalwar">new subreddit</a>, the <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/business/technology/sid-meier-on-players-decade-long-civilization-game/2012/06/18/gJQAqgQ9lV_story.html">interview with Sid Meier</a> and a player who managed to <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/theeternalwar/comments/uzpr8/fixing_a_broken_world_a_players_guide/">save the world</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.vijayp.ca/blog/2012/06/colours-in-movie-posters-since-1914/">Colours in movie posters since 1914</a><br>I love how engineers tackle all sorts of problems.</li>
<li><a href="http://mondediplo.com/2012/06/12kachin">The Kachin borderlands</a><br>China's political and economic impact on Burma's border state Kachin.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-18191589">Top US universities put their reputations online</a><br>On the online courses offered by MIT, Harvard and Stanford.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.technologyreview.com/featured-story/428145/the-great-german-energy-experiment/">The Great German Energy Experiment</a><br>After Fukushima Germany decided to change its energy policies. Was this really a wise decision?</li>
<li><a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/news/the-scam-wall-street-learned-from-the-mafia-20120620">The Scam Wall Street Learned From the Mafia</a><br>Another great article by the Rolling Stone, I always like how direct they are.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.zeit.de/gesellschaft/zeitgeschehen/2012-06/breivik-prozess-norwegen-schuld-opfer/komplettansicht">Lebenslang für Norwegen</a><br>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anders_Behring_Breivik">Breivik</a> trial is coming to its end, but the scars in the Norwegian psyche are deep (in German).</li>
<li><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/06/24/magazine/when-my-crazy-father-actually-lost-his-mind.html?_r=2&amp;pagewanted=all">When My Crazy Father Actually Lost His Mind</a><br>A touching personal account of a family dealing with mental illness.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.sciencenews.org/view/generic/id/341619/title/Like_a_prion%2C_Alzheimers_protein_seeds_itself_in_the_brain">Like a prion, Alzheimer's protein seeds itself in the brain</a><br>Always good to see some new research on a disease like Alzheimer's.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2012-01-08]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/01/08/information-overload-2012-01-08/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2012/01/08/information-overload-2012-01-08</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2011/12/newyears-resolution-full-disk-encryption-every-computer-you-own">New Year's Resolution: Full Disk Encryption on Every Computer You Own</a><br>The <a href="https://www.eff.org">EFF</a> has a great suggestion for a New Year's resolution.</li>
<li><a href="http://scienceblogs.com/goodmath/2008/12/my_favorite_strange_number_cla.php">My Favorite Strange Number: Ω</a><br>Yeah for obscure math.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.osnews.com/story/25469/Richard_Stallman_Was_Right_All_Along">Richard Stallman Was Right All Along</a><br>It's not often enough that one reads something positive about RMS, which frankly speaking is a shame.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.taz.de/Armenviertel-in-Caracas/!84778/">Zukunft in Selbstverwaltung</a><br>People in Venezuela's capital are organising themselves in order to take care of things the state fails to provide (in German).</li>
<li><a href="http://www.orgnet.com/slumlords.html">Uncloaking a Slumlord Conspiracy with Social Network Analysis</a><br>Using social network analysis for social justice.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/01/us-government-calls-censor-twitter-threaten-free-speech">U.S. Government Calls to Censor Twitter Threaten Free Speech</a><br>Yes, that's 2 articles by the EFF in one issue of the Information Overload. It's not my fault they write so much sensible stuff...</li>
<li><a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/6582/learning_from_the_masters_level_.php">Learning From The Masters: Level Design In The Legend Of Zelda</a><br>See this as a kind of follow-up to another Zelda related article I posted not so long ago.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.technologyreview.com/blog/arxiv/27469/">Mathematicians Solve Minimum Sudoku Problem</a><br>Unfortunately this was proven by using a computer to brute force the problem space, much like the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_color_theorem">Four Color Theorem</a>. A "proper" proof would be nice and I'm sure it would make for an interesting read.</li>
<li><a href="http://io9.com/5873485/an-optimistic-history-of-the-next-40-years">An Optimistic History of the Next 40 Years</a><br>That's certainly a more optimistic guess than anything I can come up with. Unfortunately I'm afraid this will stay the stuff for SciFi novels...</li>
<li><a href="http://www.salon.com/2012/01/03/david_lynch_why_brutality_makes_me_laugh/singleton/">David Lynch: Why brutality makes me laugh</a><br>An interview with David Lynch about his latest musical project.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-12-25]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/25/information-overload-2011-12-25/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/12/25/information-overload-2011-12-25</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>They’ve reminded us that politics is not a matter of choosing among what we’re offered but of fighting for what we and others actually need, not to mention what we hope for.</p><footer><strong>Nathan Schneider</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.thenation.com/article/165240/thank-you-anarchists'>Thank You, Anarchists</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://web.mit.edu/newsoffice/2011/mitx-education-initiative-1219.html">MIT launches online learning initiative</a><br>After Stanford's successful online courses, the MIT also develops a new online platform on top of the already cool <a href="http://ocw.mit.edu/index.htm">OCW</a>. I always welcome more good and free learning resources.</li>
<li><a href="http://metamodern.com/2009/05/27/how-to-learn-about-everything/">How to Learn About Everything</a><br>As you can see from the subtitle of this blog, this is something I'm also trying to do, with a comparable method.</li>
<li><a href="http://hbr.org/2006/10/sleep-deficit-the-performance-killer">Sleep Deficit: The Performance Killer</a><br>As someone who sometimes suffers from bouts of insomnia, I can attest to the bad effects lack of sleep can have. You may believe that you got used to it, but really, you don't.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.thenation.com/article/165240/thank-you-anarchists">Thank You, Anarchists</a><br>I know The Nation is a left-wing magazine, but it's still nice to see a positive article about anarchism somewhere.</li>
<li><a href="http://togetherforjacksoncountykids.tumblr.com/post/14314184651/one-teachers-approach-to-preventing-gender-bullying-in">One teachers approach to preventing gender bullying in a classroom</a><br>There should be more teachers like this.</li>
<li><a href="http://persquaremile.com/2011/12/21/which-reads-faster-chinese-or-english/">Which reads faster, Chinese or English?</a><br>Once again a language related article. The comments are also quite interesting by the way.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.andyworthington.co.uk/2011/12/16/an-extraordinary-interview-with-former-guantanamo-child-prisoner-mohammed-el-gharani/">An Extraordinary Interview with Former Guantánamo Child Prisoner Mohammed El-Gharani</a><br>Some bits of this interview seem a bit odd to me, but you can judge that for yourself.</li>
<li><a href="http://games.greggman.com/game/the-zelda-test-or-why-no-zelda-clones/">The Zelda Test (or Why no Zelda Clones?)</a><br>I don't spend much time on playing video games anymore, but it's still good to read something like this by a real gaming nerd.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.arminsoyka.at/blog/uber-das-leben-eines-heterojungen-mit-schwulen-eltern/">Über das Leben eines Heterojungen mit schwulen Eltern</a><br>An Austrian exchange student describes his experience staying with a gay couple (in German).</li>
<li><a href="http://seedmagazine.com/content/article/why_we_havent_met_any_aliens/">Why We Haven't Met Any Aliens</a><br>While the overall gist of the article doesn't really strike home with me, I still find it an interesting thought experiment.</li>
</ul>


<p><blockquote><p>The business of humanity has become entertainment, and entertainment is the business of feeding fake fitness cues to our brains.</p><footer><strong>Geoffrey Miller</strong> <cite><a href='http://seedmagazine.com/content/article/why_we_havent_met_any_aliens/'>Why We Haven't Met Any Aliens</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-10-09]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/10/09/information-overload-2011-10-09/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-09T19:45:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/10/09/information-overload-2011-10-09</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>Thus, tweeting &quot;Down with capitalism&quot; from your iPhone for those around the world to read seems to be the most ironic thing a person can do.</p><footer><strong>Robert David Graham</strong> <cite><a href='http://erratasec.blogspot.com/2011/10/independent-reporting-of.html'>Independent Reporting of #OccupyWallStreet</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://bemmu.posterous.com/what-it-costs-to-live-in-japan">What it costs to live in Japan</a><br>A foreigner living in Japan gives an interesting breakdown of the cost of living there.</li>
<li><a href="http://torrentfreak.com/belgian-isps-ordered-to-block-the-pirate-bay-111004/">Belgian ISPs Ordered To Block The Pirate Bay</a><br>Two Belgian ISPs received a court order to block the Pirate Bay after the Belgian Anti-Piracy foundation won a court appeal.</li>
<li><a href="http://kotaku.com/5846080/the-life+changing-20-rightward+facing-cow">The Life-Changing $20 Rightward-Facing Cow</a><br>Game designer, lecturer and author Ian Bogost was so bothered by "social gaming" and "gamification", that he bothered to release a satire game, which turned out become his biggest success. Great read!</li>
<li><a href="http://www.techdirt.com/articles/20111004/04402516196/brazil-drafts-anti-acta-civil-rights-based-framework-internet.shtml">Brazil Drafts An 'Anti-ACTA': A Civil Rights-Based Framework For The Internet</a><br>After already being big on FOSS and open content use, Brazil now also pushes for a new Internet regulation, that actually has a strong civil rights focus.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.wired.com/wiredscience/2011/10/asteroid-moving/">The Plan to Bring an Asteroid to Earth</a><br>I love when science starts sounding like science fiction.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.nzz.ch/nachrichten/wirtschaft/aktuell/destruktive_dynamik_im_handelsraum_1.12641170.html">Destruktive Dynamik im Handelsraum</a><br>A study found that financial traders act more ruthless than psychopaths. Who'd have thought.... (in German)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/infocus/2011/09/vladimir-putin-action-man/100147/">Vladimir Putin, Action Man</a><br>Vladimir Putin, the James Bond of politics. Joking aside though, this photo series is a great summary of the public image he has created in recent years.</li>
<li><a href="http://erratasec.blogspot.com/2011/10/independent-reporting-of.html">Independent reporting of #OccupyWallStreet</a><br>An insightful article about the current protests, with a fair share of media criticism and good observations about the protesters. I often find myself liking things written by people who label themselves libertarians, but it still is a philosophy I have strong doubts about. </li>
<li><a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/news/2011/10/exclusive-computer-virus-hits-drone-fleet.ars">Computer virus hits US Predator and Reaper drone fleet</a><br>A hard to remove virus on military infrastructure and once again it seems like external storage media was the culprit.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.adbusters.org/magazine/79/hipster.html">Hipster: The Dead End of Western Civilization</a><br>This article on hipsterdom feels so contemporary, I hadn't even noticed that it's more than 3 years old until I finished it.</li>
</ul>


<p><blockquote><p>If only we carried rocks instead of cameras, we'd look like revolutionaries.</p><footer><strong>Douglas Haddow</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.adbusters.org/magazine/79/hipster.html'>Hipster: The Dead End of Western Civilization</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Awesome Indie Games]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/10/05/awesome-indie-games/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-05T20:55:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/10/05/awesome-indie-games</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I used to be a big gamer, especially when it came to console games. Nowadays I don't have much time for that anymore, but I'm still quite interested in gaming culture and games as a medium. I'm especially fond of indie games, since their authors can afford to explore stranger concepts than more mainstream development teams. Here's a list of some of my favorites, most (all?) of which should be available on Windows, Mac and Linux:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.andyetitmoves.net/">And Yet It Moves</a>: Awesome physics-based platformer, featuring a very unique design.</li>
<li><a href="http://blendogames.com/atomzombiesmasher/">Atom Zombie Smasher</a>: Probably my absolute favorite at the moment. Great presentation, awesome music and an interesting twist on the tower defense genre.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.braid-game.com/">Braid</a>: Cute puzzle game that utilizes time as a central element of the game mechanics.</li>
<li><a href="http://crayonphysics.com/">Crayon Physics Delux</a>: Ok, I'm a sucker for physics based games, and this is no exception. The great visual style definitely helps.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.desktopdungeons.net/">Desktop Dungeons</a>: While the developers are working on a "proper" version now, the original alpha is still available for free. Think of it as the bare essence of rogue-likes.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.hemispheregames.com/osmos/">Osmos</a>: I really like this one for it's almost meditative quality.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.fargoal.com/">Sword of Fargoal Legend</a>: Another dungeon crawler that proves that good game mechanics are more important than fancy graphics.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.traumagame.com/">Trauma</a>: Maybe the most unique game in this list, this point and click adventure deals with the psychological trauma of a young woman who survived a car crash. Eerie atmosphere, great presentation.</li>
<li><a href="http://thelettervsixtim.es/">VVVVVV</a>: A 2d puzzle platformer that I'm quite fond of. Messing with gravity while listening to chiptune music? Count me in!</li>
<li><a href="http://www.worldofgoo.com/">World of Goo</a>: The cute Gooballs alone are a reason to play this one.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
