<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: netculture | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/netculture/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-24T00:37:53+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-07-17]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/07/17/information-overload-2011-07-17/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-17T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/07/17/information-overload-2011-07-17</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"How Seawater Can Power the World":http://www.nytimes.com/2011/07/11/opinion/11Prager.html<br>Interesting NYT op-ed on the future of fusion energy.</li>
<li>"Zoobotics":http://www.economist.com/node/18925855?story_id=18925855<br>Robot researchers are modeling their creations after animals now, assuming that it's hard to come up with a better design than evolution.</li>
<li>"Edward Tufte's &quot;Slopegraphs&quot;":http://charliepark.org/slopegraphs/<br>I really like this under-used chart style, I think it conveys meaning very well.</li>
<li>"Groundhog Decade":http://www.slate.com/id/2298871/pagenum/all/<br>Very good piece on how Hollywood apparently is dead set on repeating the mistakes of the music industry.</li>
<li>"Why Programming Languages?":http://soft.vub.ac.be/~tvcutsem/whypls.html<br>A programming language researcher explains why there are so many different programming languages and why we'll likely keep on seeing new ones.</li>
<li>"The Menace Within":http://www.stanfordalumni.org/news/magazine/2011/julaug/features/spe.html<br>40 years after the Stanford Prison Experiment some key players tell about their experience and what they took away from the experiment.</li>
<li>"Misattribution of Arousal":http://youarenotsosmart.com/2011/07/07/misattribution-of-arousal/<br>I love all those insights into how our brains work. This article deals with the misattribution of arousal (not only of the sexual kind) to other people.</li>
<li>"How Digital Detectives Deciphered Stuxnet, the Most Menacing Malware in History":http://www.wired.com/threatlevel/2011/07/how-digital-detectives-deciphered-stuxnet/all/1<br>If you have the slightest interest in IT security, you'll love this article, but even if you usually don't enjoy this topic the story still reads like the plot of a Hollywood movie.</li>
<li>"Tower of David: 45 Floors of Favela Chic":http://d-build.org/blog/?p=2128<br>One of Latin America's tallest buildings is now squatted by around 2500 people, many of them escaping live on the streets.</li>
<li>"My Summer at an Indian Call Center":http://m.motherjones.com/politics/2011/05/indian-call-center-americanization<br>An American citizen works in an Indian call center for a summer.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-05-15]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/05/15/information-overload-2011-05-15/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-15T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/05/15/information-overload-2011-05-15</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"Crunching the numbers: How many people have ever lived?":http://1000memories.com/blog/75-number-of-people-who-have-ever-lived<br>Why is math awesome? Because it answers questions like this one. Don't worry, no spoilers ;-)</li>
<li>"The Pirate Bay: 'The Battle of Internets is About to Begin'":http://torrentfreak.com/the-pirate-bay-the-battle-of-internets-is-about-to-begin-110509/<br>TPB's answer to the threat of a "Great Firewall" in Europe.</li>
<li>"2011 Trends":http://www.logolounge.com/article.asp?aid=lnPf<br><a href="http://www.logolounge.com/default.asp">LongoLounge.com</a>'s annual logo design trends.</li>
<li>"How to Stop Worrying and Learn to Love the Internet":http://www.douglasadams.com/dna/19990901-00-a.html<br>Wow, Douglas Adams already had a better grasp of the internet in 1999 than a lot of the people in decision-making positions have today.</li>
<li>"Silver Needle in the Skype":http://www.blackhat.com/presentations/bh-europe-06/bh-eu-06-biondi/bh-eu-06-biondi-up.pdf<br>Since everyone was talking about Skype this week, I thought I'd include this very interesting presentation from Black Hat 2006.</li>
<li>"The History of Pretty Much Everything":http://scienceblogs.com/startswithabang/2011/04/the_history_of_pretty_much_eve.php<br>If you like astronomy and/or physics, you'll probably like this too.</li>
<li>"Anonymous: peering behind the mask":http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/2011/may/11/anonymous-behind-the-mask<br>Pretty good article by "Jana Herwig":http://twitter.com/#!/digiom on Anonymous.</li>
<li>"Kill Math":http://worrydream.com/KillMath/<br>While I don't agree with everything said, this article does have some interesting points and a great visualization of integration.</li>
<li>"Satellite Images of North Korea Prison Camps Find 200,000 Living as Slaves":http://singularityhub.com/2011/05/12/satellite-images-of-north-korea-prison-camps-find-200000-living-as-slaves/<br>A follow-up to last week's article by Amnesty International, because this is something we shouldn't forget about.</li>
<li>"Are you living in a computer simulation?":http://www.simulation-argument.com/simulation.html<br>That's exactly the kind of question I want answered by Oxford's philosophy department.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2011-03-20]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/03/20/information-overload-2011-03-20/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-20T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2011/03/20/information-overload-2011-03-20</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"Haskell's Niche: Hard Problems":http://cdsmith.wordpress.com/2011/03/13/haskells-niche-hard-problems/<br>Doing more Haskell was on my todo list for 2011, but so far I've failed rather miserably. Oh well, at least I'm reading about it...</li>
<li>"Beyond Rules":http://www.friendlyanarchist.com/beyond-rules/<br>Nice post with a free download of the ebook "Beyond Rules: A Dilettante's Guide to Personal Sovereignty, Space Travel, and Lots of Ice Cream".</li>
<li>"The Tau Manifesto":http://tauday.com/<br>The math fans among my readers should like this one (and the accompanying "Half Tau Day":http://halftauday.com/), I certainly did!</li>
<li>"Was haben wir aus unserer Welt gemacht?":http://www.misik.at/texte-aus-der-taz-berlin/was-haben-wir-aus-unserer-welt-gemacht.php<br>Austrian journalist Robert Misik comments on the current nuclear energy safety discussion (in German).</li>
<li>"Antarctica, 1961: A Soviet Surgeon Has to Remove His Own Appendix":http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2011/03/antarctica-1961-a-soviet-surgeon-has-to-remove-his-own-appendix/72445/<br>The Chuck Norris of surgery.</li>
<li>"Partitioning my digital life into security domains":http://theinvisiblethings.blogspot.com/2011/03/partitioning-my-digital-life-into.html<br>Well--known security researcher Joanna Rutkowska describes how she partitions her digital life into separate domains with "Qubes OS":http://qubes-os.org/Home.html. A very interesting approach and I'm curious to see Beta 1 of the OS.</li>
<li>"Cosmonaut Crashed Into Earth 'Crying In Rage'":http://www.npr.org/blogs/krulwich/2011/03/18/134597833/cosmonaut-crashed-into-earth-crying-in-rage?ft=1&f=1026<br>The man who died to save his friend Yuri Gagarin.</li>
<li>"Facebook: Online-Proteste ohne Offline-Effekt":http://futurezone.at/netzpolitik/2282-facebook-online-proteste-ohne-offline-effekt.php<br>Good article on "Slacktivism" (in German).</li>
<li>"Chomsky on 'Intellectual Property'":http://groups.google.com/group/alt.fan.noam-chomsky/msg/12c9b62ed459d63d?pli=1<br>Interview with Noam Chomsky about intellectual property. This is a bit older, but still a good read.</li>
<li>"Nerds, we need to have a talk":http://thingist.com/t/item/4372/<br>Good rant about an attitude problem in nerd culture.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2010-11-14]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2010/11/14/information-overload-2010-11-14/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-14T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2010/11/14/information-overload-2010-11-14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"JVM Bytecode for Dummies":http://www.slideshare.net/CharlesNutter/redev-2010-jvm-bytecode-for-dummies<br>Awesome presentation by "Charles Nutter":http://blog.headius.com/ on JVM Bytecode. No matter if you are just curious or want to write your own programming language, this is interesting!</li>
<li>"Cutting out the middle men":http://www.economist.com/node/17420321?story_id=17420321&fsrc=scn/tw/te/rss/pe<br>Great pilot project in the UK, empowering homeless people instead by directly giving them money.</li>
<li>"Can't play, won't play":http://www.hideandseek.net/cant-play-wont-play/<br>Lots of websites and incentive programs nowadays try to "gamify" themselves by adding badges and point systems. Read why in most cases this has nothing to do with real games.</li>
<li>"Obscene Losses":http://www.portfolio.com/culture-lifestyle/culture-inc/arts/2007/10/15/YouPorn-Vivid-Entertainment-Profile/index.html<br>Very detailed article on how YouPorn and other amateur sites damage the business of established adult movie producers.</li>
<li>"Mystery of how cats lap is revealed":http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-11717510<br>Cats even drink in cool ways.</li>
<li>"10 centuries in 5 minutes":http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DrZvn1qckIs<br>Absolutely fantastic 5 minute video of 1000 years of European history. This is fascinating and a good reminder that today's empires may very well be tomorrow's ashes.</li>
<li>"20 Awesomely Untranslatable Words from Around the World":http://matadornetwork.com/abroad/20-awesomely-untranslatable-words-from-around-the-world/2/<br>Interesting collection of untranslatable words from around the world. This made the language geek in me very happy.</li>
<li>"What I Would Do With This: Groceries":http://blog.mrmeyer.com/?p=4646<br>The mathematics of grocery shopping.</li>
<li>"Skateistan: To live and skate Kabul":http://vimeo.com/15841377<br>Short movie about a co-educational Skateboarding school in Kabul, Afghanistan.</li>
<li>"Hubris Versus Humility: The $15 billion Difference":http://steveblank.com/2010/11/08/hubris-versus-humility-the-15-billion-difference/<br>While I think that the comparison in this article is a bit apples and oranges, it's an interesting take on initial market positioning.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Information Overload 2010-10-17]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2010/10/17/information-overload-2010-10-17/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-17T00:00:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2010/10/17/information-overload-2010-10-17</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>"The 'Irrational' Way Humans Interact With Dentists":http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=130356647<br>Are our relationships with our dentists a form of the "Stockholm Syndrome":http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stockholm_syndrome? Ask the behavioral psychologist.</li>
<li>"RCA student radically improves the UK plug":http://www.iconeye.com/index.php?id=3864:rca-student-radically-improves-the-uk-plug&option=com_content&view=article<br>Awesome redesign of an everyday item.</li>
<li>"William Gibson says the future is right here, right now":http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-11502715<br>When it comes to the future, who to trust if not William Gibson?</li>
<li>"What a scientist didn't tell the New York Times about his study on bee deaths":http://money.cnn.com/2010/10/08/news/honey_bees_ny_times.fortune/index.htm<br>Follow-up to last week's NYT article on "Colony Collapse Disorder":http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colony_collapse_disorder. How is "Bayer":http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bayer related to all of this?</li>
<li>"Die kritische Masse":http://www.spiegel.de/spiegel/0,1518,722673,00.html<br>Interesting article on online review portals, user motivation and manipulation (in German).</li>
<li>"Whistleblower reveals 'systematic' humiliation of detainees":http://www.rawstory.com/rs/2010/10/whistleblower-reveals-systematic-humiliation/<br>When reading things like this, "what goes around comes around" is always my first sad thought.</li>
<li>"The Numbers Game":http://structureofnews.wordpress.com/2010/10/12/the-numbers-game/<br>A plea to increase "numeracy":http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Numeracy amongst journalists. Amen to that!</li>
<li>"Sweden joins Europe-wide backlash against immigration":http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2010/sep/24/sweden-immigration-far-right-asylum<br>Sweden joins the ranks of European countries where xeno- and Islamophobia win elections. Also contains a short summary of similar developments all over Europe.</li>
<li>"Irish ISP wins major legal victory against record labels":http://www.techeye.net/internet/irish-isp-wins-major-legal-victory-against-record-labels<br>UPC wins a court case against the record industry and does not have to implement a three strikes system for its customers (for now).</li>
<li>"Council of Europe Agrees That Net neutrality is Key to Freedom of Expression":http://www.laquadrature.net/en/council-of-europe-agrees-that-net-neutrality-is-key-to-freedom-of-expression<br>Some more good news on the freedom of expression front.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
