<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: nintendo | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/nintendo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-21T18:37:44-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yeah Nintendo!]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/12/17/yeah-nintendo/"/>
    <updated>2006-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/12/17/yeah-nintendo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago I've blogged about me being uncertain whether to get myself a Nintento Wii or an Xbox 360 (please don't tell me to get both, that thought is too tempting already!). Currently Big N's latest offering is a slight favorite again, since - after an exhausting few days partying - I spent the late afternoon and early evening playing "Paper Mario: The Thounsand-Year Door":http://cube.ign.com/articles/556/556422p1.html, which is one of the most entertaining and funny games I've ever played. Later on I decided to finally try out the "Nintendo Wi-Fi Connection":http://www.nintendowifi.com/ with Mario Kart DS (friend code: 197655187733), and I have to say that I just love it, which means that now I really have to get myself a copy of "Metroid Prime Hunters":http://ds.ign.com/articles/697/697307p1.html as soon as possible.</p>

<p>Sweetmorn, The Aftermath 59, 3172 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delusions of grandeur]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/08/12/delusions-of-grandeur/"/>
    <updated>2006-08-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/08/12/delusions-of-grandeur</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As my PR manager told me, large numbers of fans have already complained about the recent lack of updates. Since I'm only my reader's humble servant, I of course have to comply with this wishes, so here are the long awaited news about yours truly:</p>

<p><em>Gentoo:</em>
After being a "Gentoo":http://www.gentoo.org developer for 2 years, I finally decided to leave the project. Since I haven't really been active for the past 4 month anyway for several reasons (e.g. work), this was long overdue anyway. I've met a lot of nice and interesting people in the Gentoo community and working with you guys has really been a pleasure! Thanks for that, I really appreciate what I have learned from all of you during that time!</p>

<p><em>Mac:</em>
Today I've joined the team of "Open.Source.Mac":http://opensourcemac.de/ and have already published "my first little article":http://www.opensourcemac.de/2006/08/12/machtgeil/ on the site. Enjoy!</p>

<p><em>Personal:</em>
On the 2nd of August I celebrated my 27th birthday at "Xeno":http://www.xeno.co.at/. A lot of "friends":http://red667.org/ showed up, whereas "certain people":http://berq.net/ decided to get drunk somewhere else and then blamed innocent squirrels for their not showing up. It was a cool evening which I really enjoyed, but working on the next day didn't exactly qualify as a good cure against the headaches...</p>

<p><em>Capitalism:</em>
I have to admit that I love portable consoles, especially when they are as sexy as the black Nintendo DS Lite I bought three weeks ago. So far I own "Advance Wars: Dual Strike":http://ds.ign.com/articles/643/643656p1.html, "Brain Age: Train Your Brain in Minutes a Day":http://ds.ign.com/articles/702/702057p1.html, "Feel The Magic XY/XX":http://ds.ign.com/articles/567/567496p1.html and "Castlevania: Dawn of Sorrow":http://ds.ign.com/articles/655/655830p1.html. All of them are really great and I can hardly wait until my copy of "Mario Kart DS":http://ds.ign.com/articles/666/666125p1.html finally arrives.</p>

<p>I also got myself a nice "M9 DX enclosure":http://www.macpower.com.tw/products/hdd3/m9/m9dx with a 250GB Samsung HD as a backup disk for the Mac Mini. Overall it's pretty neat, although it could match the color of the Mini a little better.</p>

<p><em>Misc</em>
Found an "article":http://www.explosm.net/articles/6135/4/ about "Habbo Hotel":http://www.habbohotel.co.uk/ on the "Pardus":http://www.pardus.at forums and just had "to try it out":http://flickr.com/photos/citizen428/sets/72157594226374139/. Like the author of the article I most likely won't visit the site again, but I had a lot of fun during the hour I spent there.</p>

<p>"teemow":http://teemow.com recently blogged about "BumpTop":http://honeybrown.ca/Pubs/BumpTop.html, a new take at the desktop metaphor we all grew used to. The video is quite impressive and I'd really like to try out such an interface myself, as I'm interested in how well it works for everyday usage.</p>

<p>Prickle-Prickle, Bureaucracy 5, 3172 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Capitalism stole my virginity...]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/02/20/capitalism-stole-my-virginity/"/>
    <updated>2006-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/02/20/capitalism-stole-my-virginity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>...but it bought me a Game Cube.</p>

<p>Today at work I got so p*ssed that I decided to go out and spend some money on stuff I don't really need. In the end I bought a Nintendo Game Cube, "Mario Kart Double Dash!!":http://www.nintendo.com/gamemini?gameid=m-Game-0000-652, a memory card, and an additional controller in a shop close to my work, as well as a copy of "Metroid Prime":http://metroid.com/prime/ on eBay which I should get in a few days.</p>

<p><em>FAQ</em>
<em>Q: You know that capitalism only works by making you so depressed that you just need to buy something in order to feel better?</em>
A: Yes, that's why I'm also pretty ashamed every time I fall for this, but sometimes you just can't help it...</p>

<p><em>Q: Don't you think that sucks then?</em>
A: Sure I do, but you can't get drunk all the time.</p>

<p><em>Q: Why a Game Cube and not a PS2/X-Box/whatever?</em>
A: I've collected game consoles starting from the old NES until Sega stopped producing their own consoles after my beloved Dreamcast. Personally I just think that Nintendo and Sega rock, while MS and Sony...ahm...just don't. I don't need the newest and greatest hardware, I just want a nice platform which offers the kind of games I like to play. Additionally I already own a Game Boy Advance for several years, which can be used in conjuction with the Game Cube.</p>

<p><em>Q: You could have bought that Game Cube a lot earlier.</em>
A: That's not a question.</p>

<p><em>Q: But still...</em>
Well, after Sega announced that they won't release any new consoles, I got so depressed and ended my career as a video game collector (I never really liked PC games). Now that I spontanously changed my mind, the Game Cube was the only system I considered worth buying. No flame wars please, I quite regularly play PS2 and X-Box games when hanging out with friends, I just don't want to spend my own money on those particular systems.</p>

<p><em>Q: Will you start blogging about Game Cube games now?</em>
A: There might be the occasional post on this topic, but this site definitely won't turn into a gaming blog.</p>

<p><em>Q: What about the revolution?</em>
See blog subtitle.</p>

<p><em>Q: Have you turned into a bitter cynic lately?</em>
You've noticed? If I only knew what could be the "reason":http://citizen428.net/archives/254-Why-working-in-Business-IT-sucks.html...</p>

<p>Boomtime, Chaos 52, 3172 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
