<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: quotes | citizen428.blog()]]></title>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/categories/quotes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://citizen428.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-07T17:09:56-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://citizen428.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Kohl]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[citizen428@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In defense of - Part I: Alcohol]]></title>
    <link href="http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/07/05/in-defense-of-part-i-alcohol/"/>
    <updated>2006-07-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://citizen428.net/blog/2006/07/05/in-defense-of-part-i-alcohol</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since too many of life's pleasures are demonized by all the greyfaces out there, I've decided to start a new series called "In defense of", where I'll collect quotes, song lyrics, etc. which show them in a different - and maybe more positive - way.</p>

<p><i><em>Kikizo:</em> So, how many drinks does it take for ideas to stop being feasible, good ideas, and start being just complete nonsense?</p>

<p><em>Itagaki:</em> Haha! It's hard to say, because I am drinking pretty much full-time. Of course, there are ups and downs, waves, of how I drink in terms of the amount, but it's a long period of time. In the last ten years - not that you asked this question - I think I had better ideas when I was drinking whisky. When I am drinking shochu, that's a conservative drink, so the ideas are not that great. Beer is just like water to me, so it just helps me and everyone else loosen up a little bit, it doesn't really contribute to coming up with ideas.</i> (found on "Ars Technica":http://arstechnica.com/journals/thumbs.ars/2006/7/4/4522)</p>

<hr>


<p><i>"I wouldn't recommend sex, drugs or insanity for everyone, but they've always worked for me."</i> - Hunter S. Thompson</p>

<hr>


<p><em>BOUNCING SOULS</em>
<i>"I Started Drinking Again"</p>

<p>Since I started drinkin' again
Since I started drinkin' again
I ain't shed one lousy tear over you
Since I started drinkin' again</p>

<p>I know that the neighbors are all a-talkin'
They swear that I have lost my mind
Ah, but they do not know
That I've just gained control
Of all the heartache that you left behind</p>

<p>[Chorus:]
Since I started drinkin' again
Since I started drinkin' again
I ain't shed one lousy tear over you
Since I started drinkin' again</p>

<p>Well I know that the boss is gonna fire me
When I stumble in late to work again
But surprise will replace that old scowl on his face
When he sees that I do not give a damn</p>

<p>[Chorus:]
Since I started drinkin' again
Since I started drinkin' again
I ain't shed one lousy tear over you
Since I started drinkin' again</p>

<p>I ain't shed one lousy tear over you
Since I started drinkin'
Since I started drinkin'
Since I started drinkin' again
</i></p>

<hr>


<p><i>&#8220;Alcohol may be man's worst enemy, but the bible says love your enemy.&#8221;</i> - Frank Sinatra</p>

<hr>


<p><i>&#8220;Alcohol is the anesthesia by which we endure the operation of life.&#8221;</i> - George Bernard Shaw</p>

<hr>


<p><i>&#8220;Man being reasonable must get drunk; The best of life is but intoxication; Glory, the grape, love, gold - in these are sunk - The hopes of all men and of every nation&#8221;</i> - Lord Byron</p>

<p>(Quotes taken from "Thinkexist.com":http://en.thinkexist.com/quotations/alcohol/)</p>

<p>Sweetmorn, Confusion 40, 3172 YOLD</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
